<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="OCTGN" source="Community" source_url="https://github.com/tftcg/faq">
  <target name="Installing OCTGN">
    <entry id="1">
      <question>How do I install OCTGN to play Transformers?</question>
      <answer>
          1. Install the app and create your account: <a href="http://octgn.net/Home/GetOctgn">http://octgn.net/Home/GetOctgn</a>
          2. Open OCTGN, and go to "Game Manager" to install "Transformers".
          3. Download the card images (.o8c files): <a href="http://www.hi-izuru.org/OCTGN/Games/Transformers/">http://www.hi-izuru.org/OCTGN/Games/Transformers/</a>
          4. In "Games Manager", choose "Add Image Pack" to upload the .o8c files into your OCTGN.
          5. Open the "OCTGN Deck Builder" and build your deck. You can also download a deck directly from <a href="https://fortressmaximus.io">https://fortressmaximus.io</a> using the "OCTGN Export" function.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2">
      <question>Why can't I see the card images?</question>
      <answer>
          You probably haven't installed the image pack. You should:
          1. Download the card images (.o8c files): <a href="http://www.hi-izuru.org/OCTGN/Games/Transformers/">http://www.hi-izuru.org/OCTGN/Games/Transformers/</a>
          2. In OCTGN's "Games Manager", choose "Add Image Pack" to upload the .o8c files into your OCTGN.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3">
      <question>Can I play on Mac OS?</question>
      <answer>
           On Mac OS before 10.15 (Catalina) you should be able to use WINE to play on Mac OS. From 10.15 onwards WINE currently appears to have issues. You could also use a VM to install Windows on top of Mac OS. Note that both of these are non-simple for the average computer user, so don't feel bad if you decide not to try. 
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4">
      <question>Can I play on Linux?</question>
      <answer>
           You should be able to use WINE to play on Linux, or you could install Windows onto Linux on a VM.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5">
      <question>Why do I get told that "The following image packs could not be installed"?</question>
      <answer>
           Double check that you have installed the Transformers game pack. OCTGN will report the image pack is invalid or broken when the game isn't installed. 
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Playing OCTGN">
    <entry id="12">
        <question>How do I report a bug/ask a question about TFTCG with OCTGN?</question>
        <answer>Any of the following are good places to report bugs or ask questions:
            1. There is a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/OCTGNprime/">Facebook OCTGN Group</a>.
            2. There is a <a href="https://discord.gg/64HqhBG">dedicated Discord server</a> to interact with the TF/OCTGN developer(s).
            3. Many other community Discord servers have OCTGN channels to connect with folk looking to play. 
            4. You can report issues and ideas on <a href="https://github.com/zz1000zz/OCTGN_TF/issues">GitHub</a>.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="11">
      <question>How do I play a secret action?</question>
      <answer>Hold down shift while you are dragging and dropping the card to the battlefield. This will play the card face-down. 
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="13">
      <question>How do I draw an arrow between two cards?</question>
      <answer>Hold down shift, click on the first card, then drag to the second card. This is commonly used to indicate that you are using the first card to attack the seconc card, or that the first card is adding an effect to the second card.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="14">
      <question>How do I fetch a different Character card?</question>
      <answer>
          Right click on the character card pile in the bottom right of the screen and select Grab Characters From Collection.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="15">
      <question>How do I fetch a Battle Card from my collection?</question>
      <answer>
          Right click on the battlefield right of the screen and select Grab Battle Card From Collection.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="16">
        <question>Are there pre-existing decks I can play?</question>
        <answer>
            Yes. Many standard decks are available at <a href="https://tftcg.github.io/decks/">https://tftcg.github.io/decks/</a>, while there are lots of community decks available on <a href="https://fortressmaximus.io/">https://fortressmaximus.io</a>. 
        </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="17">
        <question>Is there any help on using the Deck Editor?</question>
        <answer>
            Using the Deck Editor is discussed in the article, <a href="https://www.freelancepeacekeeping.com/articles/grapple.html">Grappling the Challenge</a>. 
        </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
