<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-05-28" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-52819/2167045840083896/" published_date="2019-05-28" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="528-1" tags="Raider Cindersaur - Black Ops - Demolitions,Alpha Trion - Cybertronian Sage,Battle Icon">
      <question>
Alpha Trion and Raider Cindersaur label actions by the colored battle icons. Can you explain what makes a card an Orange or Blue Card? Does that mean that they have to have at least one orange icon to be an orange card? If this is the case, then can Alpha Trion use his ability to play a Roll Out! because it has at least 1 blue icon?
      </question>
      <answer>
A “blue card” is a card with at least one blue battle icon, and so on for the other colors, so you would be able to play Roll Out with Alpha Trion’s ability.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-2" tags="Battle Icon">
      <question>
Say I, on my opponent's turn, have Infiltrate facedown and they play a secret action that has an orange icon (I, of course, don't know this). How does this interaction work, considering secret actions are considered actions?
      </question>
      <answer>
Infiltrate will never affect a Secret Action because as you’ve said, you can’t see its Battle Icons as it’s played.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-3">
      <question>
If Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend has Inverted on him, and during the attack flips Security Checkpoint and chooses to play it, does the Security Checkpoint count as Orange due to Inverted, which triggers the Secret Action Infiltrate?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes. While OPBL is battling, the blue icons on Security Checkpoint become orange. When you play Security Checkpoint, your opponent’s Infiltrate sees you playing an orange action and triggers.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-4" tags="Combiner,Optimus Maximus - Ultimate Defender,Ironhide - Steadfast Brawler">
      <question>
Since temporary effects applied to individual members of a Combiner team carry over to the Combined form for the turn, what happens if I have two active Sentinels, transform Wave 2 Ironhide in my KO area to give them Pierce 2, then play the Sentinel Enigma to combine them? Does Optimus Maximus then have Pierce 2 or Pierce 4?
      </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, Optimus Maximus would have Pierce 4.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-5" tags="Captain Ironhide - Infantry - Bodyguard,Private Red Heat - Infantry - Emergency Response">
      <question>
You previously ruled that Captain Ironhide can't use his Bot Mode ability to swap his weapon for an Energon Axe if he is undamaged. Does this also extend to other Upgrade movement effects? Does this mean I can't use Quartermaster or Private Red Heat to move an Energon Axe in play from a damaged character to an undamaged one?
      </question>
      <answer>
That is correct. Energon Axe can only be put on damaged characters.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-6">
      <question>
Say I attack using a character equipped with Backup Bag and Grenade Launcher. After the attack, would Grenade Launcher get scrapped or would Backup Bag prevent that?
      </question>
      <answer>
Backup Bag would be scrapped in place of Grenade Launcher in this scenario.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-7">
      <question>
If your character takes 10 damage while it has a Force Field and a Backup Bag, will the Backup Bag save the Force Field from being scrapped while also reducing the damage down to 4?
      </question>
      <answer>
It is Force Field’s own ability that is causing it to be scrapped, so Backup Back will apply. The character will take 4 attack damage and lose the Backup Bag.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-8" tags="General Megatron - Infantry - Leader">
      <question>
If I start my turn with 3 Attack Drones and a Sparring Gear on General Megatron, does that count as 4 Upgrades (Meaning each Attack Drone counts, and therefore trigger his ability), or only 2, since only 2 slots are filled?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes, each Attack Drone counts individually, so that is 4 upgrades, triggering General Megatron’s bot mode ability.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-9" tags="Play">
      <question>
If my opponent has one tapped character and I have two untapped characters and I start my turn. I draw a card, flip a character for the turn and play an upgrade but no action. I attack with my first character. Since it is still my turn and I can attack one more time, can I play my one action for the turn for the second attack rather than the first if the scenario is more favorable? Or do all sequence events have to be done before all attacks? 
      </question>
      <answer>
Attacking is the last thing you do in your turn. So, if you want to play an action, you must do so before your first attack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-10">
      <question>
Say I have Bumblebee - Legendary Warrior in bot mode to start the turn. I play Roll Out! (or any other character flipping card) to flip BB to alt mode where he gains the ability: When you flip to this mode -> This character can attack untapped enemies this turn as though they were tapped.
If I flip BB back to his Bot mode, does the Alt-mode ability still persist? From the wording I would assume yes, but wanted to make sure.
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes. The effect applies for the entire turn, even if Bumblebee flips to his other mode.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-11" tags="Grimlock - Powerful Commander,Dinobot Sludge - Mighty Stomper,Volcanicus - Fiery Champion">
      <question>
If I start my game with Wave 1 Dinobot Sludge and Wave 2 Grimlock and Dinobot Swoop. After I was able to bring the rest of my Wave 2 Dinobots into the KO area, Grimlock is KO’d and Dinobot Sludge was the only card left on my battlefield in bot mode. On my turn, I played the Dinobot Enigma and then flipped Dinobot Sludge to take all of his damage, was this correct? Also, what if I had played a Brainstorm then an I Still Function! and then a Dinobot Enigma after which I would flip Dinobot Sludge? Is that a better scenario?
      </question>
      <answer>
In your first scenario, Volcanicus appears on the battlefield with 55 damage counters on him. 
In your second scenario, you can I Still Function! one of the five Dinobots and then use the Dinobot Engima to form Volcanicus. Volcanicus will have 54 damage counters on him (because of the 1 damage ISF! repairs). No matter what, he will be KO’d at the end of the turn, so repairing him with Dinobot Sludge probably won’t do a lot.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="528-12" tags="Autobot Cosmos - Recon &amp; Communication">
      <question>
I attack with Autobot Cosmos in bot form and have 2 cards left in my deck, they are both orange. Do I shuffle the deck because there are zero cards, or do I reshuffle on my opponent's turn when I am forced to draw?
      </question>
      <answer>
You shuffle your deck as soon as there are no cards left.
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
