<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-10-11" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360035148411-Rules-Roundup-10-11-19" published_date="2019-10-11" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="7-1">
      <question>
I play Brainstorm. Using my 2 actions, I play Ancient Wisdom first, then System Reboot. I draw Unleash Potential off of System Reboot, do I get to play it for free now?
        </question>
      <answer>
Both Brainstorm and Ancient Wisdom resolve &#x201C;top to bottom&#x201D;. When you play Brainstorm, then you play Ancient Wisdom, you must play Unleash Potential at that moment. In your case, you&#x2019;ve moved past Ancient Wisdom and are continuing with Brainstorm, playing System Reboot. It&#x2019;s now too late to play Unleash Potential with your previous Ancient Wisdom.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-2" tags="Bold,Tough,Pierce">
      <question>
There's now an upgrade that says "Opponents cannot have more than Bold 2" or something to that effect. Mechanically, 3 instances of Bold 2 have worked the same as Bold 6. It hasn't been explicitly said that Bold and Tough stack just like Pierce, so does it?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes. Bold, Tough, Pierce, and other key words with numerical values do stack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-3">
      <question>
In a turn where I play Brainstorm, allowing for 2 more actions. I play I Still Function!, bringing Buzzsaw (Spy) from the KO Area, then I play Recover Cassette, putting Buzzsaw underneath Soundwave. Will that cancel out I Still Function!?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, it will. Once Buzzsaw goes underneath Soundwave, all existing and/or pending game effects stop applying to him.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-4" tags="Major Shockwave - Applied Sciences - Scientist">
      <question>
How does Major Shockwave work with regard to the keyword Focus? Say for instance that Major Shockwave has Focus 1 and you look at the first card of your deck with Focus. Are you then allowed to look at the next card of your deck before deciding if you want to scrap or keep the Focused card?
        </question>
      <answer>
The card you&#x2019;re looking at while Focusing is still the top card of your deck. You must decide to scrap it or not. Only after deciding to scrap it are you allowed to look at the new top card of your deck.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-5" tags="Brave">
      <question>
What happens if two characters both have Brave? Do I get to pick out of the two, which receives the damage?
        </question>
      <answer>
If two or more characters have Brave, the attacking player can choose between them.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-6">
      <question>
I have a Torox with Tooth and Claw and Mining Pick in his Armor Slot, as well as Divebomb with a Field Communicator. If I combine them into Predaking via the Predacon Enigma, am I required to keep Tooth and Claw in order to carry the Mining Pick to Predaking's armor slot, or can I bring the Field Communicator instead?
        </question>
      <answer>
Once an Upgrade is legally put into a slot, it stays there, even if the ability that allowed it to be upgraded in the first place no longer applies. In your example, you could keep Mining Pick in Predaking&#x2019;s Armor slot. Upgrades that are on characters that combine into Combiners are considered to stay in their slots, even though those slots now belong to the Combiner.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-8">
      <question>
Dreadwing is equipped with Forcefield, Emergency Defense Field, and Backup Bag takes 5 or more attack damage, what happens? I think that the Forcefield would try to scrap first (reducing the damage to 4) and the Back-Up Bag would save it... then the Emergency Defense Field would make Dreadwing take no damage and scrap. Is that right?
        </question>
      <answer>
That is correct!
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-9" tags="Permitted and Banned Cards">
      <question>
Are Character cards with Voice Actor signatures on them (if you got your card signed, something I might want to do) legal for tournament play? If so, are there any specifics? (in another TCG, as long as the signature doesn't cover any of the text on the card; it's legal)
        </question>
      <answer>
Good question! For Character Cards, markings/signatures should not obscure critical card information like rules text or character stats. Otherwise, that should be fine. Ultimately, however, legality of an individual card is up to the Head Judge of the event in question.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-10" tags="Sergeant Cog - Artillery - Mechanic,Private Red Heat - Infantry - Emergency Response">
      <question>
I have a question regarding Sergeant Cog. When he dies, I place him on Private Red Heat, and Trigger his ability. Let&#x2019;s say I draw 2 cards. I can then upgrade each of my characters, and let&#x2019;s say I play Field Communicator on one of my specialists from the Cog trigger, do I resolve Field Communicator&#x2019;s trigger before finishing the last Cog upgrade trigger, or do I finish the Cog trigger, and then resolve the Field Communicator trigger?
        </question>
      <answer>
Finish the Cog trigger completely, then resolve any resulting triggers like Field Communicator in an order of your choosing.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-11">
      <question>
If I then swap all of those upgrades with Red Heat, I can then choose the order again. From this I play a Multi-Mission Gear and play a Brainstorm, do I need to finish prior triggers before Brainstorm, or can I still choose the order?
        </question>
      <answer>
If you swap upgrades with Red Heat, you can have a lot of triggers, including another Cog trigger. You choose to resolve each of these triggers one at a time. If you choose Multi-Mission Gear&#x2019;s trigger to play Brainstorm, you now must finish Brainstorm&#x2019;s effect before continuing with your remaining triggers caused by Red Heat&#x2019;s swap.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-12">
      <question>
I&#x2019;m playing with a plane card, for example Captain Starscream, and it has on it the utility card Energy Pack. The total damage he has on him at the time is 19 and then I play the utility card Crash Landing on him, scrapping the Energy Pack and instantly KO&#x2019;ing him, does the Crash Landing take effect or not?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, Crash Landing only triggers on your opponent's turn, so it would not trigger here.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
