<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-10-25" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360035195972-Rules-Roundup-10-25-19" published_date="2019-10-25" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="8-1" tags="Razorclaw - Predacon Leader,Stealth">
      <question>
Razorclaw&#x2019;s robot mode ability says that when he flips to that mode he can attack untapped characters that turn as though they were tapped. If a character has Stealth when untapped, does Razorclaw treat them as tapped or untapped for the purpose of their Stealth?
        </question>
      <answer>
The character will still have Stealth. Razorclaw&#x2019;s ability changes the way that Razorclaw can attack but doesn&#x2019;t actually change the Tapped/Untapped state of other cards.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="8-2" tags="Infractions">
      <question>
As is my understanding, the majority of infractions which occur in the Transformers TCG can easily be addressed through other resources such as the WPN Tournament rules document, but I feel there are some situations which are exclusive to the Transformers TCG. In particular, what should occur when a player forgets to draw their card at the beginning of the turn, and neither player realizes until after combat flips have occurred? Obviously not drawing a card in this instance has the possibility to be advantageous for the active player.
My second question is similar but slightly different. How does the above ruling pertain to situations when the card draw is from a triggered ability, such as Private Firedrive's attack trigger?
        </question>
      <answer>
As long as it&#x2019;s still the same turn, the player should just draw the card when the error is noticed. It usually doesn&#x2019;t matter if the card they draw isn&#x2019;t the card they would have drawn had they drawn at the right time. However, if the player has gained knowledge of the top card of their deck or manipulated it in some way, such as with Plan, you can back up if possible, or come to another mutually agreed upon solution, such as drawing the second card of their deck. If you&#x2019;re in a tournament, a Judge should be notified as soon as the error is discovered. It doesn&#x2019;t matter whether the draw is from the normal start of turn or from a triggered ability or something else.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="8-3">
      <question>
Finally, how does Dreadwing - Sky Destroyer&#x2019;s combine ability work with this scenario? Does the &#x201C;untap step&#x201D; happen before the end of turn step? Do they happen in a sequence of the active player&#x2019;s choice? Or does the untapping of all characters happen even before this?
        </question>
      <answer>
Characters untap before the end of turn step, so you both players would untap all of their characters, then you could combine Dreadwing, then your opponent could start their turn.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="8-4">
      <question>
This was written in Rules Roundup 10/11/19:
&#x201C;I play Brainstorm. Using my 2 actions, I play Ancient Wisdom first, then System Reboot. I draw Unleash Potential off of System Reboot, do I get to play it for free now?
Both Brainstorm and Ancient Wisdom resolve &#x201C;top to bottom&#x201D;. When you play Brainstorm, then you play Ancient Wisdom, you must play Unleash Potential at that moment. In your case, you&#x2019;ve moved past Ancient Wisdom and are continuing with Brainstorm, playing System Reboot. It&#x2019;s now too late to play Unleash Potential with your previous Ancient Wisdom.&#x201D;
Would this rule also apply to Tech Research? You must play a Superior upgrade after playing Tech Research or else that Tech Research is not forfeit. Example: I play Brainstorm first, then I play Tech Research, then I play Medic. Can I play Superior Jetpack?
        </question>
      <answer>
Superior upgrades only check to see if you have played Tech Research at some point previously in your turn. Therefore, there is no issue with playing other cards between Tech Research and a Superior upgrade.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="8-5">
      <question>
Along those lines, am I limited to playing 1 Unleashed Potential per Ancient Wisdom? Am I limited to playing 1 Superior upgrade per Tech Research?
        </question>
      <answer>
Your Ancient Wisdom allows you to play a single Unleash Potential. After you&#x2019;ve played Tech Research, the number of Superior upgrades you can play is only limited by the number of upgrades you can play.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="8-6" tags="Torox - Fueler">
      <question>
Say I have Torox in alt mode and my opponent plays I Still Function! Since ISF repairs 1 damage when it pulls the character from the KO area, and Torox&#x2019; alt mode skill shuts down healing, would the character being revived with ISF:
    a) Get brought back, then immediately KO&#x2019;d due to having damage equal to its health
    b) Not get brought back since ISF would have no effect after the card would be played
    c) Get brought back as normal, ignoring Torox&#x2019; skill
        </question>
      <answer>
    The character is brought back and then immediately KO&#x2019;d as it has an amount of damage equal to its health.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="8-7">
      <question>
Can Escape Route be used on a triple changer in Alt 2 to flip into Alt 1 and vice-versa? Are triple changers affected by Roll-Out if they are not in bot mode?
        </question>
      <answer>
Escape Route and Roll Out! convert characters from Bot mode to Alt mode. They cannot convert Triple Changers from one Alt mode to another Alt mode.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="8-8">
      <question>
I have a question concerning Heroism, the Wave 1 Utility. I have Heroism on a character and place the Take Cover! secret action during my turn. During my opponent's turn I reveal Take Cover!. When my opponent goes to attack and the attack damage is transferred to the character with Heroism what type of damage is this? Heroism is a tad vague on the damage that the character is taking. If its not attack damage I assume that Take Cover! could blank the attack effectively?
        </question>
      <answer>
Damage redirected by Heroism is still attack damage, so it is not affected by Take Cover.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="8-9">
      <question>
If I have Infiltrate face down on the table during my opponent's turn when they play a secret action, can I reveal Infiltrate on the off chance that my opponent's secret action has an orange icon?
        </question>
      <answer>
No. Although the game knows that Secret Actions are Actions, it doesn&#x2019;t know specifically which one it is, so it doesn&#x2019;t know which Battle Icons it has, meaning Infiltrate will not work in this scenario.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
