<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-03-22" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-32219/2061330717322076/" published_date="2019-03-22" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="322-1" tags="Blurr - Fastest Bot in the Galaxy">
      <question>
Does Blurr’s ability combine with Mining Pick to allow you to plan 2 again on the attack of the untapped character to get +5?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-2" tags="Insecticon Skrapnel - Insecticon Leader">
      <question>
In the FAQ for Skrapnel it states, "Any damage dealt to Insecticon Skrapnel while he's defending will count. If the attacker has an ability that deals 1 damage to Insecticon Skrapnel, then he can't take more than 2 more damage from the attack." However, in a Rules Roundup (2/18 for reference) it was said, "Attack Damage is damage dealt by the attacking character as a result of an attack. Any other damage, including damage dealt during an attack because of an ability is non-attack damage." Is Skrapnel's FAQ incorrect or am I missing something? 
      </question>
      <answer>
The first answer you referenced is from an outdated FAQ. Please disregard.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-3" tags="Play">
      <question>
To scrap an upgrade from my own character, would I need a new upgrade in my hand, or can I just scrap it without a replacement upgrade?
      </question>
      <answer>
You need a new upgrade to replace a scrapped upgrade. Your robots like their weapons and don’t cotton to giving them up willingly.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-4" tags="Demolisher - Devoted Decepticon,Megatron - Decepticon Leader">
      <question>
Regarding character triggers, the following scenario is Demolisher/Darkmount/Common Megatron all in bot mode. I play Brainstorm > Hunker Down > Rapid Conversion. Hunker Down flips all 3 to alt mode, then I play armors from the scrap pile if able. Once Hunker Down is complete, I play Rapid Conversion targeting Megatron to flip him into bot mode. Brainstorm is now resolved. Moving on to character triggers, would Demolisher’s ability now draw 1 or 2 cards? Would I be allowed to use Megatron’s flip ability? 
      </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, Demolisher’s ability would draw 1 card and you would be able to use Megatron’s flip ability.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-5">
      <question>
There’s all these status effect rulings like Razorclaw flipping to bot mode and having his ability carry over to Predaking. This is because Razorclaw isn’t leaving play, he’s just changing modes. Shouldn’t this work similarly with Static Laser of Ironhide? It reads, “When the upgraded character is NOT Ironhide,” but it doesn’t say the character has to be NAMED Ironhide. 
      </question>
      <answer>
On Static Laser of Ironhide, “NOT Ironhide” should also be taken as “NOT named Ironhide”.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-6" tags="Blurr - Fastest Bot in the Galaxy">
      <question>
How does brave interact with Blurr? Let’s say an opponent taps their first character which has brave. I attack with Blurr and he lands attack damage on the tapped brave character. Is Blurr able to still attack an untapped opponent or does he have to/is he able to attack the brave opponent?
      </question>
      <answer>
Blurr must attack an untapped character and thus is unable to attack a tapped character with brave. If your opponent also had an untapped character with brave, Blurr would have to attack that character.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-7" tags="Air Raid - Fearless Flyer">
      <question>
Does Air Raid's bot mode ability trigger if you use Armed Hovercraft to do 1 damage to an enemy team?
      </question>
      <answer>
Armed Hovercraft does the damage, not the character that has it equipped.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-8" tags="Wheeljack - Weapons Inventor">
      <question>
Wheeljack is in car mode is equipped with the following: 
Multi-Tool, Turbo Boosters, and Scrapper Gauntlets.
Bumblebee - Courageous Scout is tapped, in car mode, and equipped with the following:
Drill Arms, Crushing Size, and Multi Mission Gear.
For my action, I play Swap Parts between Wheeljack and Bumblebee. There are a LOT of abilities that fire off here and I'm curious to know, what would be the appropriate order? Most importantly, when does Wheeljack's ability take priority?
      </question>
      <answer>
These would all trigger at the same, so you would choose the order they happen in.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-9">
      <question>
If I attack with Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend, equipped with Recon System, can I select the scrapped card since it was still flipped during an attack by Optimus Prime?
      </question>
      <answer>
If you scrap an action, Optimus Prime won’t be able to find it, as it has left the played area.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-10" tags="Dreadwing - Sky Destroyer">
      <question>
My question revolves around Dreadwing, and if there are 2 Security Consoles equipped in the 2 Utility Slots. Would you resolve each Security Console's effects one at a time? Or would you Draw 2 Cards and then Plan 2? (As each Security Console gives lets your Draw a card then Plan 1)
      </question>
      <answer>
Multiple Security Consoles should be resolved one at a time. Their effects do not combine. If you put a card on the top of your deck from the first one, be sure to act surprised when you draw it again.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="322-11" tags="Ironhide - Steadfast Brawler,Optimus Maximus - Ultimate Defender">
      <question>
Since Ironhide and Optimus Prime are both components of Optimus Maximus in Wave 2, how do their unique weapons from Wave 1 interact with the Combiner? Will Optimus Maximus take damage from Static Laser of Ironhide? Can I play Ion Blaster of Optimus Prime on a combined Optimus Maximus?
      </question>
      <answer>
Optimus Maximus would take the damage from Static Laser of Ironhide, as he is not named Ironhide. You can keep Ion Blaster of Optimus Prime if you already had one upgraded to Optimus Prime - Gleaming Commander, but you could not put one onto Optimus Maximus.
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
