<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-04-26" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-42619/2114132452041902/" published_date="2019-04-26" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="426-1">
      <question>
Does Peace Through Tyranny let you go first after everybody untaps? Or does it let you take a second turn right after your current attack skipping the opponents turn?
      </question>
      <answer>
Peace Through Tyranny allows you to have an extra turn after the turn in which you play it. After that turn, it’s your opponent’s turn.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-2" tags="Play">
      <question>
If my opponent has all tapped enemies and I have 3 untapped enemies, do I start my regular turn drawing my card, flipping one character, playing one action and upgrade, then attack with all 3 of my character one after another skipping the opponents turns until all of my characters are tapped? Or after each attack I make is my opponent allowed to draw a card, flip, and play an action and upgrade?
      </question>
      <answer>
All three attacks happen during the same turn. After your turn is done, then your opponent’s turn begins.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-3" tags="Major Shockwave - Applied Sciences - Scientist">
      <question>
My question is regarding the new Major Shockwave. In its ability when it states “Decepticon cards,” what does that mean exactly? I know certain cards like Decepticon Crown and Swindled have Decepticon-specific effects and have purple coloring in their titles. Are those the types of cards that could be used with new Shockwave’s ability?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-4" tags="Jetfire - Air Guardian">
      <question>
Given Hunker Down, which says "Flip each of your characters from bot mode to tank mode. Then for each of your tanks that isn't upgraded with an Armor, put an Armor on it from your scrap pile", bypasses the requirement to play Tech Research for Superior Plating, does the same apply to Jetfire, whose wording is "When you flip to this mode - Put an Armor or Utility from your scrap pile onto this character"?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-5" tags="Play">
      <question>
Do the abilities that last "until end of turn" last until the end of your attack or until all cards untap?
      </question>
      <answer>
Neither! They last until the end of your turn. Usually, the attack is the last thing to happen during a turn, but this isn’t always true. As abilities can trigger both after the attack and at the end of turn and untapping.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-6">
      <question>
Can you elaborate on today's ruling? Wouldn't Security Console no longer be in play to resolve its trigger? Or is the effect independent of the card that triggered it once the trigger occurs?
      </question>
      <answer>
Once an ability triggers, it will happen even if the card that has that ability leaves the battlefield (or other zone, if appropriate) in the meantime.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-7" tags="Sunstreaker - Bold Warrior,Cliffjumper - Renegade Warrior">
      <question>
If I flip Sunstreaker in KO area to alt mode to draw a card, would that still trigger Cliffjumper’s alt mode skill to draw a card?
      </question>
      <answer>
No. Abilities only look at things on the battlefield unless specifically stated.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-8">
      <question>
When I play Roll Out!, do all the flips to alt mode happen at once or do they happen one at a time. Also, how does this work with skills that have the "When you flip to this mode" clause?
      </question>
      <answer>
All of the bots flip at the same time. If this causes more than one Ability to trigger, you can resolve those triggers in any order.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-9" tags="Specialist Ratchet - Engineering - Rescue &amp; Repair">
      <question>
Say Specialist Ratchet (In bot mode) got a +3 attack bonus from his skill, and then flipped to alt mode. Would that +3 attack carry over into alt mode for the turn?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-10" tags="Specialist Ratchet - Engineering - Rescue &amp; Repair,Private Trailbreaker - Infantry - Fortification &amp; Defense,Major Ultra Magnus - Infantry - City Commander">
      <question>
For Wave 3 Ratchet, Ultra Magnus, Trailbreaker and Wheeljack. Do you search for their related card before you draw starting hand or after?
      </question>
      <answer>
Before the game starts, find their related card, shuffle, then draw three cards for your opening hand.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-11" tags="Slipstream - Strategic Seeker,Alpha Bravo - Airborne Special Ops">
      <question>
If I attack with Slipstream in alt mode with no damage, and my opponent has an Alpha Bravo in alt mode, is Slipstream able to fling the damage Alpha Bravo or does she miss her window to activate because she had no damage at the time the attack was declared? Also, if both characters had 1 health remaining, which effect would proc first? And would Alpha Bravo be able to resolve if Slipstream's ability KO's him?
      </question>
      <answer>
In the first scenario, Slipstream’s ability triggers first and doesn’t have any damage to move, then Alpha Bravo would deal 1 damage to Slipstream. In the second, both abilities will trigger, meaning Slipstream will move 1 damage to Alpha Bravo, KO’ing him. Then, Alpha Bravo’s ability damages Slipstream, bringing her health to 1.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-12" tags="Secret Action">
      <question>
Based on the fact that Special Ops Mission exists in conjunction with Brainstorm, does that mean you cannot play a Secret Action using a battle card effect (like those on Multi-Mission Gear or Brainstorm) unless it specifically says so?
      </question>
      <answer>
Things that effect actions also effect secret actions, which are a subset of actions.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-13" tags="Captain Wheeljack - Engineering - Scientist">
      <question>
Does Captain Wheeljack's bot mode skill trigger if you play Special Ops Mission and then play 2 secret actions?
      </question>
      <answer>
Sure does.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="426-14">
      <question>
Does Thundercracker - Mach Warrior get +1 attack if you play a Secret Action?
      </question>
      <answer>
That’s a big 10-4.
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
