<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/sections/360006518052-Rules-Roundups-FAQs">
  <target name="Rules Roundup 2019-07-12" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033430171-Rules-Roundup-7-12-19" published_date="2019-07-12" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
    <entry id="1-1">
      <question>
I have a question about Wave 1 Shockwave&#x2019;s bot mode ability. If I cause my opponent to scrap several cards at once (like with Fog of War), do they take 1 damage per card they scrap of just 1 damage in total.
</question>
      <answer>
1 damage per card scrapped.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-2">
      <question>
If Thrust has a Grenade Launcher and boosts a character that is attacking, and the opponent reveals a Bolster, to play a Scrapper Gauntlets to scrap the Grenade Launcher, does Thrust donate 7 or 3 attack to the attacking character?
</question>
      <answer>
7 attack. The amount has already been locked in.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-3">
      <question>
I was playing with Bombshell - Decepticon Psy Ops with 5 health left, against Shockwave -Cybertron Commander. I scrapped 11 cards to KO him, but should his bot mode ability have triggered, killing me in the process?
</question>
      <answer>
Shockwave&#x2019;s ability will trigger 11 times, but if those are the last two characters on the battlefield, your opponent will lose the game because Shockwave has been KO&#x2019;d by Bombshell&#x2019;s ability, but Bombshell is not yet KO&#x2019;d by Shockwave&#x2019;s ability.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-4">
      <question>
Does Skywarp &#x2013; Teleporting Seeker&#x2019;s bot mode ability trigger when playing a Secret Action from hand since the pip color is hidden information from your opponent? Will his bot mode ability trigger if it is played from the top of the deck via Leap of Faith since the pip color is no longer hidden information?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, Skywarp&#x2019;s bot mode ability would be triggered by a Secret Action as the battle icon color is hidden. It will still trigger if Leap of Faith plays a Secret Action because at the time you play the Secret Action, the Secret Action has no battle icons (it&#x2019;s not very secret).
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-5">
      <question>
Focus says &#x201C;Before flipping battle cards when battling&gt;, and Anticipation Engine says &#x201C;When the upgraded character attacks&gt;. Will Anticipation Engine trigger and resolve before Focus?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-6">
      <!-- GENERAL -->
      <question>
Can you scrap cards from your hand? This came up from playing a lot of the Turbo format with my kids. Inevitably someone had one or two cards that you couldn&#x2019;t play with the characters. If you&#x2019;re allowed to scrap them from your hand when drawn it would still allow those cards to be useful for the pips when battling.
</question>
      <answer>
You cannot scrap cards from your hand for no reason or simply because you&#x2019;d like to, but there are a plethora of effects in the game (such as green battle icons) that allow you to swap cards in and out of your hand.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-7">
      <question>
With Pop a Wheelie, the 2nd attack isn&#x2019;t from the same bot that attacked the turn the card was played, correct? I would need to have another untapped motorcycle make the 2nd attack?
</question>
      <answer>
Correct. If you have another untapped motorcycle on your team, you can attack again. However, note that the first attacker does not have to be a motorcycle.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-8">
      <question>
If I attack with a character that is equipped with Battering Ram and deal damage to a Triple Changer, does my opponent get to choose the mode they change to or do they have to change from Alt 1 to character and vice versa.
</question>
      <answer>
Your opponent can choose which mode of its other modes to flip to.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-9">
      <question>
Grapple reads you get an attack/defence bonus for flipping battle icons of "exactly 4 different colors". What happens when you flip MORE than 4 colors during your turn, say green, orange, white, green and black? Does his ability still trigger? And does this also apply to his ability on other side of the card?
</question>
      <answer>
If a number of *colors* other than four colors is flipped, Grapple&#x2019;s bot mode ability will not trigger. For his alt mode ability, you can still scrap your hand, but you will only do damage if you&#x2019;ve scrapped exactly four different battle icon colors.

Editor&#x2019;s note: It&#x2019;s important when considering Grapple&#x2019;s abilities to make a distinction between the number of battle icon *colors* and the number of battle icons. So long as the number of battle icon colors is exactly 4, the number of cards they appear on do not matter. So, in the scenario described in this question, his ability would trigger as four colors appear, even though there are multiple instances of a green battle icon.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-10">
      <!-- GENERAL -->
      <question>
Do you have to attach the Battle Master's Upgrade side? My Wife pulled 2 Lionizers in Turbo Sealed but pull no Orange. When I KO'd Lionizer, would she be forced to scrap EM24 IR Laser Launcher, or could she choose not to attach Lionizer?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, you must attach the Battle Master&#x2019;s Upgrade side. When you attach the Battle Master, you must scrap the older upgrade; in this case, EM24 IR Laser Launcher.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-11">
      <!-- GENERAL -->
      <question>
Are the current face-down side of a character card considered Hidden Information?
</question>
      <answer>
No. You may see the face-down sides of your opponent&#x2019;s character cards at any time, but please ask respectfully.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-12">
      <!-- GENERAL -->
      <question>
If I open a card in a Limited Format that says "grab a card from outside the game" am I allowed to dip into my personal collection for this (assuming I brought it ahead of time) or just the sideboard of my Limited Pool? If I have a lesser collection (or am just lazy), am I allowed to use cards from my Sideboard for my Outside-of-the-Game-Board? Or is this a Head Judge for an event decision?
</question>
      <answer>
For casual play, you are allowed to use whatever parameters your play group has decided on. For competitive play, in Limited, you are only allowed to draw &#x201C;outside the game&#x201D; cards from your Limited pool.

Editor&#x2019;s Note: In our initial ruling, we misstated our answer and accidentally ruled that &#x201C;outside the game&#x201D; cards must be limited to one&#x2019;s sideboard. This is incorrect.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-13">
      <question>
Say I play Infiltrate on my turn, then on my opponent's turn they play Focus Fire, which lets them play a second Focus Fire, which then lets them play the 3rd Focus Fire.

If I reveal my Infiltrate and negate their first Focus Fire, does it negate the other 2 as well since the first one is discarded?
</question>
      <answer>
If you negate a Focus Fire, it also negates the ability of Focus Fire to play other instances of Focus Fire, stopping the chain.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-14">
      <question>
If I played Heroism on Insecticon Leader Skrapnel, would the redirected attack damage to Skrapnel still be reduced to 3?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, redirected damage from Heroism is still attack damage.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-15">
      <!-- GENERAL (as well as Brainstorm/PTT -->
      <question>
Secret Actions say they scrap at the end of my opponent's turn. If I Brainstorm, Secret Action, Peace Through Tyranny, how long does the Secret Action stay out? Will it stay out for my second turn, until it is my opponent's turn, and then scrap at the end of their turn? Or do Secret Actions just scrap at the end of the following turn, so it would scrap at the end of my second turn?
</question>
      <answer>
It will stay out for your second turn and scrap at the end of your opponent&#x2019;s turn.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-16">
      <question>
If I am playing a team of Decepticon characters, can I still play Press the Advantage? None of my characters would get an attack boost, but a defending Decepticon gets -2 defense?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, you may play Press the Advantage. You don&#x2019;t have an Autobot to give +2 attack to, but you can still give an enemy Decepticon -2 defense.
Note: Any Decepticons on your team will no longer be welcome at the Decepticon company barbecue after you do this.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-17">
      <question>
If I play Hunker Down and flip Darkmount to tank mode can I then choose to activate to Darkmount&#x2019;s ability to discard a card from my hand before equipping an armor?
</question>
      <answer>
No, you must finish resolving Hunker Down before any triggered abilities from character flips are resolved.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-18">
      <question>
How does Alpha Trion&#x2019;s ability interact with Inverted?
</question>
      <answer>
While equipped with inverted, an attacking Alpha Trion may play an action with an orange icon they&#x2019;ve flipped (because it counts as a blue icon). He will not be able to play any actions with blue icons you may flip, because they count as orange. &#x201C;Good job!&#x201D; &#x2013; The Design Team.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-19">
      <question>
Ancient Wisdom states, &#x201C;You may play Unleash Potential.&#x201D; Do that mean it&#x2019;s allowing you it as a second action for that turn? If yes, can you play two Unleash Potentials? The text doesn&#x2019;t specify a quantity.
</question>
      <answer>
You may play one Unleash Potential.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-20">
      <question>
Can I play Ion Blaster of Optimus Prime on General Optimus Prime? Ion Blaster says "Play on Optimus Prime only", so would the word "General" in his name disallow it?
</question>
      <answer>
Just because he&#x2019;s a General doesn&#x2019;t mean he&#x2019;s any less Prime! You may indeed play Ion Blaster on General Prime.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-21">
      <question>
If I use I Still Function to bring back Skywarp - Teleporting Seeker from the KO area, does his ability trigger (assuming he's on his bot mode)?
</question>
      <answer>
No. The ability only functions on the battlefield. By the time he&#x2019;s returned to the battlefield, you&#x2019;ve already played I Still Function.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-22">
      <question>
If I were to have any Battle Master in upgrade form attached to a character ,and my opponent plays Raider Ion Storm&#x2019;s ability of &#x201C;when this attacks return the defender&#x2019;s upgrade to its owner&#x2019;s hand,&#x201D; what happens to the Battle Masters? If they leave the battlefield, do they go to the KO area?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes. They go to the KO area.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-23">
      <question>
If I Bolster into a Multi Mission Gear, can I play Dampening Field and it activates?
</question>
      <answer>
You can play Dampening Field, but it would be past the point where it would trigger.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-24">
      <question>
What happens if you use a green battle icon if your opponent has Decepticon Shockwave - Cybertron Commander in bot mode?
</question>
      <answer>
Green battle icons are a swap effect, not a scrap-from-your-hand effect.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-25">
      <question>
When Private Pteraxadon is in weapon mode (AKA Binary Edgewing Scythe), it says the defender's base armor value becomes zero during this battle. Does that count any armor bonuses from upgrades as well? Or does it only apply to the printed value on the bot?
</question>
      <answer>
Private Pteraxodon&#x2019;s weapon mode ability specifies that it only applies to an opponent&#x2019;s base defense, so it would not include defense from any upgrades or flipped battle cards.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-26">
      <question>
When I attack with Blitzwing - Relentless Foe and don't flip at least [Orange][Blue]... I don't draw a card, but can I still flip to other mode after the battle?
</question>
      <answer>
No, you may not. That is all one ability.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-27">
      <question>
Question regarding Backup Bag + Grenade Launcher / Power Punch / RR Disruptor Blade Can I scrap backup bag instead of a weapon?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes!
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-28">
      <question>
Question regarding Dismantling Claw / Reactive Armor. When character with such upgrade is KO&#x2019;d can I use this ability?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, you can!
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-29">
      <question>
When you "put a cassette from the battlefield under it" does the mini-cassette heal to full or keep its damage/upgrades?
</question>
      <answer>
All of the damage is removed, and the cassette is essentially healed to full. All upgrades attached to the cassette when it&#x2019;s moved under its deployer are scrapped.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-30">
      <question>
I have a tapped Flamewar - Veteran Decepticon with 3 life remaining with 2 other untapped characters and a facedown Bolster. My opponent has 3 untapped characters and taps their attacker, declaring Flamewar as my defender. Because the conditions are met, I reveal Bolster and play Multi-Mission Gear onto my Flamewar. That triggers Multi-Mission Gear and allows me to play an action, which I choose to play One Shall Stand, One Shall Fall targeting my Flamewar and one of my opponent's characters. This kills my Flamewar but the attacker still lives. What happens in this scenario? Does my opponent lose their attack because the defender was killed prior to battle cards being flipped? Or does my opponent get to choose another attack target?
</question>
      <answer>
Your opponent has already chosen who they are attacking, so the attack would end because there is no longer a defender.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="1-31">
      <question>
Infiltrate and Peace Through Tyranny - since the ruling was made that one can choose if a Secret Action triggers. Can I wait to see if the person playing PTT KO's one of his characters before deciding to reveal Infiltrate?
</question>
      <answer>
No, you cannot. KO&#x2019;ing a character is part of Peace Through Tyranny&#x2019;s effect, so it would be too late to reveal your Infiltrate.
Also, it would just be a straight up super not cool thing to do, man.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Rules Roundup 2019-07-29" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033433911-Rules-Roundup-7-29-19" published_date="2019-07-29" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
    <entry id="2-1">
      <question>
How does Predaking hold five weapons? Does he wad them up into a ball and throw them at his opponents? Besides, those are really big hands -- it's not like he'll be able to squeeze five triggers at once let alone one. How would one wield, like, three axes anyway? Or three Drill Arms? Oh god.
</question>
      <answer>
One finger per trigger.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-2">
      <!-- GENERAL -->
      <question>
Concerning &#x201C;start of turn&#x201D; effects timing around the drawing 1 card from the general card rules: which of the following is true:
    You Draw 1 card from general game rules, then activate Start of Turn Effects (like Omnibots&#x2019; start of turn effects playing upgrades).
    2. You activate Start of Turn Effects, then Draw 1 card from general game rules.
    3. Drawing 1 Card from general game rules counts as a Start of Turn Effect, and can be resolved in the order of the player's choosing.
</question>
      <answer>
    1.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-3">
      <question>
If you have Energy Pack on an 11-star character who is nearly dead, then attach Erratic Energy Grenade, removing Energy Pack, which KO&#x2019;s your character automatically since their health bonus is no longer there, does Erratic Energy Grenade&#x2019;s second effect still activate?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, Erratic Energy&#x2019;s Grenade&#x2019;s second effect would still activate in this scenario. Erratic Energy Grenade replaces Energy Pack without anything happening in between.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-4">
      <question>
If I use Recover Cassette to put a Mini-Cassette under Major Soundwave, what happens to the Mini-Cassette when Major Soundwave is KO&#x2019;d?
</question>
      <answer>
It stays under Major Soundwave.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-5">
      <question>
Can you use Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend to play a Secret Action?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes. Secret Actions are actions.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-6">
      <question>
If Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend plays an orange battle icon card off his flips, and I reveal Infiltrate to scrap it, does the battle icon still count when calculating attack/defense and damage?
</question>
      <answer>
The orange battle icon card increases OPBL&#x2019;s attack after it is flipped. Removing the card from the played area after it&#x2019;s flipped doesn&#x2019;t change that.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-7">
      <question>
Can you use Major Shockwave&#x2019;s bot mode ability to plays cards from the top of your deck if you go first and it&#x2019;s the first turn?
</question>
      <answer>
Nope!
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-8">
      <question>
If I use Swap Missions to untap a tapper character and then tap an untapped character, and that same untapped character has a tap ability &#x2013; does Swap Missions trigger that tapped ability?
</question>
      <answer>
No, tap abilities (ones with the tap symbol) happen when the player activates them on their turn and don&#x2019;t happen if the character is tapped in any other way.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-9">
      <question>
Is there a central place where all previous rules round ups can be accessed?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes!
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-10">
      <question>
Correct me if I'm wrong, but you can put Decepticon Cassettes underneath Blaster and vice-versa with Soundwave since they are "Mini-Cassettes". Does this count as starting the game with Decepticon characters or Autobot characters or are they effectively "out of the game"?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, any Mini-Cassette can be put under Blaster or Soundwave regardless of faction. Any Mini-Cassettes you start the game with count toward your starting team. For example, if your starting team has Decepticon characters (including Soundwave) and Autobot Mini-Cassettes, any effect that cares about your starting team being all Decepticons, would not work.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-11">
      <question>
Similarly, if Blaster or Soundwave are KO'd whilst still having Mini-Cassettes beneath them, are the Mini-Cassettes KO'd as well?
</question>
      <answer>
They remain beneath their deployer wherever it physically goes.

For example, if Soundwave was KO&#x2019;d with Buzzsaw still under him, you would have Soundwave in KO, fully damaged with Buzzsaw underneath him with no damage. You could not I Still Function Buzzsaw, but if you ISF&#x2019;d Soundwave, Buzzsaw would remain underneath him when Soundwave returned to the battlefield. At the end of the turn, when Soundwave is KO&#x2019;d again, Buzzsaw would return to KO with him unless you had deployed Buzzsaw during that turn, in which case, Buzzsaw would remain on the battlefield.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-12">
      <question>
Do character abilities still trigger if the requirements are met through cards played but negated by the opponent or otherwise?
For example, Wave 1 Thundercracker&#x2019;s bot mode ability --&gt; Player 1 uses Supercharge, but player 2 reveals Infiltrate and negates Supercharge. Does Thundercracker's ability still trigger because an action was played? Meaning he would indeed get +1?
</question>
      <answer>
The Infiltrate will scrap the action you played and negate its effect, but Thundercracker&#x2019;s ability still triggers because you played an action.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-13">
      <question>
Blaster and Soundwave have the ability to add the cassettes from your starting line up under three when the game starts. This is different to Metroplex text because the card under him start under him and aren&#x2019;t in your lineup. So, if you play either blaster or sound wave with all three cassettes it would make your starting lineup 25 stars. Since both have the text your star cost is then raised by one when does that mean you can only play Blaster/Soundwave with two cassettes? Seeing as 10 + (5+1) + (5+1) would equal 22, there for having the exact number of star cards for each theme deck bringing it to its cap of 25 stars. Would this be correct, or am I reading the card wrong?
</question>
      <answer>
Each mini-cassette you play with a deployer adds 1 star to your star limit above 25, up to 28. You are allowed to add 1-3 stars depending on how many Mini-Cassettes you play with a deployer.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-14">
      <question>
When I attack with Cosmos in bot mode and then Anticipation Engine activates and I flip Rapid Conversion and flip him to alt mode. Would his KO effect take place since he&#x2019;s no longer in bot mode? And I no longer have cards in my deck?
</question>
      <answer>
If during Cosmos&#x2019; attack, Anticipation Engine reveals Rapid Conversion as the last card in your deck, and you play it, you will immediately shuffle your deck, triggering Cosmos&#x2019; ability, then flip Cosmos to Alt Mode.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-15">
      <question>
Energy Pack reads "The upgraded character has +4 health." When I play this on a character does the character get an immediate 4 to its health? Or does it just increase the health total?
</question>
      <answer>
Gaining +4 health has no effect on the amount of damage counters a character has. For example, if you had a character with 10 health and 3 damage counters, upgrading it with Energy Pack results in it having 14 health and 3 damage counters.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-16">
      <question>
The cards Dismantling Claw, Reactive Armor and Personal Targeting Drone say "When this upgrade is scrapped from a character...". Do these effects trigger when the character is KO'd and the upgrade goes to the scrap pile? Do these effects trigger when you replace the upgrade and it goes to the scrap pile?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes and yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-17">
      <question>
Do Battle Masters in Upgrade mode count towards Stars in the KO area for Emergency Maintenance?
</question>
      <answer>
No. When in Upgrade mode, Battle Masters do not count as characters, so they would not be counted by Emergency Maintenance on the battlefield or in the KO area.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-18">
      <question>
Say I have a weapon on a character and Backup Bag as well. For my turn I placed a different or same weapon on the same character. But because I already have a weapon taken up does the original weapon get scrapped or can I keep both weapons and scrap Backup Bag instead?
</question>
      <answer>
Playing the new weapon causes the old weapon to be scrapped, but it&#x2019;s the rules of the game that are doing this, not an effect of the new weapon. Backup Bag affects only cards such as Salvage for Parts or Grenade Launcher.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-19">
      <question>
If I play a card that allows me to play an upgrade, can I play a Superior Plating/Jetpack/Cannon without needing to play Tech Research?
</question>
      <answer>
No.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-20">
      <question>
My opponent has attacked me, and I reveal the Secret Action Bolster. I use Bolster to attach a Multi-Mission Gear to a Specialist. I then use the Action granted by Multi-Mission Gear to play All-Out Attack. World implodes, right?
</question>
      <answer>
Your characters can never attack on your opponent&#x2019;s turn, even if a card seems to say otherwise. Same rules apply even in the event of a galactic implosion and resulting gravitational chaos.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-21">
      <question>
When I equip Erratic Energy Grenade, do I subtract one health right away? Is the beginning of my turn after everyone is tapped and I reset all the characters, and then that's when I subtract one health? Or is my turn right after my opponent finishes their attack?
</question>
      <answer>
Erratic Energy Grenade does 1 damage at the beginning of your turn.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-22">
      <question>
How do I use a Micromaster&#x2019;s tap ability? Let's say Raider Detour. I tap Raider Detour, then scrap a card with a blue battle icon, and draw my 2 cards. Does that mean I have used Raider Detour and now I attack with one of my other characters?
</question>
      <answer>
You can still play an Action or Upgrade if you haven&#x2019;t and would like to, but then you can move on. Each turn, you can use one tap ability. Raider Detour will not be able to attack because he is tapped. However if he were untapped somehow, he would still be able to attack.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-23">
      <question>
My friends and I played a game where Metroplex had Six-Gun deployed in alt mode. The defending player had a tapped character with 1 health left and an untapped, undamaged character. Metroplex converted into bot mode and attacked the character, and Six-Gun's ability KO&#x2019;d the defending character. Does Metroplex still flip battle cards to see if it can use the bot mode ability or does the death of the tapped character mean the attack stops?
</question>
      <answer>
No, Metroplex does not flip battle cards in this scenario.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-24">
      <question>
The question I have today is in regard to attacking with Anticipation Engine. I am playing with a combiner team, and I have just converted my last character. I don't have the Enigma in my hand to play it, so I play a different action instead. I attack using a character with Anticipation Engine, and flip the Enigma. Am I able to play it, transform, and continue the attack with the Combiner, or does my attack get cancelled and it becomes my opponent's turn? (This is because the Enigma has the Combiner enter play untapped) Update to the question, as I see it was already answered in a previous Rules Round-up.
Anticipation Engine + Enigma = Transformed and attacking, but untapped
You said the character was untapped, but still attacking. Does this mean that my opponent can only attack with one character if they have multiple available?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, your opponent can attack with only one character.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-25">
      <question>
Ransack - Insecticon Commando's alt mode flip ability says to move 2 damage counters from another character onto him. Does that include enemy characters? Assuming, of course, that I have a good reason to heal my opponent?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, you can move damage from an opponent&#x2019;s character onto Ransack, should you be so bold.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-26">
      <question>
LV Gamma-Disruptor Launcher states that up to 2 of them can fit in one Weapon Slot. If I were to play a 3rd one, would it replace the 2 already in the Weapon Slot or would it only replace 1 of them?
</question>
      <answer>
It would only replace one of the previously equipped two.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-27">
      <question>
In the FAQ it says that Sergeant Cog, as a Weaponizer, interacts with cards in the same manner as a Battle Master. The battle card Quartermaster specifies recalling a KO'd Battle Master in weapon mode. Will this be able to target Heavy Force Defensebreaker Cannon in the KO pile the same way it would target a Battle Master?
</question>
      <answer>
No, it is a Weaponizer and not a Battle Master.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-28">
      <question>
Question about green battle icons and how the work. The text on a card with a green icon says "After a battle, you swap a card from your hand with a green icon you flipped" does this mean since Swarm makes you flip the battle cards. Can you grab a green icon you flipped for Swarm after you battle?
</question>
      <answer>
No, only cards with green battle icons that you flipped during that battle can be retrieved after the battle.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-29">
      <question>
Blaster vs. Soundwave. Ravage is in the KO area. Step #1, I play brainstorm. Step #2, I play I Still Function, which brings him back with 1 health. Step #3, I play Recover Cassette, which puts him under Soundwave to heal 2 damage. Now for the question: does I Still Function resolve and Ravage goes back into the KO area? Or does Ravage bypass that effect, thus he is not KO&#x2019;d?
</question>
      <answer>
Ravage is not KO&#x2019;d. I Still Function does not find him on the battlefield.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-30">
      <question>
Can a 13-star character be put in the sideboard for a Metroplex deck and still fight with Metro's friends, swapping Metroplex out?
</question>
      <answer>
You can have a 13-star character in your sideboard. However, Metroplex&#x2019;s 3 component bots enter the game only if Metroplex is your starting character. This means you could play the next game with only the 13-star character as your team, but this sounds unwise.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-31">
      <question>
When I flip Blaster to his Bot Mode and Deploy a Mini-Cassette, am I required to play the top card of my deck? If not, can I look at it first?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, you must play the top card of your deck if you are able.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-32">
      <question>
Does Battering Ram function like Cornered! when attacking, so that your opponent gets the ability of the mode flipped to? For example, General Optimus Prime has Battering Ram and hits my Nemesis, flipping him to alt mode. So now my opponent should assign 2 damage to a character of his choice, correct?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes. Battering Ram causes your opponent to flip the character, so abilities like Nemesis&#x2019; will trigger.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-33">
      <question>
If I have Autobot Hot Rod with the AirQuake Hammerclaw, Spare Parts, and Bashing Shield equipped (and no other equipment) and my opponent hits me with a Bashing Shield of their own, am I required to scrap the Spare Parts?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes. Their Bashing Shield would try to scrap your Bashing Shield, and Spare Parts would heroically leap in the way. Using Spare Parts in this scenario is not optional. Thank you, Spare Parts.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-34">
      <question>
If I play Multi-Mission Gear on Private Camshaft first thing on my first turn, then use that to play Treasure Hunt, would the weapons &amp; armor I draw be valid to put on my Omnibots in that "At the start of your first turn &gt; You may play a..." window?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, after you&#x2019;re done with Private Camshaft&#x2019;s ability (including the Treasure Hunt it let you play) you would then handle other Omnibot abilities that trigger &#x201C;at the start of your first turn.&#x201D;
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-35">
      <question>
Once a Battle Master is in the KO pile does it still count as a character while in it's upgrade mode? Can I bring it back to the field with ISF? Is it forced back into bot mode to take the damage if it can? If not does it automatically equip? if it can equip, is it forced to ko pile at the end of the turn?
</question>
      <answer>
No, no, not applicable, not applicable, not applicable.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-36">
      <question>
If I have Captain Starscream in bot mode, and I play Vandalize, and scrapping, say, two upgrades on Enemy 1 and one upgrade on Enemy 2, do I then do two damage to Enemy 1, and one damage to Enemy 2?
</question>
      <answer>
Correct.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-37">
      <question>
Are there any requirements to have the Constructicon Tower in play? Is a single Constructicon sufficient?
</question>
      <answer>
You must have Scrapper on your team to start the game with the Tower in your KO area.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-38">
      <question>
I'm playing Major Soundwave with Raider Ravage and Raider Laserbeak. It's my turn and all of my characters are untapped and in Bot mode. All of my opponents characters are tapped. I attack, or use the tap ability, of both Ravage and Laserbeak, then attack last with Soundwave, triggering his "When this attacks -- Untap each of your Spy Patrols" ability, which untaps Ravage and Laserbeak. After Soundwave's attack, since they were untapped before my turn ended, can I attack/tap again with Ravage and Laserbeak?
</question>
      <answer>
You can attack again, but you cannot use tap abilities once you&#x2019;ve started attacking.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-39">
      <question>
In sanctioned play, if my main deck team consists of General Optimus (Wave 3), Sentinel Ironhide (Wave 2), and Sentinel Prowl (Wave 2), and I have Sentinel Optimus (Wave 2) in my sideboard, can I exchange Optimuses (Optimi?) between games and still get the remaining Sentinels in my KO Area for an Optimus Maximus plan game 2?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-40">
      <question>
If I have Jazz equipped with Point Defense System while defending against an enemy with exactly 2 pierce after combat flips, will this enable Jazz's ability to trigger if I flipped 2 white icons?
</question>
      <answer>
No. Point Defense System doesn&#x2019;t cause a character to gain or lose pierce. The attacking character with pierce 2 will have its pierce reduced to 0, but it still has pierce. RIP Jazz.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-41">
      <question>
So Major Shockwave's ability where he can play Decepticon cards or secret actions on the top of the player's deck as though they were in the player's hand, does this mean at any time since his other ability allows the player to look at the top of their deck at any time? So during attacks or while defending, and during my opponents turn can I play these cards as long as they're on the top of my deck? Or do these actions and upgrades count as the action and upgrade for the turn? And finally, can it only be done once a turn, or any number of times if I have three or so of those cards in a row on top of my deck?
</question>
      <answer>
Major Shockwave&#x2019;s ability doesn&#x2019;t change when you can play any card. If you play an action from the top of your deck this way, that is your one action for that turn. If another effect allows you to play additional actions, you can keep playing them from the top of your deck, if applicable.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-42">
      <question>
Can the Secret Action be activated on your turn with the requirement is fulfilled?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-43">
      <question>
I have run into a situation where my deck had no cards and no discard pile to shuffle in. We ruled it as when I attacked or defended, I had no cards to flip so I added 0 to my attack and defense. We were wondering if this would be a proper ruling. Second, for the card Inverted. It says that for each orange pip you flip becomes a blue pip and vice versa. For cards that rely on you flipping a certain color pip, do the pips flipped count as what they are or the inverted color?
</question>
      <answer>
When you have no deck left, you just don&#x2019;t flip any cards. Inverted&#x2019;s effect applies immediately. For example, if an ability triggers whenever you flip two orange icons, and you flip two blue icons under Inverted (meaning the cards literally have blue icons printed on them), that ability will trigger.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-44">
      <question>
Character X attacks with Anticipation Engine. They flip Supercharge. Is Bold 3 applied and will they flip 3 extra cards? Bold/Tough are locked in once the first battle flip begins?
</question>
      <answer>
Anticipation Engine&#x2019;s ability triggers before you flip battle cards, therefore Supercharge will increase your bold.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-45">
      <question>
When Bumbleebee - Legendary Warrior flips to alt mode to trigger its effect, does he still have to attack a tapped &#x2018;Brave&#x2019; character?
</question>
      <answer>
Bumblebee can now attack any character, tapped or untapped. So if there&#x2019;s a character with Brave, Bumblebee must attack it. If there are multiple characters with Brave, Bumblebee must attack one of them. Your choice.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-46">
      <question>
I play Full Loadout on Wave 1 Wheeljack in Alt Mode. I play Multi-Tool, Multi-Mission Gear, and Field Communicator onto him. How are the triggers handled? Do I resolve each Upgrade and Wheeljack trigger mid-Loadout, or do I wait until I play all three upgrades then resolve the six triggers?
</question>
      <answer>
Full Loadout will put all three upgrades onto Wheeljack. You then handle all of the triggers in an order of your choosing.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-47">
      <question>
With the Omnibots' "Start of Your First Turn" triggers, do I play the appropriate upgrades before or after I draw my card for the turn?
</question>
      <answer>
After.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-48">
      <question>
How does Brainstorm work, exactly? Do I play the two actions from my hand immediately, then resolve them, or do I resolve the first action before playing and resolving the second action? What if a character's trigger happens between actions, such as Wave 1 Thundercracker? Are triggers resolved before or after the action that triggers them?
</question>
      <answer>
You play one action from your hand, then you play the second, then resolve the triggers caused by those actions.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-49">
      <question>
I have a team of all Autobots, including Captain Wheeljack in bot mode. I play Brainstorm, and as the first action, play Confidence. Do I play my second action for Brainstorm now, or do I resolve Confidence first and play an action via Confidence? Either way, this will trigger Captain Wheeljack&#x2019;s "When you play your third action" ability. Do I draw the card for that immediately, or do I wait until all the actions played via Confidence and Brainstorm have resolved?
</question>
      <answer>
Finish Confidence first (including possibly playing another action), then play your second action for Brainstorm. After that&#x2019;s done, all abilities that triggered while Brainstorm was resolving happen in an order of your choosing.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="2-50">
      <question>
If Blurr attacks and deals damage thus triggering his effect, if the only untapped character(s) left have stealth, will Blurr not untap? Or will it still untap and just not attack again?
</question>
      <answer>
Blurr will untap and Blurr will attack one of the characters that has stealth.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Rules Roundup 2019-08-09" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033067552-Rules-Roundup-8-9-19" published_date="2019-08-09" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
    <entry id="3-1">
      <question>
What is my build total for stars if I play both Soundwave - Communications, Blaster - Communications, and one Mini-Cassette. Do both "Your Starting Star Limit" abilities trigger?
</question>
      <answer>
27 Stars. Both abilities would apply.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-2">
      <question>
How do Soundwave and Blaster decide who gets to start with the Mini-Cassette under them, for both start of game and Recover Cassette?
</question>
      <answer>
You choose where the Mini-Cassette goes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-3">
      <question>
But what kind of music competition do they compete in?
</question>
      <answer>
Dueling Banjos, clearly.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-4">
      <question>
Since I'm not privy to what happens between two fictional characters in a hypothetical situation, do I just choose who the Mini-Cassette goes under which deployer?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, you choose.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-5">
      <question>
Does "outside the game" refer to the sideboard? The other question is if I play Brainstorm with Wave 3 Skywarp on the field, how do I proceed if I have 2 Defensive Formations at hand? Do I play the 1st Defensive Formation, draw a card and then play the 2nd Defensive Formation to draw a 2nd card? Or do I play the 1st defensive formation, then the 2nd, and then draw the 2 cards?
</question>
      <answer>
It can refer to your sideboard, however your &#x201C;outside the game&#x201D; cards do not have to be in your sideboard to be considered detectable by the game.
In resolving the Brainstorm, you will play both Defensive Formations. Skywarp&#x2019;s ability will trigger for each of them, but you won&#x2019;t draw cards for the ability until you&#x2019;ve finished resolving the Brainstorm.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-6">
      <question>
I play a Bolster, and attack with my specialist. Turn ends. Opponent attacks my defender who is a specialist. I play bolster then I play Multi-Mission Gear, then for the action you play Peace Through Tyranny, KO&#x2019;ing the specialist defender, effectively ending the attack with no flips.
Do you get an extra turn, then a normal turn?
</question>
      <answer>
You take your extra turn, then your normal turn. You can&#x2019;t take any additional turns.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-7">
      <question>
Does Micro Capacitor work on Thrust's ability? Probable not but I want to make sure.
</question>
      <answer>
You are correct. It does not!
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-8">
      <question>
When defending I reveal the secret action Bolster. I then proceed to play Multi-Mission Gear to play Brainstorm, in turn playing Battlefield Report and Defensive Formation. As these 2 have the same trigger condition as Bolster, am I able to reveal them now that Bolster has finished resolving?
</question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, it is too late to reveal them.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-9">
      <question>
If Reclaim is the last card in your deck and Major Shockwave is in Bot mode, when he uses his continuous effect to play the top Secret Action/Decepticon card of your deck as if it were in your hand, will Reclaim resolve its effect first and put the selected upgrade on top of the deck, or will the deck need to be shuffled immediately since there zero cards left in the main deck?
</question>
      <answer>
Your deck will need to be shuffled immediately in this scenario. Reclaim will not be able to find an upgrade and will have no further effect. Major Shockwave will stand around looking confused.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-10">
      <question>
If a Battle Master or Weaponizer is in the KO Pile, and the match runs to time and damage on all characters is assessed, should they count their damage for that total, or are they simply an upgrade with no damage on them?
</question>
      <answer>
They are an upgrade with no damage on them.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-11">
      <question>
If I KO my opponent&#x2019;s Battlemaster and it has a Dismantling Claw on it, and it scraps my Dismantling Claw, I think my Dismantling Claw would therefore scrap the newly applied Battlemaster due to he is now a weapon on my opponents bot. Is that correct?
</question>
      <answer>
That is correct.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-12">
      <question>
Can you transform an already tapped character in the field? (For example .. I want to play Rapid Conversion on Barrage who is tapped). If yes, will this still trigger his ability? (He can give another character +2 Pierce when he is flipped to Bot mode.)
</question>
      <answer>
Yes and yes!
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-13">
      <question>
If I play a Battering Ram on to a truck and I&#x2019;m battling Elita-1 in bot mode, and I do enough damage to KO her, would her ability still work or would she be flipped into her alt mode and not get her abilities?
</question>
      <answer>
Elita-1 will be KO&#x2019;d first. When Battering Ram&#x2019;s ability resolves, Elita-1 will already be in the KO area and therefore cannot be effected by Battering Ram.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-14">
      <question>
Player plays Fully Loadout on Megatron - Living Weapon. Does Megatron have the ability to place three weapons in Bot Mode due to his ability?
</question>
      <answer>
No. Full Loadout specifically says &#x201C;A weapon, an armor, and a utility&#x201D;. Megatron &#x2013; Living Weapon only changes what can be put into his slots.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-15">
      <question>
Can "Interpret The Airwaves be placed in a deck without Blaster and be used (not played) only for the Pips?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes, it can.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-16">
      <question>
Private Sideswipe - Does his effect apply twice if you can somehow manage to get him to flip to car mode, back to bot mode to car mode again?
</question>
      <answer>
Yes. If you can pull it off, that would work.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-17">
      <question>
Would Cornered work on a Battle Master causing it to flip to its upgrade side? If yes, what would happen to the upgrade?
</question>
      <answer>
No, you can&#x2019;t flip a Battle Master while it&#x2019;s on the battlefield.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="3-18">
      <question>
I have run into a situation where my deck had no cards and no discard pile to shuffle in. We ruled it as when I attacked or defended, I had no cards to flip so I added 0 to my attack and defense. We were wondering if this would be a proper ruling.

Second, for the card Inverted. It says that each orange pip you flip becomes a blue pip and vice versa. For cards that rely on you flipping a certain color pip, do the pips flipped count as what they are, or the inverted color?
</question>
      <answer>
If your deck and scrap pile are empty, you don't flip any cards and the game proceeds.

For Inverted, there's no sequence when the icon changes from one color to another. They are changed from the moment Inverted is played and stay so as long as Inverted is on the character.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Rules Roundup 2019-08-23" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033073232-Rules-Roundup-8-23-19" published_date="2019-08-23" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
    <entry id="4-1">
      <question>
What happens if someone has Brave and Stealth at the same time, like if I played Hiding Spot on Blitzwing while he was in tank mode, do they cancel out, does the newer stays take effect?
        </question>
      <answer>
They cancel each other out. An attacker is not able to fulfill both conditions, therefore the attacking player can choose a defender as normal.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-2">
      <question>
I have a ruling question about Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend. If I my attack checks an action like Pep Talk, when do I activate the effect? Immediately (I draw 2 cards, then continue the check) or after resolution? (continue the checks, then draw two cards). On a similar note. If I decide to use an action with an orange or white pip, am I still able to keep the pip effect, or does that vanish with the card?
        </question>
      <answer>
First, you attack with OPBL, then you flip the Battle Cards (including any Bold). If you flip a white battle icon, you flip two more Battle Cards. Then, you check if you have flipped an Action. You can play one of the actions. You will still get plus attack from the orange icons flipped on that Action.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-3">
      <question>
I was wondering about Sergeant Chromia from Wave 3 and how the Alt mode flip ability works. Does the flip ability work in saying that you can play any blue armor upgrade, like possibly Superior Plating as an example, along with your original upgrade and action, or is it saying that the player is able to play an additional blue armor upgrade from hand along with their own upgrade and action on that turn?
        </question>
      <answer>
Sergeant Chromia&#x2019;s flip ability asks you to play a blue armor right then. If you don&#x2019;t, you&#x2019;ve forfeited the opportunity to do so. Your normal upgrade play and action play aren&#x2019;t affected by this. The flip ability does not allow playing Superior Plating without previously having played Tech Research.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-4">
      <question>
I have Sturdy Armor on Soundwave and my opponent's Optimus Prime, Battlefield Legend attacks him while in Bot Mode, where he is Ranged. Optimus flips Roll Out as one of his Battle Card flips and plays it via his ability, changing to Alt Mode, in which he is now Melee. Does Soundwave still get the extra +1 Defense from Sturdy Armor since Optimus was Ranged when he attacked? Or does he not get the bonus since Optimus is now Melee?
        </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, Sturdy Armor would not give the extra +1 Defense as Optimus is not Ranged. Sturdy Armor is constantly checking for the enemy&#x2019;s Ranged trait, all the way up until damage is dealt.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-5">
      <question>
If I have a tapped character get KO&#x2019;d that has already attacked, if I play I Still Function!, does he come from the KO pile untapped?
        </question>
      <answer>
Tapped characters get KO&#x2019;d into the KO Area and are no longer tapped or untapped once in the KO Area. I Still Function! Returns the KO&#x2019;d character to the Battlefield untapped.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-6">
      <question>
If I have a Laser Cutlass and a Crushing Treads on say, Slammer, and I attack an opponent, does Slammer get the pierce 3 from the Laser Cutlass plus the pierce 3 from the Crushing Treads since pierce adds together and both pierce abilities are triggered differently? So, attacking for 4 with Pierce 6.
        </question>
      <answer>
That&#x2019;s correct. In this scenario you would be attacking for 4 with Pierce 6. Pierce stacks on Pierce, but not on regular attack damage.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-7">
      <question>
Optimus Prime, Gleaming Commander attacks Private Lionizer, knocking him out. Lionizer changes to RS Firesteel Saber, onto another of my characters, but Optimus Prime triggers his bot mode ability, and uses it to transform Prowl, Strategic Mastermind in my opponent&#x2019;s KO area, which then transforms to Prowl&#x2019;s bot mode and triggers his bot mode ability to remove a weapon. My opponent scraps RS Firesteel Saber. This all happened as a result of my opponent&#x2019;s attack- is this the correct order of play?
        </question>
      <answer>
Not quite. There are two errors in the scenario you&#x2019;re describing. The first is that Optimus&#x2019; trigger will resolve before damage is dealt to Lionizer. The second, is that your Optimus can only choose characters in your KO Area, so you would not be able to flip any characters in your opponent&#x2019;s KO Area.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-8">
      <question>
Question about Unconventional Flying Object. Can this be played on a Spaceship that is already in bot mode in order to flip it to alt mode, essentially ignoring the first sentence as "already done" (somewhat similar to Hunker Down)?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, it cannot.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-9">
      <question>
Can Quartermaster be used on Sergeant Cog? If not, is there a way to revive Cog from the KO/discard area for use again?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, and not currently&#x2026;
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-10">
      <question>
The question I have today is in regard to attacking with Anticipation Engine. I am playing with a combiner team, and I have just converted my last character. I don't have the Enigma in my hand to play it, so I play a different action instead. I attack using a character with Anticipation Engine and flip the Enigma. Am I able to play it, transform, and continue the attack with the Combiner, or does my attack get cancelled and it becomes my opponent's turn? (This is because the Enigma has the Combiner enter play untapped)

Update to the question, as I see it was already answered in a previous Rules Round-up.

&#x201C;Anticipation Engine + Enigma = Transformed and attacking, but untappedYou said the character was untapped, but still attacking. Does this mean that my opponent can only attack with one character if they have multiple available?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, your opponent can attack with only one character&#x201D;
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-11">
      <question>
My questions are:
1. If all my opponent&#x2019;s characters have already been tapped, can I still attack with the newly formed Combiner?
If all of your opponent&#x2019;s characters have already been tapped and you finish an attack with your untapped Combiner, you will then attack a second time with the Combiner.

    When Bolster activates during my opponent&#x2019;s turn, and Multi-Mission Gear is played with a Combiner Enigma, where does the attack land? As the defending character is no longer there, does it hit the Combiner?
        </question>
      <answer>
    The character they were attacking is part of your newly formed Combiner, so they are now attacking your Combiner.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-12">
      <question>
Does Start Your Engines affect cars in the KO area?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, it does not. Cards only affect cards in the KO Area if it is specifically stated in the card text.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-13">
      <question>
Hi, I just wondered if you can choose somebody that can't take non-attack damage as the recipient of non-attack damage, like if an opponent played Frag Toss and I had Motormaster in alt mode, would the damage have to go on Motormaster or could I choose somebody else and nullify it?
        </question>
      <answer>
You can choose someone else to nullify it.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-14">
      <question>
I have a character with a weapon and Spare Parts. My opponent hits me with Disarm or Debilitating Crystal. Is the weapon returned to my hand or does Spare Parts get scrapped, or returned to my hand instead?
        </question>
      <answer>
Same scenario, but my weapon is a Battle Master/Weaponizer.
In both scenarios, Spare Parts does not protect your weapon. A Battle Master or Weaponizer in weapon mode would go to KO rather than to your hand.
        </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Rules Roundup 2019-09-06" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033650671-Rules-Roundup-9-6-19" published_date="2019-09-06" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
    <entry id="5-1">
      <question>
Can Quartermaster be used to move a Superior Cannon, Jetpack, or Plating from one character to another or do you still have to play a Tech Research first?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, it can.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-2">
      <question>
If I attack with a character that is upgraded with an anticipation engine and the first card flipped is an action that untaps my attacking character, such as Start Your Engines in a cars deck, does my character still count as attacking? Does it still flip battlecards for attack? Does my opponent need to wait for me to attack with the same, or another, character?

Another similar confluence of mechanics would be OPBL flipping a swap missions during attack and untapping. I know the effects and triggers are at slightly different points in the attack but the result is broadly the same; an attacker that hasn&#x2019;t tapped out that round.
Is this intended?
        </question>
      <answer>
Changing the tapped/untapped status of a character does not affect whether it is attacking or not. At the end of that attack, if your opponent has any untapped characters, your turn ends. Otherwise, continue attacking with any of your untapped characters.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-3">
      <question>
My question is in regard to Wave 1 Kickback and Demolisher. If the ability states to flip two extra battlecards for each other Insecticon you started the game with, or flip extra battle cards equal to your defense, and you don&#x2019;t flip a white on your initial two flips, does a white battle icon flipped during those extra flips cause you to flip two extra cards?
        </question>
      <answer>
It doesn&#x2019;t matter when the white icon is flipped. The first time it&#x2019;s flipped, it will use its ability.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-4">
      <question>
I have Cliffjumper in car mode with a metal detector.
Cliffjumper attacks and taps.
Metal detector flips over Turbo Boosters.
Does Cliffjumper attack untapped?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, he does.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-5">
      <question>
Since it sounds like (understandably) that a comprehensive rules document might take a while, perhaps you could answer a more specific timing question then.

Taken to a corner case, how would a player properly process an attack in the following scenario.

Your team:

Specialist Flamewar in bot mode equipped with an Anticipation Engine in her weapon slot, a Metal Detector in her Utility slot. She has Focus 2 from her bot mode ability.

Her teammate, Raider Aimless has a Decepticon Crown equipped in his Utility slot giving out Plan 1 when a Decepticon attacks.

Her other teammate General Optimus Prime is in Alt Mode giving Bold 1 and Tough 1 to his teammates.

What would be the proper sequence of triggers when Specialist Flamewar initiates an attack? Which goes first Plan, Focus, the Equipment Triggers? Which Equipment Triggers first? Can both trigger on the same combat if you have an equipment and an action (or vice versa) as your top 2 cards?
        </question>
      <answer>
When Specialist Flamewar attacks, the abilities of Anticipation Engine, Metal Detector, and Decepticon Crown will all trigger. As the attacking player, you will resolve all of those abilities in the order of your choosing, one at a time. Then you will use your Focus ability. Then, you will flip battle cards, including an extra from General Optimus&#x2019; Bold 1.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-6">
      <question>
Apologies if this has been asked before but have a question about type-specific upgrades like Power Sword and Body Armor - These cards specifically requiring Melee characters.
If a character changes type - what happens to the upgrade?
        </question>
      <answer>
Traits, like Melee, are only requirements for upgrades to be attached to a character. Once attached, they stay on when a character flips between alt and bot modes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-7">
      <question>
Does Motormaster's ability prevent damage from character abilities? Such as Decepticon Shockwave's discard damage or Superion's first time combining ability if the opponent decided to target someone other than Motormaster?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-8">
      <question>
If I have a Grenade Launcher on Blurr, and I attack a tapped character, which will occur first: the second attack on an untapped character, or scrapping the Grenade Launcher?
        </question>
      <answer>
Grenade Launcher only lasts for one battle, so it would be scrapped before Blurr launches his second attack.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-9">
      <question>
In a previous round up you mentioned that if Ion Blaster of Optimus Prime was played on Optimus, then he was combined into Optimus Maximus, the Combiner could keep that weapon, however not if he was already formed. I&#x2019;m assuming that also works with Laser Cutlass? Play onto an Aerialbot for example. Once combined, does it carry over?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-10">
      <question>
Regarding All-Out Attack.
Scenario:

Bumblebee-TL tapped in bot mode, Prowl-MS and Cliffjumper-RW untapped in car mode.
I play All-Out Attack. Cliffjumper attacks and uses Anticipation Engine to trigger a Start Your Engines. Bee flips to car mode, Prowl is irrelevant, Cliffjumper untaps. Using Bee's extra action via flip to alt mode, I play Ready for Action to untap Bee. Cliffjumper finishes his attack. All 3 cars are now untapped.

Am I free to attack again with Cliffjumper?
Am I free to attack with Bee?
Am I free to end my attacks when I choose because of AoA?
        </question>
      <answer>
All-Out Attack says &#x201C;Each of your untapped Transformers (Editor&#x2019;s Note: Characters) can attack this turn.&#x201D; At the time you play All-Out Attack, check which of your characters are untapped. Those characters are allowed to attack this turn, in sequence. They are not, however, required to attack. They can&#x2019;t attack a second time unless your opponent is tapped out. As usual, you still must attack with at least one character during your turn if you are able.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Rules Roundup 2019-09-20" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033718332-Rules-Roundup-9-20-19" published_date="2019-09-20" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
    <entry id="6-1">
      <question>
The opponent had an Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend with an Anticipation Engine and attacked my Ramhorn. I had a Force Field in hand and was ready to play my white armor, when he flipped a Security Checkpoint with Anticipation Engine. Do I still get to play the Force Field in this situation or does the Checkpoint get rid of the Force Field before I play it?
        </question>
      <answer>
Because attack triggers will resolve before defense triggers, in this scenario Security Checkpoint will get rid of your Force Field before you can play it.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-2">
      <question>
I have 2 untapped cars and a Wave 2 Bumblebee tapped in bot mode. I play Ready for Action untapping him. I then flip him, triggering his mode ability and I play All-Out Attack allowing all my character to attack this turn as they are now all untapped prior me playing All-Out Attack (AOA). I put Anticipation Engine on one of my characters. I then attack with Bee first (tapping him), my 2nd character (tapping him), and finally the last character with Anticipation Engine (AE) which then taps him. AE triggers and I get Start Your Engines (SYE). I untap that last character with AE. Seeing how AOA was played during a time where all my characters were untapped, does that last character get to attack again since it was untapped with SYE post AOA being played?
        </question>
      <answer>
If the opponent has no untapped characters, you will attack again with the last character. If the opponent has at least one untapped character, you cannot attack again with the last character. All Out Attack allows one attack with each of your untapped characters at the time you play it.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-3">
      <question>
I believe I know the answer to this one, but asking for clarity purposes - I attack with 5 ATK/Pierce 7 onto a character with Point Defense System. Does the final attack get reduced to ATK 5/Pierce 5 (which I believe is the correct answer) or ATK 5/Pierce 3?
        </question>
      <answer>
It would be reduced to 5 Attack, Pierce 5.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-4">
      <question>
I go first and during my first turn I manage to play Peace Through Tyranny (PTT. {I'm sparing the details on how this can be pulled off, but I can go into details if you need me to}), killing off one of my character to grant me an extra turn. Normally on turn 1, that player cannot play a card from their hand and on turn two, the other player gets to play either an Action or an Upgrade. But since I get an extra turn and I am not the other player, on the PTT granted turn (technically the game's and my 2nd turn), do I get to play an Action and Upgrade seeing I'm no longer on my 'first' turn?
        </question>
      <answer>
During turn 1, that player can&#x2019;t play any cards. During turn 2, the player can play 1 card. From turn 3 onwards, each player can play up to one Action and up to one Upgrade.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-5">
      <question>
If a Mini-Cassette attacks with an Anticipation Engine attached, reveals Recover Cassette, and Recover Cassette is played to put that Mini-Cassette under Soundwave or Blaster, does the attack end and no cards are flipped for attacking and defending? 
        </question>
      <answer>
The attack ends and no Battle Cards are flipped.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-6">
      <question>
Callous Leadership says "move up to 5 damage counters from..." and I was asked if you can put an excess amount of damage on somebody i.e putting 5 on an Acid Storm who only has 4 health left, or can you only move four damage counters on him?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, you can move 5 damage to a character even if they have fewer than 5 health remaining.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-7">
      <question>
Please clarify the interaction between Thrust and Chop Shop under the following scenario:
    Chop Shop flips to bot-mode
    Equip a Grenade Launcher onto Thrust
    Chop Shop attacks
    Thrust and Chop Shop's abilities trigger at the same time, so order of resolution is up to the turn-player
    1) Resolve Thrust's ability and tap him to add 7 atk (base + Grenade Launcher) to Chop Shop
    2) Resolve Chop Shop's ability moving the Grenade Launcher from Thrust to Chop Shop
    Chop Shop's final attack is [BASE] + [GRENADE_LAUNCHER] + [THRUST_BASE] + [GRENADE_LAUNCHER]; 4 + 4 + 3 + 4 = 15
    Battle flips omitted
Is this correct?
        </question>
      <answer>
You can choose to resolve Thrust and Chop Shop&#x2019;s abilities in this order. You could also choose to resolve them in the other order, but that would probably not turn out as well for you, so maybe don&#x2019;t.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-8">
      <question>
In a situation where someone is using Thrust and an Anticipation Engine attached to a different bot, could that person use Thrust's ability multiple times if they flip a Ready for Action using the Anticipation Engine?
        </question>
      <answer>
Thrust&#x2019;s ability only triggers once&#x2013;when one of your other characters attacks. To use Thrust&#x2019;s ability more than once, you need to untap Thrust and attack a second time with one of your other characters.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-9">
      <question>
If Dreadwing - Sky Destroyer has 2 Spinner Rims attached and flips a white trigger on attacking, does he flip 1 extra battle card for each Spinner Rims attached, or just 1 extra?
        </question>
      <answer>
Both copies of Spinner Rims will trigger and allow you to flip an extra Battle Card, for a total of two, in this scenario.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-10">
      <question>
So Ultra Magnus armor on Omega Supreme: does the armor reduce the damage that Omega takes from his soak 2 ability in bot mode?
        </question>
      <answer>
Ultra Magnus Armor would not reduce the damage Omega Supreme would take because the damage is still Attack damage.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Rules Roundup 2019-10-11" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360035148411-Rules-Roundup-10-11-19" published_date="2019-10-11" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
    <entry id="7-1">
      <question>
I play Brainstorm. Using my 2 actions, I play Ancient Wisdom first, then System Reboot. I draw Unleash Potential off of System Reboot, do I get to play it for free now?
        </question>
      <answer>
Both Brainstorm and Ancient Wisdom resolve &#x201C;top to bottom&#x201D;. When you play Brainstorm, then you play Ancient Wisdom, you must play Unleash Potential at that moment. In your case, you&#x2019;ve moved past Ancient Wisdom and are continuing with Brainstorm, playing System Reboot. It&#x2019;s now too late to play Unleash Potential with your previous Ancient Wisdom.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-2">
      <question>
There's now an upgrade that says "Opponents cannot have more than Bold 2" or something to that effect. Mechanically, 3 instances of Bold 2 have worked the same as Bold 6. It hasn't been explicitly said that Bold and Tough stack just like Pierce, so does it?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes. Bold, Tough, Pierce, and other key words with numerical values do stack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-3">
      <question>
In a turn where I play Brainstorm, allowing for 2 more actions. I play I Still Function!, bringing Buzzsaw (Spy) from the KO Area, then I play Recover Cassette, putting Buzzsaw underneath Soundwave. Will that cancel out I Still Function!?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, it will. Once Buzzsaw goes underneath Soundwave, all existing and/or pending game effects stop applying to him.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-4">
      <question>
How does Major Shockwave work with regard to the keyword Focus? Say for instance that Major Shockwave has Focus 1 and you look at the first card of your deck with Focus. Are you then allowed to look at the next card of your deck before deciding if you want to scrap or keep the Focused card?
        </question>
      <answer>
The card you&#x2019;re looking at while Focusing is still the top card of your deck. You must decide to scrap it or not. Only after deciding to scrap it are you allowed to look at the new top card of your deck.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-5">
      <question>
What happens if two characters both have Brave? Do I get to pick out of the two, which receives the damage?
        </question>
      <answer>
If two or more characters have Brave, the attacking player can choose between them.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-6">
      <question>
I have a Torox with Tooth and Claw and Mining Pick in his Armor Slot, as well as Divebomb with a Field Communicator. If I combine them into Predaking via the Predacon Enigma, am I required to keep Tooth and Claw in order to carry the Mining Pick to Predaking's armor slot, or can I bring the Field Communicator instead?
        </question>
      <answer>
Once an Upgrade is legally put into a slot, it stays there, even if the ability that allowed it to be upgraded in the first place no longer applies. In your example, you could keep Mining Pick in Predaking&#x2019;s Armor slot. Upgrades that are on characters that combine into Combiners are considered to stay in their slots, even though those slots now belong to the Combiner.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-8">
      <question>
Dreadwing is equipped with Forcefield, Emergency Defense Field, and Backup Bag takes 5 or more attack damage, what happens? I think that the Forcefield would try to scrap first (reducing the damage to 4) and the Back-Up Bag would save it... then the Emergency Defense Field would make Dreadwing take no damage and scrap. Is that right?
        </question>
      <answer>
That is correct!
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-9">
      <question>
Are Character cards with Voice Actor signatures on them (if you got your card signed, something I might want to do) legal for tournament play? If so, are there any specifics? (in another TCG, as long as the signature doesn't cover any of the text on the card; it's legal)
        </question>
      <answer>
Good question! For Character Cards, markings/signatures should not obscure critical card information like rules text or character stats. Otherwise, that should be fine. Ultimately, however, legality of an individual card is up to the Head Judge of the event in question.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-10">
      <question>
I have a question regarding Sergeant Cog. When he dies, I place him on Private Red Heat, and Trigger his ability. Let&#x2019;s say I draw 2 cards. I can then upgrade each of my characters, and let&#x2019;s say I play Field Communicator on one of my specialists from the Cog trigger, do I resolve Field Communicator&#x2019;s trigger before finishing the last Cog upgrade trigger, or do I finish the Cog trigger, and then resolve the Field Communicator trigger?
        </question>
      <answer>
Finish the Cog trigger completely, then resolve any resulting triggers like Field Communicator in an order of your choosing.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-11">
      <question>
If I then swap all of those upgrades with Red Heat, I can then choose the order again. From this I play a Multi-Mission Gear and play a Brainstorm, do I need to finish prior triggers before Brainstorm, or can I still choose the order?
        </question>
      <answer>
If you swap upgrades with Red Heat, you can have a lot of triggers, including another Cog trigger. You choose to resolve each of these triggers one at a time. If you choose Multi-Mission Gear&#x2019;s trigger to play Brainstorm, you now must finish Brainstorm&#x2019;s effect before continuing with your remaining triggers caused by Red Heat&#x2019;s swap.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="7-12">
      <question>
I&#x2019;m playing with a plane card, for example Captain Starscream, and it has on it the utility card Energy Pack. The total damage he has on him at the time is 19 and then I play the utility card Crash Landing on him, scrapping the Energy Pack and instantly KO&#x2019;ing him, does the Crash Landing take effect or not?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, Crash Landing only triggers on your opponent's turn, so it would not trigger here.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
