<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-05-02" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-5219/2124771710977976/" published_date="2019-05-02" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="502-1">
      <question>
My question is the following scenario:
Player A has one bot remaining with 1 health 
Player B has one bot remaining with 3 health
Player A attacks with his one remaining bot into Player B's bot that has Energized Field equipped.
Player A's total attack value after flipping all cards (attack and defense flips) is enough to kill Player B's bot BUT during the defense card flips Player B flips a single orange card thus triggering Energized Field’s ability.
What would be the order of operations?
      </question>
      <answer>
Energized Field’s ability would trigger before damage is dealt, KO’ing Player A’s last character and winning the game for Player B.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-2" tags="Volcanicus - Fiery Champion,Grimlock - Powerful Commander">
      <question>
I wondering, given that Volcanicus is a Dinobot, is he a valid target for wave 2 Grimlock’s ability that lets you put Dinobots from outside the game into the KO area?
      </question>
      <answer>
No. Volcanicus can’t exist outside of the game because he needs to be combined inside the game, so Grimlock cannot recruit him into the game.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-3" tags="Menasor - Menacing Colossus">
      <question>
I have Menasor on the field and two Team-Up Tactics in my hand. If I play them, do they do nothing, am I forced to pick one effect, or do both effects go off?
      </question>
      <answer>
Menasor is not a truck or a car, so Team-Up Tactics would have no effect on him.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-4" tags="Specialist Ratchet - Engineering - Rescue &amp; Repair">
      <question>
If you play Salvage for Parts while Specialist Ratchet is in bot mode, and you scrap, say, 2 opponent upgrades along with yours do you get to use the repair for the opponents scrapped upgrades as attack for Ratchet?
      </question>
      <answer>
For Salvage for Parts, you’re doing all of the repairing, so Ratchet’s ability will trigger that many times. In this scenario, that would give Ratchet +4 Attack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-5" tags="Major Shockwave - Applied Sciences - Scientist">
      <question>
If I have Major Shockwave in bot mode and have a Decepticon card as my top card, can I play that on my opponents turn? Or does the wording ‘from your hand’ translate to the action or upgrade you can do for your turn only?
      </question>
      <answer>
No, you cannot play it on your opponent’s turn. If you play the top card of your deck, you use your normal action or upgrade for the turn. Major Shockwave just gives you access to one more card while doing so.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-6">
      <question>
If Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend is at 13 damage counters and he attacks and flips into One Shall Stand One Shall Fall, and I assign 3 damage to him, causing him to KO, what happens to the ATK Damage? Or is there no attack and the turn ends? Does my opponent need to flip for defense? 
      </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, the attack ends and you do not flip for defense.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-7" tags="KO">
      <question>
When KO’d, a Battle Master comes back as a weapon. Then once it gets destroyed, it goes into the KO area. My question is, can you flip it back to bot mode in the KO area after it falls off?
      </question>
      <answer>
No. You may only flip characters in the KO area using your normal once-per-turn flip.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-8" tags="Metroplex - Autobot City,Slammer - Combat Drone">
      <question>
I'm playing a game of Stunticons vs. Metroplex.
Turn 1, Metroplex Flips and Attacks.
Turn 2, feeling clever, Stunticons puts a Battering Ram on Menasor and Attacks Metroplex, dealing 1 Damage. Metroplex Flips and Deploys Slammer. 
Does Turn 2 end now or does the Stunticon player get to keep attacking since the condition that allowed him to keep attacking had already been met?
      </question>
      <answer>
After each attack concludes, the game checks to see if the opponent has any untapped characters. In this scenario, Slammer is there, so the Stunticon player does not get to keep attacking.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-9" tags="Raider Visper - Infantry - Patrol Leader,Tap Ability">
      <question>
If I’m defending with Raider Visper, who is untapped, and my opponent plays EMP Wave, do I get the option of discarding 3 green pips to force them to discard 3 cards? If they’re matching, do I get to draw three? Also, EMP Wave would always make it the turn of the person who didn’t play it, correct? Or if I’m attacking and play EMP Wave do I get to swing with a character that I just tapped?
      </question>
      <answer>
No, a Tap ability is something you use on your turn, not whenever the character becomes tapped. If you play EMP Wave on your turn, all characters will be tapped. Your turn continues, and you can play an upgrade, flip a character, etc. At the end of your turn, all characters will untap, and your opponent’s turn will begin.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="502-10" tags="Major Shockwave - Applied Sciences - Scientist">
      <question>
If I play Incoming Transmission while I have Major Shockwave on the field, and I draw the two cards, am I able to look at the next card in the deck BEFORE I put a card on the top of my deck, or must I complete Incoming Transmission before looking?
      </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, you may look at the next card in the deck before you put a card on the top of your deck.
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
