<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-02-22" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-22219/2022354597886355/" published_date="2019-02-22" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
Does Jetfire’s ability bypass Tech Research and allow me to attach cards like Superior Jetpack and Superior Plating?
      </question>
      <answer>
Jetfire’s wording of “put” is different than “play”, which does circumvent the restrictions on cards like Superior Jetpack and Superior Plating.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
Is Plan mandatory? For example: on Secret Dealings it says draw a card, then Plan 1. Are you required to put a card on top of your deck or is it optional?
      </question>
      <answer>
It says “You may”, so it is optional.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
For Unleash Potential, can you add any card from outside the game even if you would exceed 25 stars? Or would you still need to be under the limit?
      </question>
      <answer>
You can add any card with a 1-star cost and you can go over the 25-star limit.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
If I play Ancient Wisdom and scrap two upgrades or two actions, do I just pick one to add to my hand and the other stays in the scrap pile? Or do I have to scrap an upgrade and an action to activate its effect.
      </question>
      <answer>
You can pick one and the other stays in the scrap pile.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
If I form a Combiner while one of the component pieces is equipped with three Attack Drones, am I allowed to transfer all three to the combined form, or just one?
      </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, you can transfer all three Attack Drones.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
If one of my planes is equipped with a Grenade Launcher and a Crash Landing before getting KO'd, would the Grenade Launcher add an additional 4 damage to Crash Landing's effect?
      </question>
      <answer>
It will include the attack modifier from the Grenade Launcher.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
Say I have Razorclaw equipped with Tooth and Claw, and because of that effect Razorclaw has a Grenade Launcher in its armor slot. If I combine into Predaking, can I transfer the Grenade Launcher from Razorclaw's armor slot to Predaking's armor slot?
      </question>
      <answer>
You would have to keep Tooth and Claw to keep the Grenade Launcher for Predaking’s armor slot.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
When does a white battle icon trigger during a battle? If I have Recon System equipped to a battling character and I flip a white and an orange, will Recon System trigger first or the white icon?
      </question>
      <answer>
Recon System says you scrap it without using its battle icons, and it will happen first.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
For Divebomb's bot mode ability, how would you suggest choosing a random card? Can it be any way as long as both players approve, it or is there an official way to select the random card?
      </question>
      <answer>
Any reasonable method players can agree upon is acceptable.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
Is this the correct order of operations for Silverbolt? He starts in alt mode and attacks. He flips all his cards, using his Bold 1. After he flips all his cards, he meets the prerequisites for his alt mode ability. He flips to bot mode, deals 1 damage to an enemy, then calculates his attack with his bot mode, then the target makes their flips and calculates defense, then damage is dealt and battle ends.
      </question>
      <answer>
That is correct!
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
At the start of the game, are players allowed to look through each other's decks?
      </question>
      <answer>
If both players agree to it, sure. However, it is not part of the official rules of the game.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
At the start of the game, does a player who has battle cards with a star cost have to tell their opponent this? If yes, do they have to tell them how many/which cards they are?
      </question>
      <answer>
No.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
So, with Leap of Faith: it says to scrap a card, which you may play, then scrap another card, and you may play that. For actions, it's a no brainer. But for upgrades, if you play it from your scrap, does it stay on the battlefield?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes. You’ll play the upgrade just as you would from your hand and it will remain attached to the character as normal.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
          Say Dirge (In bot mode) gets the effect of Steamroll, and then KOs a character, but does too much damage and ends up with 3 damage left over. Following Steamroll's effect, that 3 damage gets moved to a different character, but the damage spillover target has only 3 health left, and the second character is KO'd. The first KO obviously doesn't trigger Dirge's bot mode skill, but would that second KO cause Dirge's skill to kick in untap him?
      </question>
      <answer>
          When you move the damage via Steamroll, it ceases to be attack damage and therefore doesn’t trigger Dirge’s bot mode ability.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
Okay, so you've stated in the past that your opponent's characters count as "cards" when referring to Motormaster rulings. I was wondering, with regards to Spare Parts (which scraps itself instead of another Upgrade attached to your character) and Force Field, would a character attack count as a card causing Force Field to discard? In other words, if your opponent attacked an upgraded character with both a Spare Parts and a Force Field with enough damage to trigger the Force Field's effect, would you scrap the Force Field or the Spare Parts?
      </question>
      <answer>
You would scrap Force Field because its ability is what causes it to be scrapped, not your opponent’s attack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
Say I have 2 copies of Universal Network Access (Or any star card) in my deck, and I use Unleash Potential to bring a third copy into my hand. Fast forward a bit, and I manage to play Unleash Potential again. Could I use that to bring a fourth copy of that card into the game or does the rule of three still apply?
      </question>
      <answer>
The rule only applies when building your deck. In this scenario you could bring in another copy.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
If I’m running Stunticons and have two Cargo Trailers on Motormaster, and one on Offroad, will the combined Menasor be able to merge all three into his one Utility slot or will he just attach Motormaster’s two?
      </question>
      <answer>
Menasor can keep all three.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="222-1">
      <question>
If Prowl is KO'd, does his ability trigger from his own KO?
      </question>
      <answer>
No. That ability is tied to Prowl’s bot mode, in which he is not a car, so it wouldn’t apply.
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
