<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Wave 2 Battle Cards">
  <target name="Aerialbot Formation">
    <entry>
      <question>If the upgraded character is tapped, does it give itself a +1 attack bonus?</question>
      <answer>No. The upgraded character doesn&#x2019;t count, only your other tapped Aerialbots.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Ancient Wisdom">
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if I scrap two Actions or two Upgrades?</question>
      <answer>In that case, you can return one card to your hand. The other card remains scrapped.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if I play this card with 2 cards left in my deck?</question>
      <answer>Whenever a card tells you to scrap (or reveal) cards from the top of your deck and then do something else with those cards, those cards aren&#x2019;t included in the reshuffle. So you&#x2019;ll scrap the top two cards, shuffle all other cards in your scrap pile into your deck, then return one or both scrapped cards to your hand, depending on what they are.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if I play this card with 1 card left in my deck?</question>
      <answer>In that case, you&#x2019;ll scrap the one card and shuffle all other cards in your scrap pile into your deck. Then scrap the new top card of your deck, meaning you&#x2019;ve scrapped a total of two cards.  Then return one or both scrapped cards to your hand, depending on what they are.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>What happens to a scrapped card that I don&#x2019;t return to my hand?</question>
      <answer>It stays in the scrap pile.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>If I scrap Unleash Potential and return it to my hand, can I then play it?</question>
      <answer>Yes. You follow the instructions of Ancient Wisdom in the order written.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Attack Drone">
    <entry>
      <question>If I have a character upgraded with more than one Attack Drone and I play another Weapon, what happens?</question>
      <answer>All the Attack Drones in the character&#x2019;s weapon slot are scrapped.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Bumpers">
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if a card tries to move damage counters to the upgraded character?</question>
      <answer>That effect is ignored. The damage counters stay where they are. They aren&#x2019;t repaired. If the card trying to move the damage counters has other instructions, those are still followed if possible.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Combat Commands">
    <entry>
      <question>If I have a Sentinel in my KO area that&#x2019;s in alt mode, can I flip it to bot mode?</question>
      <answer>No. Combat Commands works only on Sentinels in your KO area in alt mode.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Confidence">
    <entry>
      <question>Does the Action I play have to be one of the cards I drew?</question>
      <answer>No. You can play any Action in your hand after you scrap 2 cards from it.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if I have no other cards in my hand when I play Confidence?</question>
      <answer>You&#x2019;ll draw 2 cards and them immediately scrap them. You won&#x2019;t be able to play an Action because your hand will be empty.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Cooling Vents">
    <entry>
      <question>Can I put this on an undamaged Ranged character or a character that isn&#x2019;t Ranged?</question>
      <answer>Yes. You&#x2019;ll ignore the repair ability though.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Cornered!">
    <entry>
      <question>When I play Cornered! and force my opponent to flip one of their character's do they get to use a "when you flip to this mode&#x201D; Ability on my turn?</question>
      <answer>Yes. If you play Cornered! on an opponent&#x2019;s character, they get to use a flip ability on that turn.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Defensive Driving">
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if two effects are trying to modify the damage a character takes?</question>
      <answer>In cases like that, the player whose character it is can choose which effect to apply. Then see if the other effect(s) still apply. Keep applying these effects until none apply. Each effect can apply to the same damage only once.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Electrified Spikes"><entry><question>If I flip four orange battle icons, does it deal 2 damage?</question><answer>No. The ability does a maximum of 1 damage, no matter how many orange battle icons you</answer></entry>
flip.
<entry><question>What happens if the 1 damage KO&#x2019;s the attacker?</question><answer>In that case, no damage is done to the defender.</answer></entry>
</target>
  <target name="Enemy Combat Analysis">
    <entry>
      <question>If a character is in a mode that has no stars printed on it, does it have 0 stars?</question>
      <answer>No. A character has the same number of stars no matter what mode it&#x2019;s in.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Energized Field">
    <entry>
      <question>If I flip two orange battle icons, does it deal 2 damage?</question>
      <answer>No. The ability does a maximum of 1 damage, no matter how many orange battle icons you flip.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Erratic Lightning">
    <entry>
      <question>Can I put this on an enemy character to lower its defense?</question>
      <answer>No. You can put Upgrades on your characters only.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>If I play this on a character with 0 defense, and then later something gives it +1 defense, what will its total defense be?</question>
      <answer>0. Erratic Lightning won&#x2019;t drop your character&#x2019;s defense below 0, but the -1 applies again once your character&#x2019;s defense is raised.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Field Communicator">
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if I put this on a Specialist when there&#x2019;s only 1 card left in my deck?</question>
      <answer>In that case, you&#x2019;ll scrap that card. Then you&#x2019;ll shuffle all the other cards in your scrap pile into your deck. Then you may play the card you scrapped. If you don&#x2019;t, it will stay in your scrap pile.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Focus Fire">
    <entry>
      <question>Do I count the Focus Fire I&#x2019;m playing?</question>
      <answer>Yes. The first one gives one of your characters bold 1.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>If I play a second Focus Fire, can I give the same character bold 1 twice?</question>
      <answer>Yes. You can give one character bold 1 twice (which is just like giving it bold 2), or you can give two separate characters bold 1.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Fog of War">
    <entry>
      <question>Who scraps cards from their hand first?</question>
      <answer>Actually, you each scrap cards at the same time. Each player should choose the cards they&#x2019;re going to scrap and set them aside without revealing them. Once both players are ready, they turn them face up and put them in their scrap pile.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Inferno Breath">
    <entry>
      <question>Can I play this if I have no untapped characters with 5 stars or more?</question>
      <answer>No. If you can&#x2019;t follow the instructions on the left side of the arrow on an Action, you can&#x2019;t play the Action.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Intelligence Mission">
    <entry>
      <question>Can I play this if I have no untapped Specialists with 5 stars or more?</question>
      <answer>No. If you can&#x2019;t follow the instructions on the left side of the arrow on an Action, you can&#x2019;t play the Action.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Leap of Faith">
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if I play Leap of Faith with only 1 card left in my deck?</question>
      <answer>First, you&#x2019;ll scrap that card. Then you&#x2019;ll shuffle all the other cards in your scrap pile into your deck. Then you may play the card you scrapped. If you don&#x2019;t, it will stay in your scrap pile. Then scrap the new top card of your deck and you may play it.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Mounted Missiles">
    <entry>
      <question>Can I put Mounted Missiles into a Weapon slot?</question>
      <answer>Yes. It can go into an Armor or Utility slot, but it doesn&#x2019;t have to.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>If I play Mounted Missiles on a character, do I have to choose which slot it&#x2019;s going in?</question>
      <answer>Yes. If you want it in the Armor slot, put it to the right of the character, where an Armor would normally go. If you want it in the Utility slot, put it below the character, where a Utility would normally go. Once Mounted Missiles is in a slot, it can&#x2019;t move to another slot. This means that if you put it into a character&#x2019;s Armor slot, you&#x2019;d have to scrap Mounted Missiles if later you wanted to play an Armor on it.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Press the Advantage">
    <entry>
      <question>Can I play this if I don&#x2019;t have any Autobots or my opponent doesn&#x2019;t have any Decepticons just to get one of the effects?</question>
      <answer>Yes.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>Let&#x2019;s say I play this and choose my opponent&#x2019;s Decepticon with 1 defense. Later in the turn, it gets +2 defense. What will its total defense be?</question>
      <answer>1. Press the Advantage won&#x2019;t drop the Decepticon&#x2019;s defense below 0, but the -2 applies again once the Decepticon&#x2019;s defense is raised.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Recon System">
    <entry>
      <question>Let&#x2019;s say I flip 3 battle cards (the normal 2 + 1 for Recon System) and there&#x2019;s a white battle icon there. Do I scrap one for Recon System&#x2019;s effect immediately or do I flip the 2 extra cards?</question>
      <answer>Flip the extra cards first, then choose one of the cards you flipped and scrap it.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>If I put Recon System on Optimus Prime, Battlefield Legend (bot mode), can I scrap an Action that I flipped and then play it?</question>
      <answer>No. By the time you use Prime&#x2019;s ability to play one of the Action cards, it will be in the scrap pile and not among the cards you flipped.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Scrounge">
    <entry>
      <question>If I play Scrounge with only 1 card left in my deck and it&#x2019;s an Upgrade, can I play it?</question>
      <answer>Yes. You&#x2019;ll shuffle all the other cards in your scrap pile and then you may play the Upgrade.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Spare Parts">
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if an opponent&#x2019;s card tries to scrap a Weapon and an Armor from the upgraded character at the same time? Can Spare Parts save both of them?</question>
      <answer>No, Spare Parts can save only one other Upgrade. You choose whether it saves the Weapon or the Armor. Spare Parts and the other Upgrade will be scrapped.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Steamroll">
    <entry>
      <question>Can you give me an example of how this card works?</question>
      <answer>Sure. Let&#x2019;s say your opponent has a character with 12 health and 9 damage counters on it.  You attack with the chosen character and would do 6 damage to it. That&#x2019;s 3 more than you need to KO the defender, so your opponent chooses one of their other characters and puts 3 damage counters on it.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>What if your opponent puts those 3 damage counters on a character with 10 health and 9 damage counters already on it? Do the extra damage counters on go to a third character?</question>
      <answer>No. The &#x201C;Steamroll damage&#x201D; only carries over to one other character. That 10-health character would end up in the KO area with 10 damage counters on it. The extra 2 damage counters are lost.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>Does the damage counters my opponent puts on another character count as attack damage?</question>
      <answer>Yes. The damage counters represent attack damage done by the chosen character.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Swindled">
    <entry>
      <question>Does the Upgrade I play have to be one of the cards I drew?</question>
      <answer>No. You can play any Upgrade in your hand after you scrap 2 cards from it.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>What happens if I have no other cards in my hand when I play Confidence?</question>
      <answer>You&#x2019;ll draw 2 cards and them immediately scrap them. You won&#x2019;t be able to play an Upgrade because your hand will be empty.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Tackle">
    <entry>
      <question>Can I play this if I have no untapped Melee characters?</question>
      <answer>No. If you can&#x2019;t follow the instructions on the left side of the arrow on an Action, you can&#x2019;t play the Action.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Tech Research">
    <entry>
      <question>Tech Research&#x2026; doesn&#x2019;t do anything?</question>
      <answer>Not by itself, but you&#x2019;ll need to play it to play some Upgrades in the set.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Tooth and Claw">
    <entry>
      <question>If I want to play a Weapon on the upgraded character, do I choose which slot it goes in?</question>
      <answer>Yes. If you want the Weapon in its Armor slot, put it to the right of Megatron, where an Armor would normally go. Once the Weapon is in a slot, it can&#x2019;t move to another slot. This means that if you put a Weapon into its Armor slot, you&#x2019;d have to scrap that Weapon if later you wanted to play an Armor on it.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>If I have a Weapon in the upgraded character&#x2019;s Armor slot and Tooth and Claw is removed from the character, what happens to the Weapon?</question>
      <answer>It stays where it is. Once an Upgrade is legally put into a slot, removing what made it legal to put it there doesn&#x2019;t matter.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Unleash Potential">
    <entry>
      <question>Does this mean I get a card from my collection? Do I have to own the card?</question>
      <answer>Yes, you get a card that&#x2019;s not in the current game and add it to your hand. For the rest of the game, you&#x2019;ll have one more battle card.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <question>Can I get a card if I&#x2019;m already playing with 3 of that card in my deck?</question>
      <answer>Yes. The 3-card and 25-star limits apply only to your starting deck and team. You can bring in a fourth card, even if it would put you over the 25-star limit.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Vandalize">
    <entry>
      <question>If I choose Weapons and my opponent has characters with Weapons in either Utility or Armor slots, are those Weapons scrapped?</question>
      <answer>Yes. It only matters what kind of Upgrade it is, not what slot it&#x2019;s in.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
