<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-09-20" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033718332-Rules-Roundup-9-20-19" published_date="2019-09-20" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="6-1">
      <question>
The opponent had an Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend with an Anticipation Engine and attacked my Ramhorn. I had a Force Field in hand and was ready to play my white armor, when he flipped a Security Checkpoint with Anticipation Engine. Do I still get to play the Force Field in this situation or does the Checkpoint get rid of the Force Field before I play it?
        </question>
      <answer>
Because attack triggers will resolve before defense triggers, in this scenario Security Checkpoint will get rid of your Force Field before you can play it.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-2">
      <question>
I have 2 untapped cars and a Wave 2 Bumblebee tapped in bot mode. I play Ready for Action untapping him. I then flip him, triggering his mode ability and I play All-Out Attack allowing all my character to attack this turn as they are now all untapped prior me playing All-Out Attack (AOA). I put Anticipation Engine on one of my characters. I then attack with Bee first (tapping him), my 2nd character (tapping him), and finally the last character with Anticipation Engine (AE) which then taps him. AE triggers and I get Start Your Engines (SYE). I untap that last character with AE. Seeing how AOA was played during a time where all my characters were untapped, does that last character get to attack again since it was untapped with SYE post AOA being played?
        </question>
      <answer>
If the opponent has no untapped characters, you will attack again with the last character. If the opponent has at least one untapped character, you cannot attack again with the last character. All Out Attack allows one attack with each of your untapped characters at the time you play it.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-3">
      <question>
I believe I know the answer to this one, but asking for clarity purposes - I attack with 5 ATK/Pierce 7 onto a character with Point-Defense System. Does the final attack get reduced to ATK 5/Pierce 5 (which I believe is the correct answer) or ATK 5/Pierce 3?
        </question>
      <answer>
It would be reduced to 5 Attack, Pierce 5.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-4">
      <question>
I go first and during my first turn I manage to play Peace Through Tyranny (PTT. {I'm sparing the details on how this can be pulled off, but I can go into details if you need me to}), killing off one of my character to grant me an extra turn. Normally on turn 1, that player cannot play a card from their hand and on turn two, the other player gets to play either an Action or an Upgrade. But since I get an extra turn and I am not the other player, on the PTT granted turn (technically the game's and my 2nd turn), do I get to play an Action and Upgrade seeing I'm no longer on my 'first' turn?
        </question>
      <answer>
During turn 1, that player can&#x2019;t play any cards. During turn 2, the player can play 1 card. From turn 3 onwards, each player can play up to one Action and up to one Upgrade.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-5">
      <question>
If a Mini-Cassette attacks with an Anticipation Engine attached, reveals Recover Cassette, and Recover Cassette is played to put that Mini-Cassette under Soundwave or Blaster, does the attack end and no cards are flipped for attacking and defending?
        </question>
      <answer>
The attack ends and no Battle Cards are flipped.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-6">
      <question>
Callous Leadership says "move up to 5 damage counters from..." and I was asked if you can put an excess amount of damage on somebody i.e putting 5 on an Acid Storm who only has 4 health left, or can you only move four damage counters on him?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, you can move 5 damage to a character even if they have fewer than 5 health remaining.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-7" tags="Chop Shop - Sneaky Insecticon,Thrust - Supersonic Interceptor">
      <question>
Please clarify the interaction between Thrust and Chop Shop under the following scenario:
    Chop Shop flips to bot-mode
    Equip a Grenade Launcher onto Thrust
    Chop Shop attacks
    Thrust and Chop Shop's abilities trigger at the same time, so order of resolution is up to the turn-player
    1) Resolve Thrust's ability and tap him to add 7 atk (base + Grenade Launcher) to Chop Shop
    2) Resolve Chop Shop's ability moving the Grenade Launcher from Thrust to Chop Shop
    Chop Shop's final attack is [BASE] + [GRENADE_LAUNCHER] + [THRUST_BASE] + [GRENADE_LAUNCHER]; 4 + 4 + 3 + 4 = 15
    Battle flips omitted
Is this correct?
        </question>
      <answer>
You can choose to resolve Thrust and Chop Shop&#x2019;s abilities in this order. You could also choose to resolve them in the other order, but that would probably not turn out as well for you, so maybe don&#x2019;t.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-8" tags="Thrust - Supersonic Interceptor">
      <question>
In a situation where someone is using Thrust and an Anticipation Engine attached to a different bot, could that person use Thrust's ability multiple times if they flip a Ready for Action using the Anticipation Engine?
        </question>
      <answer>
Thrust&#x2019;s ability only triggers once&#x2013;when one of your other characters attacks. To use Thrust&#x2019;s ability more than once, you need to untap Thrust and attack a second time with one of your other characters.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-9">
      <question>
If Dreadwing - Sky Destroyer has 2 Spinner Rims attached and flips a white trigger on attacking, does he flip 1 extra battle card for each Spinner Rims attached, or just 1 extra?
        </question>
      <answer>
Both copies of Spinner Rims will trigger and allow you to flip an extra Battle Card, for a total of two, in this scenario.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="6-10" tags="Omega Supreme - Autobot Defense Base">
      <question>
So Ultra Magnus Armor on Omega Supreme: does the armor reduce the damage that Omega takes from his soak 2 ability in bot mode?
        </question>
      <answer>
Ultra Magnus Armor would not reduce the damage Omega Supreme would take because the damage is still Attack damage.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
