<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-04-01" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-4119/2076354045819743/" published_date="2019-04-01" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder" tags="Combiner">
    <entry id="401-1">
      <question>
Let's say you have a team of combiners. And your opponent’s characters are all tapped out. You have one character untapped and all of your characters are in bot mode. I know you can’t use Inferno Breath in this instance because you wouldn’t be able to attack to end the turn. However, if you play Brainstorm and then play Inferno Breath, tapping your last character and then using the Brainstorm’s second effect to play and enigma and combine, is that a legal play?
      </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, you actually could play Inferno Breath because you can tap your last character. When it comes time to attack, if you have no untapped characters, your turn would end. If your opponent also has no untapped character, you would untap all characters as usual and your opponent’s turn would begin. If you play the enigma and combine your characters into a Combiner, the Combiner begins untapped, so it would be the character that attacks.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-2">
      <question>
If Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend attacks and flips an Espionage and uses it for his effect, can you also add it back to your hand, with the green icon mechanic? Or does the ‘played’ card become in play for the turn, thus, not being able to add it?
      </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, you would be able to add Espionage back to your hand.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-3" tags="Dreadwing - Sky Destroyer">
      <question>
Quick question: If Dreadwing has two Crash Landings equipped, does it deal double damage when KO'd? And if it does, can I do 7 damage to two separate targets?
      </question>
      <answer>
Quick answer: Yes, and yes.
Not so quick answer: Each Crash Landing is triggered separately.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-4" tags="Motormaster - Stunticon Leader">
      <question>
My group has found conflicting answers in regard to Steamroll’s damage carryover being considered "combat damage" or not. FAQ on the app states that it is Attack Damage. Yet, Roundup 2/28/19 states that Motormaster would protect against Steamroll (making it non-attack damage) and Roundup 2/22/19 specifically states that Steamroll is NOT attack damage. 
      </question>
      <answer>
It’s possible you might be looking at an older iteration of the FAQ. There were conflicting answers earlier in the set’s life, but Steamroll’s damage carryover is not considered attack damage.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-5">
      <question>
Would playing multiple instances of Steamroll in the same turn allow for damage, if it were high enough to KO the second character as well as the initial character that was knocked out, to carry over to a second or third target? For example: Brainstorm into two Steamrolls or play Steamroll and then flip Bumblebee - Trusted Lieutenant into alt-mode and play a second or even a third Steamroll (if Brainstorm was played first). 
      </question>
      <answer>
Playing more than one instance of Steamroll on the same character has no additional effect. The extra damage will carry over only once.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-6">
      <question>
If I play Brainstorm, am I allowed to play the same action twice if I have 2 copies in my hand?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-7" tags="Thrust - Supersonic Interceptor">
      <question>
Let's say a Grenade Launcher is put on Thrust, then a DIFFERENT character is tapped to attack, the player decides to tap Thrust also in order to activate his ability. 
1. Does the extra attacks that Thrust gives to the attacking character include the Grenade Launcher's +4? 
2. and Does the Grenade Launcher get removed after the attack, even though Thrust wasn't technically attacking?
      </question>
      <answer>
1. Yes.
2. No. As you noted, the character with Grenade Launcher did not attack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-8" tags="Superior Cannon,Superior Jetpack,Superior Plating">
      <question>
Can Leap of Faith bypass the condition on all the Superior cards (Cannon, Jet pack, Plating) and allow you to attach them to a bot?
      </question>
      <answer>
No.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-9" tags="Air Raid - Fearless Flyer,Sunstorm - Fusion Flyer">
      <question>
My opponent's Air Raid (Bot Mode) attacks my Sunstorm (with Crash Landing), doing enough Damage to KO Sunstorm. Air Raid's player is able to Scrap the Crash Landing before I can use it to KO an Aerialbot, correct?
      </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, Air Raid’s ability can’t do anything because Sunstorm has been KO’d and as a result, his upgrades have been scrapped. Crash Landing’s effect will work.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-10" tags="Play">
      <question>
When playing Best 2 out of 3, how do you decide who goes first after the first match?
      </question>
      <answer>
There aren’t official rules for this, but we recommended letting the loser of the first game choosing who goes first in the next game.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="401-11" tags="Battle Icon">
      <question> 
The wording on what exactly goes on with green pip cards added to the hand from the flip zone has me minorly confused. 
1. When the swap occurs, is the card from hand exchanged scrapped then or at the end of the turn?
2. Does this trigger the bot mode ability of Decepticon Shockwave - Cyberton Commander?
      </question>
      <answer>
1. At the end of the battle, you can swap one card in your hand for a green battle icon card you’ve flipped.
2. It does not trigger Shockwave’s ability because you’re not scrapping a card from your hand. The flipped cards are being scrapped.
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
