<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-04-05" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-4519/2082325761889238/" published_date="2019-04-05" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="405-1" tags="Dreadwing - Sky Destroyer">
      <question>
How do double Forcefields work on Dreadwing? Will both be scrapped in a single attack thus making 1 pointless? Or will 1 trigger and resolve then the 2nd is left on?
      </question>
      <answer>
Both Forcefields will try to apply. You’ll need to choose one, which would reduce the damage, making the other Forcefield no longer apply to the scenario.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="405-2" tags="Play">
      <question>
If you run out of cards in a deck, do you shuffle immediately or wait until you have to draw/flip? 
      </question>
      <answer>
Reshuffle immediately.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="405-3" tags="Dreadwind - Air Defense,Dreadwing - Sky Destroyer,Blackwing Aerial Attacker">
      <question>
Re: Rules Roundup: 2/18 - as related to Dreadwing and 'So what happens when your opponent is tapped out and you attack with Blackwing/Dreadwind and combine at the end of your turn?' The answer to this question is as I understood it, however, what is the sequence of play in this situation?
      </question>
      <answer>
You would attack, check if all characters are tapped. If they are tapped, untap them, then end the turn. At that point, you may Combine. 
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="405-4" tags="Deck">
      <question>
I have a question about the game, and apologize if you answered it somewhere in the rules, but I could not find it. It is listed that a minimum of 40 battle cards be used. And one place mentions 40+ cards. But what is the maximum number of battle cards one can have in their deck?
      </question>
      <answer>
There is currently no maximum number of cards allowed in your Battle Deck.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="405-5">
      <question>
I have Wheeljack - Weapons Inventor in alt mode on the field. I play Leap of Faith and flip Field Communicator as my first card. I play Field Communicator and equip it to Wheeljack. With this scenario, does Wheeljack’s ability to draw then scrap a card occur before I do my second flip for Leap of Faith or does it have to wait until Leap of Faith has fully resolved?
      </question>
      <answer>
EDIT: You must resolve Leap of Faith and the second card you flip from Leap of Faith, then Field Communicator’s ability and Wheeljack’s ability can be resolved in an order of your choosing.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="405-6">
      <question>
Playing Turbo. I have a Drill Arms in play. I draw the last card in my deck. I have no scrap pile. I play another Drill Arms on the same bot and there are no armors in play, sending the old Drill Arms to the scrap pile. What happens next? Do I draw the old Drill Arms?
      </question>
      <answer>
In order to play the second Drill Arms, you first scrap the one that’s already in play. This immediately becomes the only card in your deck, so when you use the ability of the new Drill Arms, that’s the card you’ll draw.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="405-7" tags="Play">
      <question>
Scenario: You've just reshuffled your scrap pile, you have a very large hand, and you go into battle with a lot of bold. You run out of cards in your deck to flip, and there are no cards in your scrap pile. What happens?
      </question>
      <answer>
You stop flipping and immediately regret holding onto so many cards.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="405-8" tags="KO">
      <question>
    1. "When this is in your KO area and you flip to this mode => [do something]"
This suggests to me that A) you can flip characters in the KO area, and B) character abilities are active while in the KO area. Is this correct?
    2. If the answer to either the above is "yes", how does a card like Ransack work while in KO?
"When you flip to this mode => move 2 damage counters from another character to this one."
      </question>
      <answer>
1. Yes, when you flip a character in your turn, you can flip a character on the battlefield or in your KO area.
2. Abilities only function in the KO area if they specifically say so. Most abilities, like Ransack’s, do not function in the KO area.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="405-9">
      <question>
Drill Arms reads that you draw a card if you cannot scrap an opponent’s armor. What happens if your opponent uses spare parts and scraps that instead of an armor? Draw or no draw?
      </question>
      <answer>
No draw.
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
