<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-05-17" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-51719/2146988135423000/" published_date="2019-05-17" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="517-1" tags="Major Ultra Magnus - Infantry - City Commander,Private Firedrive - Ground Command - Artillery">
      <question>
Let's say I have Major Ultra Magnus in bot mode and Private Firedrive on the field, with Firedrive having 1 health remaining. If I attack with Ultra Magnus and trigger his bot mode ability, which causes Firedrive to die and I put the Duo-Charge Electrostatic Photon Cannon onto Ultra Magnus, what happens? Does Ultra Magnus get the +3 attack for this battle? Am I able to scrap cards from my hand to increase said attack?
      </question>
      <answer>
Major Ultra Magnus will get the +3 attack, but since the long-name weapon was attached after he began his attack, the ability will not trigger and you will not be able to scrap any cards to add to your attack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-2" tags="Private Firedrive - Ground Command - Artillery">
      <question>
Similarly, let's say I have Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend on the field in Bot mode and during my attack I flip a Quartermaster to bring back the Duo-Charge Electrostatic Photon Cannon and put it onto Optimus Prime. For that battle, does Optimus Prime get +3 attack? Am I also able to scrap cards from my hand to increase the attack?
      </question>
      <answer>
Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend will get the +3 attack, but since the weapon with the very long name was attached after he began his attack, the ability will not trigger and you will not be able to scrap any cards to add to your attack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-3" tags="Major Shockwave - Applied Sciences - Scientist">
      <question>
If I use Major Shockwave's bot mode skill to play a Secret Action, does that count as my action for the turn?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes, it does.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-4" tags="Omega Supreme - Autobot Defense Base,Insecticon Skrapnel - Insecticon Leader">
      <question>
If I had a team with Omega Supreme and Decepticon Skrapnel and someone attacked my Skrapnel for 15 damage but because of his ability (can only take 3 damage) Does two of those 3 damage go over to Omega Supreme? Therefore Skrapnel will only take 1 damage?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes, you can choose to allocate the attack damage that way in this scenario.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-5" tags="Decepticon Shockwave - Cybertron Commander,Captain Ironhide - Infantry - Bodyguard">
      <question>
If I have Captain Ironhide in alt mode and my opponent has Decepticon Shockwave in bot mode and causes me to scrap a card. If I direct that damage to Captain Ironhide does his alt mode skill deny the damage? 
      </question>
      <answer>
Are opponents’ cards considered battle cards and character cards as per Captain Ironhide’s skill wording?
The answer to both questions is yes!
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-6" tags="Major Ultra Magnus - Infantry - City Commander,Nemesis Prime - Dark Clone">
      <question>
If I have Major Ultra Magnus with 16 Damage on him and my opponent has Nemesis Prime with 15 Damage on him and I Attack Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend, causing my bot mode skill to trigger, does this cause Major Ultra Magnus to be KO’d and Nemesis Prime to be KO’d therefore no combat with Optimus?
      </question>
      <answer>
That is correct.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-7" tags="Captain Elita-1 - Special Ops - Ranger">
      <question>
How does the new Captain Elita-1 interact with I Still Function!? If my opponent KO’s her during their turn, and I scrap I Still Function as one of the two cards from her trigger, is Elita-1 a valid target for the card?
      </question>
      <answer>
Elita-1 would be a valid target for I Still Function!, but she would still be KO’d at the end of the turn. She would trigger again.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-8" tags="Captain Elita-1 - Special Ops - Ranger">
      <question>
What if I use I Still Function during my turn to bring back Elita-1 and then, at end of turn, when she is KO’d again, she reveals another I Still Function? If I am able to bring back a character with it, when is that character KO’d by I Still Function's effect?
      </question>
      <answer>
Almost immediately. At the end of that turn.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-9" tags="Motormaster - Stunticon Leader">
      <question>
With Motormaster's bot mode ability, when do you choose who going to defend? Is it before your opponent flips or after they flip and before you flip? The key phrase that I'm confused about is "If this would defend". When is the "defend" step?
      </question>
      <answer>
Motormaster’s bot mode ability is triggered in response to an attack, so the attacker will resolve all of their triggers from attacking, then Motormaster’s ability will allow you to choose a new defender, then the defense triggers will begin.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-10" tags="Sergeant Cog - Artillery - Mechanic">
      <question>
What is the order of operations with Sergeant Cog’s upgrade form?
      </question>
      <answer>
Attach Cog, draw your cards, attach all of the upgrades, resolve abilities that trigger from attaching upgrades in an order of your choosing.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="517-11">
      <question>
If I play Ancient Wisdom and follow it with Unleash Potential 4 times in one game, am I allowed to add 4 copies of the same card; i.e. Mounted Missiles, to my hand, even though under normal deck constraints a playset is 3?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes, you can. Deck constraints only apply to your starting deck.

          <tftcg-note>This changed in later competitive rules to state they could only pull from the sideboard, and that the only three copies applies to deck and sideboard. </tftcg-note>
      </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
