<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-09-06" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033650671-Rules-Roundup-9-6-19" published_date="2019-09-06" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="5-1">
      <question>
Can Quartermaster be used to move a Superior Cannon, Superior Jetpack, or Superior Plating from one character to another or do you still have to play a Tech Research first?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, it can.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-2">
      <question>
If I attack with a character that is upgraded with an anticipation engine and the first card flipped is an action that untaps my attacking character, such as Start Your Engines in a cars deck, does my character still count as attacking? Does it still flip battlecards for attack? Does my opponent need to wait for me to attack with the same, or another, character?

Another similar confluence of mechanics would be OPBL flipping a swap missions during attack and untapping. I know the effects and triggers are at slightly different points in the attack but the result is broadly the same; an attacker that hasn&#x2019;t tapped out that round.
Is this intended?
        </question>
      <answer>
Changing the tapped/untapped status of a character does not affect whether it is attacking or not. At the end of that attack, if your opponent has any untapped characters, your turn ends. Otherwise, continue attacking with any of your untapped characters.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-3" tags="Kickback - Cunning Insecticon,Demolisher - Devoted Decepticon">
      <question>
My question is in regard to Wave 1 Kickback and Demolisher. If the ability states to flip two extra battlecards for each other Insecticon you started the game with, or flip extra battle cards equal to your defense, and you don&#x2019;t flip a white on your initial two flips, does a white battle icon flipped during those extra flips cause you to flip two extra cards?
        </question>
      <answer>
It doesn&#x2019;t matter when the white icon is flipped. The first time it&#x2019;s flipped, it will use its ability.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-4">
      <question>
I have Cliffjumper in Car mode with a Metal Detector.
Cliffjumper attacks and taps.
Metal Detector flips over Turbo Boosters.
Does Cliffjumper attack untapped?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, he does.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-5" tags="Specialist Flamewar - Special Ops - Hunter">
      <question>
Since it sounds like (understandably) that a comprehensive rules document might take a while, perhaps you could answer a more specific timing question then.

Taken to a corner case, how would a player properly process an attack in the following scenario.

Your team:

Specialist Flamewar in bot mode equipped with an Anticipation Engine in her weapon slot, a Metal Detector in her Utility slot. She has Focus 2 from her bot mode ability.

Her teammate, Raider Aimless has a Decepticon Crown equipped in his Utility slot giving out Plan 1 when a Decepticon attacks.

Her other teammate General Optimus Prime is in Alt Mode giving Bold 1 and Tough 1 to his teammates.

What would be the proper sequence of triggers when Specialist Flamewar initiates an attack? Which goes first Plan, Focus, the Equipment Triggers? Which Equipment Triggers first? Can both trigger on the same combat if you have an equipment and an action (or vice versa) as your top 2 cards?
        </question>
      <answer>
When Specialist Flamewar attacks, the abilities of Anticipation Engine, Metal Detector, and Decepticon Crown will all trigger. As the attacking player, you will resolve all of those abilities in the order of your choosing, one at a time. Then you will use your Focus ability. Then, you will flip battle cards, including an extra from General Optimus&#x2019; Bold 1.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-6">
      <question>
Apologies if this has been asked before but have a question about type-specific upgrades like Power Sword and Body Armor - These cards specifically requiring Melee characters.
If a character changes type - what happens to the upgrade?
        </question>
      <answer>
Traits, like Melee, are only requirements for upgrades to be attached to a character. Once attached, they stay on when a character flips between alt and bot modes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-7" tags="Motormaster - Stunticon Leader">
      <question>
Does Motormaster's ability prevent damage from character abilities? Such as Decepticon Shockwave's discard damage or Superion's first time combining ability if the opponent decided to target someone other than Motormaster?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-8" tags="Blurr - Fastest Bot in the Galaxy">
      <question>
If I have a Grenade Launcher on Blurr, and I attack a tapped character, which will occur first: the second attack on an untapped character, or scrapping the Grenade Launcher?
        </question>
      <answer>
Grenade Launcher only lasts for one battle, so it would be scrapped before Blurr launches his second attack.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-9" tags="Optimus Maximus - Ultimate Defender,Optimus Prime - Gleaming Commander">
      <question>
In a previous round up you mentioned that if Ion Blaster of Optimus Prime was played on Optimus, then he was combined into Optimus Maximus, the Combiner could keep that weapon, however not if he was already formed. I&#x2019;m assuming that also works with Laser Cutlass? Play onto an Aerialbot for example. Once combined, does it carry over?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="5-10">
      <question>
Regarding All-Out Attack.
Scenario:

Bumblebee-TL tapped in bot mode, Prowl-MS and Cliffjumper-RW untapped in car mode.
I play All-Out Attack. Cliffjumper attacks and uses Anticipation Engine to trigger a Start Your Engines. Bee flips to car mode, Prowl is irrelevant, Cliffjumper untaps. Using Bee's extra action via flip to alt mode, I play Ready for Action to untap Bee. Cliffjumper finishes his attack. All 3 cars are now untapped.

Am I free to attack again with Cliffjumper?
Am I free to attack with Bee?
Am I free to end my attacks when I choose because of AoA?
        </question>
      <answer>
All-Out Attack says &#x201C;Each of your untapped Transformers (Editor&#x2019;s Note: Characters) can attack this turn.&#x201D; At the time you play All-Out Attack, check which of your characters are untapped. Those characters are allowed to attack this turn, in sequence. They are not, however, required to attack. They can&#x2019;t attack a second time unless your opponent is tapped out. As usual, you still must attack with at least one character during your turn if you are able.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
