<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Wave 4 FAQ" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360035662892-War-for-Cybertron-Siege-II-FAQ-and-Rules-Roundup" sourced_at="2020-03-03">
    <target name="Bounty">
      <entry id="1">
        <question>
             What are Bounty abilities?
        </question>
        <answer>
             There are two parts to a Bounty ability: a trigger condition that tells you to &#x201C;use this card&#x2019;s Bounty ability&#x201D; and the Bounty ability itself that gives you a reward. In this set, all the conditions are the same: when the character does enough attack damage to KO an enemy. The rewards are different on each card.
        </answer>
        </entry>
      <entry id="2">
        <question>
             If a character does more than enough attack damage to KO an enemy, does that count?
        </question>
        <answer>
             Yes. The character can do more attack damage than is necessary to KO the enemy and you&#x2019;ll still get the reward.
        </answer>
        </entry>
    </target>
            <target name="Safeguard">
      <entry id="3">
        <question>
             What is Safeguard?
        </question>
        <answer>
             Safeguard is a new keyword ability that limits how much damage can be done to a character that&#x2019;s undamaged.
        </answer>
        </entry>
      <entry id="4">
        <question>
             Does Safeguard apply to all damage or just attack damage?
        </question>
        <answer>
             All damage, including damage done by Actions or other abilities.
        </answer>
        </entry>
      <entry id="5">
        <question>
             Does Safeguard work if something tries to move a damage counter onto the character while it&#x2019;s undamaged?
        </question>
        <answer>
             No. Moving damage counters doesn&#x2019;t count as damaging the character, although after the damage counter is moved, the character will be damaged and Safeguard will no longer work. Sneaky!
        </answer>
        </entry>
      <entry id="6">
        <question>
             Can Safeguard apply to the same character more than once?
        </question>
        <answer>
             Yes. Safeguard works as long as the character is currently undamaged, even if it was previously damaged in the game. If you repair that damage, Safeguard can cushion another blow.
        </answer>
        </entry>
    </target>
            <target name="Revenge">
      <entry id="7">
        <question>
             What are Revenge abilities?
        </question>
        <answer>
             A Revenge ability is a triggered ability that triggers when the character with the ability is KO&#x2019;d. There aren&#x2019;t that many of them. They&#x2019;re a Decepticon thing. The Decepticons must be up to something.
        </answer>
        </entry>
    </target>
            <target name="Battle Masters &amp; Weaponizers">
                <entry id="8" tags="Battle Master,Weaponizer">
        <question>
             What are Battle Masters &amp; Weaponizers?
        </question>
        <answer>
Battle Masters and Weaponizers are characters that start in bot mode and can be played in their Upgrade mode after they are KO&#x2019;d. They don&#x2019;t have alt modes and can&#x2019;t flip while they are on the battlefield.
In Siege 2 (Wave 4), there are two Weaponizers, each made up of two cards. They start assembled together in bot mode. When one of these Weaponizers is KO&#x2019;d, it splits into two different Upgrades that you can then play. These Upgrades can be played on separate characters or onto the same character.
After a Battle Master or Weaponizer Upgrade would leave the battlefield, it&#x2019;s put into your KO area instead.
        </answer>
    </entry>
    </target>
                <target name="Battle Cards in the KO Area">
      <entry id="9" tags="KO">
        <question>
             Several cards in this set cause battle cards to be put into the KO area. What does that mean?
        </question>
        <answer>
             Those cards are essentially out of the game, except if something specifically puts them somewhere else. They aren&#x2019;t scrapped, so they won&#x2019;t be reshuffled into your deck when your deck is empty.
        </answer>
    </entry>
</target>
  <target name="Captain Omega Supreme - Transport - City Defender">
    <entry id="10" mode="alt">
      <question>I noticed that Omega Supreme (Base) doesn&#x2019;t have an ability to combine into Captain Omega Supreme. What happens if both the Spaceship and Tank are KO&#x2019;d before I get the chance to combine?</question>
      <answer>The combine abilities don&#x2019;t work from the KO area, so in that case your Base would be left standing alone. Unless you have a way to bring the Spaceship or the Tank back onto the battlefield, you won&#x2019;t be able to combine them into Captain Omega Supreme. Good luck!</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="11" mode="alt">
      <question>The Spaceship and the Tank have very similar abilities to combine into Captain Omega Supreme. What happens if my opponent reshuffles their deck and both abilities would apply?</question>
      <answer>Captain Omega Supreme can only be combined once. The redundant ability is ignored.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Raider Skytread - Special Ops - Soldier">
    <entry id="12" mode="alt">
      <question>What happens if my last two characters are those two and they&#x2019;re both KO&#x2019;d at the same time. Dpo their Revenge abilities work and keep me in the game?</question>
      <answer>Unfortunately, no. Once your last character is KO&#x2019;d, you lose the game. Fortunately, having them both KO&#x2019;d at the same time is pretty unusual.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="13" mode="alt">
      <question>Both Revenge abilities put cards from my hand under Raider Skytread. What does this mean?</question>
      <answer>The cards under Raider Skytread are basically out of play for a while. They&#x2019;re not considered on the battlefield, even if that&#x2019;s where they are physically, so none of their abilities apply. If one of those cards is an Upgrade, that Upgrade isn&#x2019;t on Raider Skytread, and so on. They&#x2019;re also not in your scrap pile, so they won&#x2019;t be shuffled into your deck when it&#x2019;s empty. They can return to your hand using Raider Skytread&#x2019;s last ability.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Captain Astrotrain - Space Force - Transport">
    <entry id="14">
      <question>Each of Captain Astrotrain&#x2019;s abilities triggers if he has a certain number of Upgrades. What happens if the ability triggers, but then his Upgrades are scrapped during the attack?</question>
      <answer>Once the ability triggers, it doesn&#x2019;t matter how many Upgrades Captain Astrotrain has. He&#x2019;ll keep the specified bonus until end of turn.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Captain Jetfire - Engineering - Air Guardian">
    <entry id="15" mode="alt">
      <question>What happens if I have fewer than 5 cards in my deck when I flip Captain Jetfire to alt mode?</question>
      <answer>In that case you&#x2019;ll reveal as many cards as you can from your deck, then&#x2014;leaving those cards aside&#x2014;shuffle your scrap pile to rebuild your deck. Then reveal more cards so a total of 5 are revealed. The revealed cards that aren&#x2019;t Upgrades will be only cards in your scrap pile when you&#x2019;re done.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Lockdown - Bounty Hunter">
    <entry id="16" mode="bot">
      <question>Lockdown&#x2019;s Bounty ability puts a card from the bottom of my deck under himself. What does it mean when a card is under Lockdown?</question>
      <answer>The cards under Lockdown are basically out of play for a while. They&#x2019;re not considered on the battlefield, even if that&#x2019;s where they are physically, so none of their abilities apply. If one of those cards is an Upgrade, that Upgrade isn&#x2019;t on Lockdown, and so on. They&#x2019;re also not in your scrap pile, so they won&#x2019;t be shuffled into your deck when it&#x2019;s empty. They&#x2019;re just used to keep track of the bonuses from Lockdown&#x2019;s other abilities.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="17" mode="bot">
      <question>Can I look at the card as it&#x2019;s put under Lockdown?</question>
      <answer>No. The card is face-down, so neither player can look at it while it&#x2019;s under Lockdown.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="18" mode="bot">
      <question>What happens to the cards under Lockdown if he is KO&#x2019;d?</question>
      <answer>They&#x2019;re put into your scrap pile.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Lord Megatron - Conqueror of Cybertron">
    <entry id="19" mode="alt">
      <question>What happens if my opponent doesn&#x2019;t have enough cards in their deck to scrap?</question>
      <answer>In that case, your opponent scraps all the cards in their deck. Then, setting those cards aside, they shuffle all the other cards in their scrap pile into their deck. Then they scrap enough cards from their reformed deck to scrap the total number of cards they were supposed to. In most cases, however many cards they were supposed to scrap will be the number of cards in their scrap pile after Megatron&#x2019;s ability is finished. Sorry, after Lord Megatron&#x2019;s ability is finished.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="20" mode="bot">
      <question>What does &#x201C;reshuffles their deck&#x201D; mean?</question>
      <answer>Reshuffling your deck is when you shuffle your scrap pile into your deck because your deck is empty. If you shuffle your deck for another reason, that&#x2019;s not &#x201C;reshuffling your deck.&#x201D; That&#x2019;s just shuffling your deck.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="21" mode="bot">
      <question>Although it&#x2019;s unlikely, let&#x2019;s say my opponent&#x2019;s deck runs out of cards, but there are no cards in their scrap pile. What happens?</question>
      <answer>If there are no cards in their scrap pile, they can&#x2019;t reshuffle their deck, so Megatron . . . sorry, Lord Megatron&#x2019;s ability won&#x2019;t trigger.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Sergeant Six-Gun - Artillery - Soldier">
    <entry id="22" mode="bot">
      <question>If I have a Weapon in my hand that gives an attack bonus because of an ability in its text box, will that bonus count for Six-Gun&#x2019;s ability?</question>
      <answer>No. You can scrap a Weapon only if it has a + number in the orange stats box.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="MTX-S2A Guided Missile Launcher">
    <entry id="23" mode="bot">
      <question>This Weapon can be in an Armor or Utility slot. When I play it, do I have to say which slot it&#x2019;s in?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Usually, players indicate which slot an Upgrade is in by placing it on a particular side of the character: Weapons on the left, Armors on the right, and Utilities below. Once the Upgrade is in a slot, it can&#x2019;t be moved to another slot to free up space.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="24" mode="bot">
      <question>If MXT-S2A Guided Missile Launcher is put into an Armor slot, does it then count as an Armor?</question>
      <answer>No. It&#x2019;s always a Weapon, no matter what slot it&#x2019;s in.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Private Fixit - Rescue Patrol - Medic">
    <entry id="25" mode="bot">
      <question>What happens if a player has fewer than 4 cards in hand and the tap ability is used?</question>
      <answer>Each player draw 4 cards, no matter how many cards they scrapped.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Private Hot Rod - Infantry - Soldier">
    <entry id="26" mode="alt">
      <question>What does &#x201C;reshuffle your deck&#x201D; mean?</question>
      <answer>Reshuffling your deck is when you shuffle your scrap pile into your deck because your deck is empty. If you shuffle your deck for another reason, that&#x2019;s not &#x201C;reshuffling your deck.&#x201D; That&#x2019;s just shuffling your deck.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="27" mode="alt">
      <question>Hot Rod&#x2019;s ability puts a card from the bottom of my deck under himself. What does that mean?</question>
      <answer>The card under Hot Rod is basically out of play for a while. It&#x2019;s not considered on the battlefield, even though that&#x2019;s where it is physically, so none of its abilities apply. If it&#x2019;s an Upgrade, that Upgrade isn&#x2019;t on Hot Rod, and so on. It&#x2019;s also not in your scrap pile, so it won&#x2019;t be shuffled into your deck when it&#x2019;s empty. The card is used by its bot mode ability.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Private Seawatch - Rescue Patrol - Search &amp; Rescue">
    <entry id="28" mode="alt">
      <question>If I flip at least two white battle icons while one of my Rescue Patrols is battling, and the 3 additional battle cards I flip have two more white battle icons, do I flip 3 more battle cards again?</question>
      <answer>No. Private Seawatch&#x2019;s last ability can trigger only once each attack.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Private Sidetrack - Battle Patrol - Demolitions">
    <entry id="29" mode="bot">
      <question>What happens if I use the tap ability and have fewer than 4 cards in my deck?</question>
      <answer>In that case, scrap all the cards in their deck. Then, setting those cards aside, shuffle all the other cards in your scrap pile into your deck. Then scrap enough cards from your reformed deck to scrap a total of 4 cards. The cards that aren&#x2019;t Upgrades will be only cards in your scrap pile when you&#x2019;re done.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Private Turbo Board - Air Command - Evac">
    <entry id="30" mode="bot">
      <question>My opponent played a Secret Action. Does that count as one of the 2 cards they can play?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Note that if they end up revealing a Secret Action during their turn, that&#x2019;s not playing a card.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Private Vanguard - Ground Command - Advance Guard">
    <entry id="31" mode="bot">
      <question>How does Private Vanguard&#x2019;s ability interact with effects that modify how much attack damage a character takes, such as Blast Suit.</question>
      <answer>That ability doesn&#x2019;t directly modify how much attack damage is being done to the character (note it doesn&#x2019;t use &#x201C;instead&#x201D;), so it waits for effects like Blast Suit to apply, then sees if the character is taking more than 5 attack damage. If it is, the character takes 5 attack damage.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Raider Caliburst - Air Force - Weapons">
    <entry id="32" mode="bot">
      <question>Let&#x2019;s say my opponent plays Pep Talk, an Action that says &#x201C;Draw 2 cards.&#x201D; What happens?</question>
      <answer>Assuming they drew a card at the start of their turn, Raider Caliburst&#x2019;s ability would trigger twice. Your opponent could choose the same character for each one or they could choose a different character each time.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Sergeant Barricade - Infantry - Enforcer">
    <entry id="33" mode="bot">
      <question>Sergeant Barricade&#x2019;s ability puts a flipped card under himself instead of into your scrap pile. What does it mean when a card is under Sergeant Barricade?</question>
      <answer>The card under Sergeant Barricade is basically out of play for a bit (at least, until you play it using the alt ode ability). While the card is under Sergeant Barricade, it&#x2019;s not considered on the battlefield, even if that&#x2019;s where it is physically, so none of its abilities apply. If the card is an Upgrade, that Upgrade isn&#x2019;t on Sergeant Barricade, and so on. It&#x2019;s also not in your scrap pile, so it won&#x2019;t be shuffled into your deck when it&#x2019;s empty.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Sergeant Mirage - Special Ops - Spy">
    <entry id="34" mode="alt">
      <question>Is the card I reveal the card (or the first card) I draw?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Whether it has a blue battle icon or not, it will the card you next draw.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="35" mode="bot">
      <question>Several cards in this set put battle cards under characters on the battlefield. If my opponent does this, and one of those cards is a Secret Action, will Sergeant Mirage&#x2019;s ability see it and give him Tough 2?</question>
      <answer>No. Sergeant Mirage&#x2019;s ability looks only in the played area. Secret Actions that somehow end up in your opponent&#x2019;s KO area, scrap pile, or under a character on the battlefield don&#x2019;t count.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Sergeant Springer - Special Ops - Aerial Defense">
    <entry id="36" mode="bot">
      <question>Let&#x2019;s say I have exactly 7 cards in my hand when I flip Sergeant Springer to bot mode. Its ability triggers and I play an Action. Now I only have 6 cards in hand. Do I still get to play an Upgrade?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Once the ability triggers, you&#x2019;ll do everything it says. The trigger condition doesn&#x2019;t recheck in the middle.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Brunt - Artillery Drone">
    <entry id="37" mode="bot">
      <question>Does Brunt have a bot mode?</question>
      <answer>No. As a drone, Brunt has only alt mode. Brunt can&#x2019;t be flipped, so ignore any instruction that tells you to.  </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="4-Wheel Drive">
    <entry id="38">
      <question>If I play this on a Truck, and later in the turn it flips so it&#x2019;s no longer a Truck, what happens to its attack?</question>
      <answer>If the character stops being a Truck, 4-Wheel Drive stops applying, and its base attack will revert to whatever is printed on the card.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="39">
      <question>How do other attack bonuses work with 4-Wheel Drive?</question>
      <answer>Changing a character&#x2019;s base attack is just like changing the number that&#x2019;s printed on the card. From there, all other bonuses apply as normal. For example, if you have a Truck with 3 attack upgraded with Indestructible Sword (that gives it +2 attack), its attack will be 9 (7 from 4-Wheel Drive +2 from the upgrade). If it stops being a Truck that turn, its attack will be 5 (base 3 attack +2 from the upgrade).</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Backfire">
    <entry id="40">
      <question>If the damage done by Backfire is enough to KO the attacker, does the attacker still do attack damage?</question>
      <answer>No. You reveal Backfire before battle cards are flipped. In fact, if Backfire KO&#x2019;s the attacker, the attack will end and no one flips battle cards.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Multi-Missile Pod">
    <entry id="41">
      <question>Let&#x2019;s say I have three Multi-Missile Pods and I decide to FIRE ALL THE MISSILES! What happens?</question>
      <answer>Although you can totally FIRE ALL THE MISSILES, you still do it one at a time. So first you scrap one that will do 1 damage. Then you scrap the second to do 2 damage. Finally you scrap the last one to do 3 damage. 6 damage total.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Battlefield Incursion">
    <entry id="42">
      <question>Can I play Battlefield Incursion if there are no characters under my Trypticon?</question>
      <answer>You can. It won&#x2019;t have any effect itself, but other cards may have effects that depend on you playing Actions.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Blast Suit">
      <entry id="43">
          <question>Let&#x2019;s say I have a character with 10 health, 8 damage counters, and a Blast Suit. I also have Heroic Resolve face down. My opponent attacks, and my character would take 3 attack damage. What happens?</question>
          <answer>If there are multiple abilities trying to modify how much attack damage the upgraded character would take, the controller of that character decides what order to apply them in. In this example, you could choose either of the following:
    Reveal Heroic Resolve first. Instead of taking 3 attack damage, your character is now taking 1 attack damage (enough to drop it to 1 health). Now Blast Suit applies, and the 1 attack damage becomes 0 attack damage, which is half of 1 rounded down. Your character ends up taking no attack damage and Blast Suit is scrapped.
    Apply Blast Suit first. Instead of taking 3 attack damage, your character now is taking 1 attack damage, which is half of 3 rounded down. This isn&#x2019;t enough attack damage to KO your character, so Heroic Resolve stays face down.
          </answer>
      </entry>
</target>
  <target name="Composite Armor">
    <entry id="44">
      <question>If I flip at least one black battle icon during the battle, when does Composite Armor do 1 damage to the attacker?</question>
      <answer>The damage is done after the battle, just after you scrap Composite Armor.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="45">
      <question>If I didn&#x2019;t flip a black battle icon during the battle, do I still have to scrap Composite Armor?</question>
      <answer>Yes.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Contract Contingency">
    <entry id="46">
      <question>Can I choose a character that doesn&#x2019;t have a Bounty ability just to get the attack bonus?</question>
      <answer>Yes. The last ability won&#x2019;t do anything, but you&#x2019;ll still get the +2 attack.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Coup">
    <entry id="47">
      <question>If the character that was KO&#x2019;d has was one of my characters with a Bounty ability, can I use that ability?</question>
      <answer>No. That character is no longer on the battlefield when Coup&#x2019;s ability is uses.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Crowbar">
    <entry id="48">
      <question>If Crowbar is put onto a character during a battle after it attacks, is it scrapped after the battle?</question>
      <answer>No. The ability triggers only if the character is holding the Crowbar as it attacks. If Crowbar appears after that point (say because of Metal Detector), it can stay for at least another attack.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Crude Club">
    <entry id="49">
      <question>Does Crude Club count?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Even with no other Upgrades, the upgraded character will get +1 attack from just the Crude Club.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Daring Escape">
    <entry id="50">
      <question>Are the cards revealed when they&#x2019;re put into the KO area?</question>
      <answer>Yes. They will be face up in the KO area. Either player can look at them. (Don&#x2019;t grab your opponent&#x2019;s cards without permission though.)</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Decipher">
    <entry id="51">
      <question>If my opponent has Secret Actions in their hand, scrap pile, or even in their KO area (say because of Daring Escape), do those count?</question>
      <answer>No. Daring Escape counts only the Secret Actions in your opponent&#x2019;s played area.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Defensive Configuration">
    <entry id="52">
      <question>Say the upgraded character has 2 Armors and Defensive Configuration is scrapped. What happens?</question>
      <answer>In most cases, this means the character won&#x2019;t have enough Armor slots to keep both Armors. If it&#x2019;s your character, you choose which one the character keeps. The other one is scrapped.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Dual Wield">
    <entry id="53">
      <question>At the end of the turn the character will lose the extra Weapon slot. Which Weapon does the character keep?</question>
      <answer>If it&#x2019;s your character, you choose which one the character keeps. The other one is scrapped.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Energy Transfer">
    <entry id="54">
      <question>How does Energy Transfer interact with cards like Toolbox?</question>
      <answer>Moving damage counters doesn&#x2019;t count as repairing or damaging either character.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="55">
      <question>Can I choose to move no damage counters?</question>
      <answer>Yes. You can even play Energy Transfer if you have only one character or if none of your characters have damage counters on them. It won&#x2019;t have any effect itself, but other cards may have effects that depend on you playing Actions, and you&#x2019;ll get the orange battle icon back in your deck.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Even the Score">
    <entry id="56">
      <question>How does Even the Score interact with effects that modify how much attack damage a character takes, such as Blast Suit.</question>
      <answer>Even the Score doesn&#x2019;t directly modify how much attack damage is being done to the character (note it doesn&#x2019;t use &#x201C;instead&#x201D;), so it waits for effects like Blast Suit to apply, then sees if the character is taking more than enough attack damage to be KO&#x2019;d.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="57">
      <question>Is the damage done to the attacker attack damage?</question>
      <answer>No. Only damage done by the attacker counts as attack damage. Damage done by other cards, such as the damage done by Even the Score, isn&#x2019;t attack damage.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Guarded Posture">
    <entry id="58">
      <question>Say a character with base attack 0 has Guarded Posture, and then I put a Primary Laser (a Weapon that gives it +2 attack) on it. What is the character&#x2019;s attack?</question>
      <answer>It will have 1 attack. Although a character&#x2019;s attack can&#x2019;t go below 0, the -1 applies again once your character&#x2019;s attack is raised.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Head-on Collision">
    <entry id="59">
      <question>If the chosen character attacks in alt mode but then somehow flips to a different mode in the middle of the attack, does it keep the +3 attack bonus?</question>
      <answer>No. The +3 attack bonus applies as long as the character is attacking and in alt mode. As soon as one of those isn&#x2019;t true, the bonus stops applying. However, if the character returns to alt mode while it&#x2019;s still attacking, the bonus would apply again.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Heroic Resolve">
    <entry id="60">
      <question>How does Heroic Resolve with other effects that try to modify how much attack damage is done to a character?</question>
      <answer>If there are multiple abilities trying to modify how much attack damage the upgraded character would take, the controller of that character decides what order to apply them in. See the entry for Blast Suit for an example.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Hijack">
    <entry id="61">
      <question>Jack: Hi!</question>
      <answer>Hello.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="62">
      <question>After I reveal Hijack, do I draw the card from my opponent&#x2019;s deck they were going to draw?</question>
      <answer>No. You always draw from your deck. Nothing happens to the card your opponent was going to draw. It just stays on top of their deck.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="63">
      <question>Let&#x2019;s say my opponent plays Pep Talk, an Action that says &#x201C;Draw 2 cards.&#x201D; What happens?</question>
      <answer>Assuming they drew a card at the start of their turn, you would reveal Hijack. Then instead them drawing two cards, you&#x2019;d draw two cards. Hijack&#x2019;s effect lasts for the rest of the turn, so if they tried to draw more cards, you&#x2019;d draw them again.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Increased Durability">
    <entry id="64">
      <question>Let&#x2019;s say the upgraded character normally has 10 health. It gets upgraded with Increased Durability, then gets 12 damage counters. If Increased Durability is scrapped, what happens?</question>
      <answer>Any time the game notices a character with a number of damage counters equal to or greater than its current health, the character is KO&#x2019;d. So your character is KO&#x2019;d. Sorry.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Indestructible Sword">
    <entry id="65">
      <question>If Indestructible Sword is on a character that gets KO&#x2019;d, do I return the Sword to my hand?</question>
      <answer>Yes. If a character is KO&#x2019;d, all upgrades it had are scrapped at the same time. The game sees that the upgrade was scrapped from a character.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Involuntary Promotion">
    <entry id="66">
      <question>What happens if the character I bring back from the KO area ends up with enough damage counters to KO it?</question>
      <answer>Both characters will end up KO&#x2019;d, but the character that started in the KO area will be on the battlefield for a short time. For example, any ability that triggers when Upgrades are moved onto that character will still happen. If that character has any revenge abilities, those abilities will also happen.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Jam Signals">
    <entry id="67">
      <question>Say my opponent has an ability that triggers when they play an Action. They play a blue action, but I reveal Jam Signals to scrap it with no effect. Does their other ability trigger?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Although the blue action itself will have no effect, your opponent still played an action, so the other ability will still work.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Kinetic Intensifier Whip">
    <entry id="68">
      <question>Can this ability trigger more than once in the same turn?</question>
      <answer>Yes. If you&#x2019;re showing off and have some way to flip the upgraded character multiple times in the same turn, the ability will add Bold 2 each time.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Lucky Vest">
    <entry id="69">
      <question>How does Lucky Vest interact with other effects that modify the amount of attack damage a character can take?</question>
      <answer>Lucky Vest doesn&#x2019;t directly modify how much attack damage is being done to the character (note it doesn&#x2019;t use &#x201C;instead&#x201D;), so it waits for effects like Blast Suit to apply, then sees if the character is taking more than 4 attack damage. If it is, the character takes 4 attack damage.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Minor Medic Kit">
    <entry id="70">
      <question>Let&#x2019;s say the upgraded character normally has 10 health. It gets upgraded with Minor Medic Kit, then gets 10 damage counters. If Minor Medic Kit is scrapped, what happens?</question>
      <answer>Any time the game notices a character with a number of damage counters equal to or greater than its current health, the character is KO&#x2019;d. So your character is KO&#x2019;d. Really sorry.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Opportune Offensive / Opportune Repairs">
    <entry id="71">
      <question>Does it matter if the Mercenary on my team got KO&#x2019;d before I played Opportune Offensive or Opportune Repairs?</question>
      <answer>Nope. As long as it was on your starting team, you can play it.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Overheat">
    <entry id="72">
      <question>If Overheat is revealed, do effects like Energized Field&#x2019;s still work?</question>
      <answer>Yes. With Overheat, orange battle icons don&#x2019;t add to the attack value, but they were still flipped, so any other effects that care about flipping orange battle icons will still work. The same is true for black battle icons.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Overwhelming Advantage">
    <entry id="73">
      <question>Say I have 3 Decepticons on the battlefield when I play Overwhelming Advantage. Can I put just 2 cards from my hand on top of my deck?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Each Plan is optional, so you could anywhere from 0 to 3 cards from your hand on top of your deck.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="74">
      <question>Do I have to choose one of my characters when I play Overwhelming Advantage?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Even if you have two characters with the right upgrades and you plan to attack with both of them during your turn, you choose which character will be affected when you play Overwhelming Advantage.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="75">
      <question>If I meet all the conditions listed in the second ability (WOOHOO!), and the 15 damage is enough to KO the defender, will my opponent flip battle cards?</question>
      <answer>No. As soon as the defender is KO&#x2019;d, the attack ends.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Pincer Movement">
    <entry id="76">
      <question>Say I play Pincer Movement, but the first attack ends up KOing the defender. Do I still get to attack again?</question>
      <answer>No. If you can&#x2019;t attack the same enemy with a different Decepticon, you don&#x2019;t get the extra attack.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Relentless Invasion">
    <entry id="77">
      <question>Can I still attack with another character that turn?</question>
      <answer>Yes. The characters put onto the battlefield will all attack that turn (one at a time), but you can attack with a character as normal. That could be Trypticon or a different character that was already on the battlefield.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="78">
      <question>What happens if one of the characters I put onto the battlefield is somehow KO&#x2019;d before the turn ends? Is it still put under Trypticon?</question>
      <answer>No. If the character gets KO&#x2019;d, it will just stay in the KO area at end of turn.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="79">
      <question>Can I play this card if only one or two of the characters are in the KO area?</question>
      <answer>Yes. You&#x2019;ll put as many of the three characters onto the battlefield as you can. For example, let&#x2019;s say you have Full-Tilt on the battlefield, Wipe-Out in the KO area, and Brunt under Trypticon. Playing Relentless Invasion will put Wipe-Out onto the battlefield. It will attack this turn and then be put back under Trypticon. Full-Tilt doesn&#x2019;t have to attack, and at the end of the turn it will stay on the battlefield.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Reprocess">
    <entry id="80">
      <question>Any character?</question>
      <answer>Yep. Yours or your opponent&#x2019;s. Even if there&#x2019;s no damage to repair.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Shoulder Holster">
    <entry id="81">
      <question>Say the upgraded character has 2 Weapons and Shoulder Holster is scrapped. What happens?</question>
      <answer>In most cases, this means the character won&#x2019;t have enough Weapon slots to keep both Weapons. If it&#x2019;s your character, you choose which one the character keeps. The other one is scrapped.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Step Forward">
    <entry id="82">
      <question>Once I reveal Step Forward and choose one of my Autobots to get Brave, can my opponent change which of their characters is attacking?</question>
      <answer>No. The choice of attacker is locked in before Step Forward is revealed.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Sturdy Javelin">
    <entry id="83">
      <question>If Sturdy Javelin is on a ranged character, can I do 2 damage to any enemy, or must it be the defender?</question>
      <answer>Nope, you can throw the Javelin in any direction to hit any enemy.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Valuable Contract">
    <entry id="84">
      <question>Do I have to show my opponent which card I&#x2019;m putting into my hand?</question>
      <answer>Yes. Your opponent is allowed to see the card and verify it has exactly 1 star.</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="85">
      <question>Say I upgrade a character that already has a Bounty ability with Valuable Contract. If it does enough attack damage to an enemy to KO it, what happens?</question>
      <answer>In that case, you&#x2019;ll get to use both Bounty abilities in either order. You can&#x2019;t use the character&#x2019;s Bounty ability twice or Valuable Contract&#x2019;s Bounty ability twice though.</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
