<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Wave 1 Characters" source="https://wpn.wizards.com/en/document/transformers-tcg-faq" published_date="2018-10-11" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
  <target name="Arcee, Skilled Fighter">
    <entry id="arcee-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
                What happens if some of my characters are undamaged when I flip Arcee to alt mode?
            </question>
      <answer>
                There are no damage counters to remove, so nothing happens to those characters.
            </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="arcee-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
        If Arcee&#x2019;s attack is boosted by actions or Upgrades, does that raise her Pierce number?
    </question>
      <answer>
        Yes. For example, if you play an action card that gives Arcee +2 attack until end of turn, she&#x2019;ll have Pierce 3.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="arcee-3" mode="bot">
      <question>
        Let&#x2019;s say I attack with Arcee and reveal two orange attack icons, giving her +2 attack. Does her Pierce number go up?
    </question>
      <answer>
        Yes.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="arcee-4" mode="bot">
      <question>
        What happens if Arcee has a Piercing Blaster or another Upgrade that gives her more Pierce?
    </question>
      <answer>
        In that case, Arcee will have Pierce equal to her attack plus the Pierce from the Upgrade. In that example, Arcee&#x2019;s attack is 1, so she&#x2019;ll have Pierce 4. However, remember that characters with Pierce 
can&#x2019;t deal more damage than their attack total, so she&#x2019;ll do only 1 damage (not including other attack bonuses or orange battle icons).
    </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Autobot Cosmos, Recon &amp; Communication">
    <entry id="autobot-cosmos-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
        If there are two cards left in my deck, and I attack with Autobot Cosmos, will his ability trigger?
    </question>
      <answer>
        Yes. You reshuffle your scrap pile into your deck as soon as the deck is empty. In this case, Autobot Cosmos will attack, you&#x2019;ll flip up the two remaining cards in your deck, and the defender will be KO&#x2019;d (assuming it has 12 starsor fewer). Your opponent won&#x2019;t flip any battle cards for the attack if their character is KO&#x2019;d this way.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="autobot-cosmos-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
        Say Autobot Cosmos has a Data Pad. Will Autobot Cosmos&#x2019;s ability trigger if you draw the last card of your deck while he&#x2019;s attacking?
    </question>
      <answer>
        Yes. Drawing the last card of your deck will cause you to shuffle your deck, and this will cause Autobot Cosmos to KO the defender.
    </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Autobot Hound, Long-Range Scout">
    <entry id="autobot-hound-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Let&#x2019;s say you attack with another character and flip a white battle icon. Then, because your
opponent&#x2019;s characters are all tapped, you get to attack again. For your second attack, you attack with
Autobot Hound and flip a white battle icon. Will his ability trigger?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. The white battle icon you flipped while attacking with Autobot Hound wasn&#x2019;t your first white
battle icon that turn, so he won&#x2019;t get the bonus.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Autobot Jazz, Special Ops">
    <entry id="autobot-jazz-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    If the attacking character would deal more than 2 damage, what happens to the extra damage?
</question>
      <answer>
    The extra damage doesn&#x2019;t happen. The attacking character will deal only 2 damage.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="autobot-jazz-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    Let&#x2019;s say Autobot Jazz defends and the attacker has an ability that deals damage to him. Does that
damage count for Autobot Jazz&#x2019;s ability?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. Any damage dealt to Autobot Jazz while he&#x2019;s defending and his ability is active will count. If the
attacker has an ability that deals 1 damage to Autobot Jazz, then he can&#x2019;t take more than 1 more
damage from the attack.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Autobot Mirage, Lone Wolf">
    <entry id="autobot-mirage-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    If I played an action because of his ability, can I play another action that turn?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Bumblebee, Courageous Scout">
    <entry id="bumblebee-cs-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    What happens if I have no cards in my hand when I use this ability?
</question>
      <answer>
    You&#x2019;ll draw a card, look at it, and immediately put it on top of your deck. You can&#x2019;t do anything else
with the card (like play it) before putting it on top of your deck.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="bumblebee-cs-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Let&#x2019;s say I reveal one white battle icon during Bumblebee&#x2019;s combat. Then I flip another white battle
icon in the two bonus cards. Will his ability trigger?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. For any ability that looks at what battle icons you flipped, flip your two bonus cards before
checking if that ability triggers or not.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Bumblebee, Legendary Warrior">
    <entry id="bumblebee-lw-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    Does flipping Bumblebee to alt mode mean I have to attack with him that turn?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. It just lets Bumblebee attack untapped enemies if you decide to attack with Bumblebee.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="bumblebee-lw-2" mode="alt">
      <question>
    Can Bumblebee still attack tapped enemies that turn?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. Because Bumblebee will be able to attack any enemy, tapped or untapped, you choose which
enemy he attacks.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="bumblebee-lw-3" mode="alt">
      <question>
    Does attacking an untapped enemy cause that enemy to become tapped?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. The enemy will stay untapped. None of the other rules of combat change.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Chop Shop, Sneaky Insecticon">
    <entry id="chop-shop-1" mode="alt"><question>
    If I scrap three Upgrades from Chop Shop, can I repair 1 damage from each of three of my
</question>
Insecticons, or do I have to repair 3 damage from one Insecticon?
<answer>
    You can choose a different Insecticon for each repair.
</answer>
</entry>
    <entry id="chopshop-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If Chop Shop has a Weapon attached to him, can you move another Weapon onto him?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes, but you&#x2019;ll have to scrap the Weapon he originally had.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="chopshop-3" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If the Upgrade I move onto Chop Shop has an ability that triggers &#x201C;when the Upgraded character
attacks,&#x201D; does that ability trigger?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. That Upgrade wasn&#x2019;t on Chop Shop when he attacked, so that ability won&#x2019;t trigger.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="chopshop-4" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If the Upgrade I move onto Chop Shop gives him Bold or an ability to flip extra battle cards when
attacking, do I flip extra battle cards?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. Chop Shop&#x2019;s ability happens before you flip battle cards, so Upgrades that give Chop Shop Bold
will work.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="chopshop-5" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Can Chop Shop&#x2019;s ability be used to move an Upgrade that says &#x201C;Put only on Planes&#x201D; onto him?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. Any ability that says what an Upgrade can be put on still apply, so you can&#x2019;t sneak Upgrades onto
Chop Shop that he can&#x2019;t have.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Chromia, Special Ops">
    <entry id="chromia-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Let&#x2019;s say I reveal one white battle icon during Chromia&#x2019;s attack. Then I flip another white battle icon
in the two bonus cards. Will her ability trigger?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. For any ability that looks at what battle icons you flipped, flip your two bonus cards before
checking if that ability triggers or not.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Cliffjumper, Renegade Warrior">
    <entry id="cliffjumper-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    What happens if one of my characters that&#x2019;s a Car while in alt mode but not in bot mode is KO&#x2019;d
while it&#x2019;s in bot mode?
</question>
      <answer>
    Characters are put in the KO area in the same mode they were in on the battlefield. In that case, the
KO&#x2019;d character isn&#x2019;t a Car and won&#x2019;t add to Cliffjumper&#x2019;s bonus.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Darkmount - Cruel Overlord">
    <entry xref="Rules_Roundup#1-17"/>
  </target>
  <target name="Decepticon Shockwave - Cybertron Commander">
      <entry xref="Rules_Roundup#1-1" mode="bot"/>
      <entry xref="Rules_Roundup#1-3" mode="bot"/>
  </target>
  <target name="Demolisher, Devoted Decepticon">
    <entry id="demolisher-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If I play an Action or Upgrade to increase Demolisher&#x2019;s defense, do I flip that many more battle cards?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. Consider Demolisher&#x2019;s current defense, including all bonuses from other cards, when
determining how many more battle cards you flip.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Dinobot Sludge, Mighty Stomper">
    <entry id="dinobot-sludge-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    Dinobot Sludge&#x2019;s health is 12. Let&#x2019;s say there are 15 damage counters total on my other Dinobots.
When I flip Dinobot Sludge to alt mode, can I move all those damage counters onto him?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. This will, of course, cause Dinobot Sludge to be KO&#x2019;d. He&#x2019;ll be sad.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Dinobot Snarl, Desert Warrior">
    <entry id="dinobot-snarl-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Do I put the card on top of my deck before flipping battle cards?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. The card you put on top of your deck (if any) will be the first battle card you flip.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Grimlock, Dinobot Leader">
    <entry id="grimlock-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    Can Grimlock give himself Bold 3 with his ability.
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. Grimlock Dinobot. Grimlock count.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="grimlock-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    How does Grimlock&#x2019;s ability work?
</question>
      <answer>
    Let&#x2019;s say Grimlock attacks a character with 10 health and 8 damage counters. If he does 4 attack
damage to that character, 2 of that damage is enough to KO the defender. For the extra 2 damage, your
opponent chooses one of their other characters. That character would get 2 damage counters.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="grimlock-3" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Let&#x2019;s say the extra damage is enough to KO a second character. Does the extra damage keep going to
a third character?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. The extra damage isn&#x2019;t attack damage. Continuing the previous example, your opponent could
choose a character with 12 health and 11 damage counters and do 2 more damage to it. That character
would be KO&#x2019;d.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Inferno, Fearless Firefighter">
    <entry id="inferno-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    Can I choose one of my characters and return all its Upgrades to my hand?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. You can choose any character, one of yours or an enemy. You could even choose a character with
no Upgrades if you didn&#x2019;t want to return any to their owner&#x2019;s hand.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Insecticon Skrapnel, Insecticon leader">
    <entry id="insecticon-skrapnel-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If the attacking character would deal more than 3 damage, what happens to the extra damage?
</question>
      <answer>
    The extra damage doesn&#x2019;t happen. The attacking character will deal only 3 damage.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="insecticon-skrapnel-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Let&#x2019;s say Insecticon Skrapnel defends and the attacker has an ability that deals damage to him. Does
that damage count for Insecticon Skrapnel&#x2019;s ability?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. Any damage dealt to Insecticon Skrapnel while he&#x2019;s defending will count. If the attacker has an
ability that deals 1 damage to Insecticon Skrpanel, then he can&#x2019;t take more than 2 more damage from
the attack.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry xref="Rules_Roundup#1-14" mode="bot"/>
  </target>
  <target name="Jetfire, Air Guardian">
    <entry id="jetfire-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Can I use Jetfire&#x2019;s ability to put an Upgrade on him if he already has an Upgrade of that type?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes, but you&#x2019;ll have to scrap the Upgrade of that type he originally had.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Megatron, Living Weapon">
    <entry id="megatron-lw-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Does Megatron&#x2019;s ability mean he can hold three Weapons?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. He can have a Weapon in his Weapon slot as well as Weapons in his Armor and/or Utility slots.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="megatron-lw-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If I play a Weapon on Megatron, do I have to choose which slot it&#x2019;s going in?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. As long as Megatron can hold all the Upgrades attached to him, you don&#x2019;t have to specify which
slot anything is in. For example, if Megatron has two Weapons and a Utility, and you play an Armor onto
him, you can choose at that time which Weapon it will replace.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="megatron-lw-3" mode="bot">
      <question>
    When Megatron flips to alt mode, can he keep all his Weapons?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. The bot mode ability applies only to how the Weapons are put on Megatron.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Nemesis Prime, Dark Clone">
    <entry id="nemesis-prime-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Can I look at the bottom card of my deck before putting it under Nemesis Prime?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. Neither you nor your opponent will know what card it is.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="nemesis-prime-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    What happens to the cards under Nemesis Prime when he&#x2019;s KO&#x2019;d?
</question>
      <answer>
    They&#x2019;re put into the scrap pile, along with any Upgrades he had.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Optimus Prime, Battlefield Legend">
    <entry id="opbl-1" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If I flip a white battle icon, do I flip the extra cards before using Optimus Prime&#x2019;s ability?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. The ability works after you&#x2019;ve flipped all cards, including extra cards from abilities like Bold or
from white battle icons.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="opbl-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If I play one of the Actions I flip, do I still count its orange battle icons?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. The Action card was still flipped for the attack, so its orange battle icons will still count.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="opbl-3" mode="bot">
      <question>
    If the Action I play gives Optimus Prime Bold, can I flip more battle cards?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. You&#x2019;ve already flipped cards for that attack.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Prowl, Military Strategist">
    <entry id="prowl-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    If I flip Prowl to alt mode and give my Cars Bold 2, but later in the turn I flip one of my Cars so it&#x2019;s no
longer a Car, does it keep Bold 2 until end of turn?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. Once the bonus has applied, the character will keep Bold 2 until the end of the turn.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="prowl-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    Prowl&#x2019;s ability says &#x201C;When one of your Cars is KO&#x2019;d -&gt; Repair 3 damage from one of your other
characters.&#x201D; Does &#x201C;one of your other characters&#x201D; mean other than Prowl or other than the Car that was
KO&#x2019;d?
</question>
      <answer>
    It means other than Prowl. Prowl can&#x2019;t repair himself.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Ransack, Insecticon Commando">
    <entry id="ransack-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    What happens if I flip Ransack to alt mode and there are no damaged characters?
</question>
      <answer>
    In that case, nothing happens. No damage counters are put on Ransack.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="ransack-2" mode="alt">
      <question>
    What happens if the only damaged characters are enemies? Can I choose one of my characters and
do nothing?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. You choose any other character, damaged or not. Then move 2 damage counters from that
character onto Ransack fi you can.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="ransack-3" mode="bot">
      <question>
    How does Ransack&#x2019;s ability work with Actions or Upgrades that raise his attack?
</question>
      <answer>
    Ransack&#x2019;s ability sets his base attack value, what you&#x2019;d see printed on the card if it didn&#x2019;t change.
From there, Actions and Upgrades can raise that value. For example, if Ransack has 5 damage counters,
his base attack would be 5. If he then got a Weapon that gave him +2 attack, his attack would be 7. This
wouldn&#x2019;t change the number of damage counters on him.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Slipstream, Strategic Seeker">
    <entry id="slipstream-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    What happens if the 1 damage counter I move onto the defender is enough to KO it?
</question>
      <answer>
    If either character is KO&#x2019;d in the middle of an attack, the attack immediately ends. In that case, you
won&#x2019;t flip battle cards (and neither will your opponent).
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="slipstream-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    What does &#x201C;3 different battle icons&#x201D; mean? If I flip two orange battle icons and one blue battle icon,
does that count?
</question>
      <answer>
    No. It means you must flip at least one of three different battle icons. For example, one orange, one
blue, and one white battle icon.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Sunstorm, Fusion Flyer">
    <entry id="sunstorm-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    What happens if I have 3 or more cards in my hand when I flip Sunstorm to alt mode?
</question>
      <answer>
    Nothing. You won&#x2019;t draw any cards, and nothing happens to the cards in your hand.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="sunstorm-2" mode="bot">
      <question>
    How does Sunstorm&#x2019;s ability work with Actions or Upgrades that raise his attack?
</question>
      <answer>
    Sunstorm&#x2019;s ability sets his base attack value, what you&#x2019;d see printed on the card if it didn&#x2019;t change.
From there, Actions and Upgrades can raise that value. For example, if you have 3 cards in hand, his
base attack would be 3. If he then got a Weapon that gave him +2 attack, his attack would be 5. This
wouldn&#x2019;t change the number of cards in your hand.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Thundercracker, Mach Warrior">
    <entry id="thundercracker-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    What happens if my opponent doesn&#x2019;t have any melee enemies?
</question>
      <answer>
    In that case, nothing happens.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Wheeljack, Weapons Inventor">
    <entry id="wheeljack-1" mode="alt">
      <question>
    If I play an Action that puts an Upgrade on one of my Cars, does Wheeljack&#x2019;s ability trigger?
</question>
      <answer>
    Yes. That ability triggers no matter how the Upgrade was put onto one of your Cars.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
