<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Additional Keywords" source="Community" source_url="https://github.com/tftcg/faq">
  <target name="Dinobot Enigma">
    <entry id="1" tags="Grimlock - Powerful Commander">
      <question>Dinobot Enigma says "5 Dinobots in bot mode", can I use Wave 1 Dinobots to form Volcanicus?</question>
      <answer>No. The Wave 2 Combiner Dinobots must be used. This was covered in a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/TransformersTCG/videos/volcanicus-and-not/473222143208266/">video</a>. </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Cargo Trailer">
      <entry id="2">
          <!-- This is based on a Facebook screenshot shared on Discord of a question WotC answered -->
          <question>
              If a character has more than one Cargo Trailer, how much additional attack does it have?
          </question>
          <answer>
              <ul><li>One cargo trailer &#x2192; +1 attack</li><li>Two cargo trailers &#x2192; +4 attack</li><li>Three cargo trailers &#x2192; +9 attack</li></ul>
              Each cargo trailer checks for how many cargo trailers are on the bot. So, with three cargo trailers equipped,
              the first one checks, sees that three cargo trailers are on the bot, and adds three attack. Then the second one 
              checks and adds an additional three attack and so on. 
          </answer>
      </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Gold Bumblebee - Electrum Warrior">
      <entry id="3">
          <question>
              What is the English translation of the Bumblebee Lunar New Year Promotion?
          </question>
          <answer>
            Bumblebee - Electrum Warrior
              Alt-mode: "When you flip to this mode -> This character has Bold 2 until end of turn. "
              Bot-mode: "While this character has 5 or more damage counters -> It has Tough 2. "
         </answer>

      </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Limited Sideboarding">
      <entry id="3">
          <question>
              How does Sideboarding work in Limited competitions (e.g. Sealed or Draft)?
          </question>
          <answer>
              The Tournament Rules (2019-11-21) say that <i>"Players participating in Limited tournaments may freely change the composition of their decks between matches (but not games) by exchanging cards from their deck for other cards in their card pool without being required to return their deck to its original composition before their next match."</i>. 
              This is the expectation for regular instore play, however, for the Energon International it was determined that (in <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/transformerstcg/permalink/2591276550907826/?comment_id=2591285324240282">this Facebook post</a>) that <i>"Players will need to return to their registered configuration prior to Game 1 of any match and they will be able to sideboard cards in during Games 2 &amp; 3."</i>
              Despite this expectation, most competitions appear to follow the Energon International format, but ultimtely it is up to the discretion of the tournament organizer. 
          </answer>
      </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Turbo Rules">
      <entry id="4">
          <question>
              What do you do with battle cards costing 1 or more stars?
          </question>
          <answer>
              You include them in your Turbo deck as usual. They do not apply to the cost of your deck in Turbo, so they do not affect the amount of damage taken before the game. 
          </answer>
      </entry>
  </target>
  <target name="Perceptor - Precise Sniper">
      <entry id="5">
          <question>
              With respect to Perceptor's alt mode ability, is zero a pile?
          </question>
          <answer>
              Yes, zero is a pile. It is perfectly fine to split the cards into two piles, one of four cards and one of zero. Listen to this <a href="https://soundcloud.com/vectorsigma-info/traveling-transformer-ep9-matt-smith">designer interview</a> for confirmation (30:26 into the interview). 
          </answer>
      </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
