<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Wave 5 Communuty FAQ" source="Community" source_url="https://github.com/tftcg/faq">
    <target name="PLACEHOLDER">
        <!--
      <entry id="1">
        <question>
             How many stars does a Titan Master (Head mode + Body mode) cost?
        </question>
        <answer>
            For the purposes of building a deck, both the Head and the Body star costs are included in the 25-star limit unless otherwise stated.

            For the purposes of the cost of the character, then both the Head and Body apply. For example, a 7-star Body with a 4-star Head is 11-stars and thus can use an Energy Pack. 
        </answer>
        </entry>
        -->
        <entry id="2" tags="Head Mode &amp; Body Mode">
            <question>
                Can you I Still Function a character with a Body mode?
            </question>
            <answer>
                <!-- Content in a WotC article I believe -->
                You can't bring back a Body mode character from KO because it won't have a head. Effects like I Still Function! and Involuntary Promotion will not work at all to bring back a Body. You can, however, bring back a Head from KO because it will be in Bot mode (and only in Bot mode). 
            </answer>
        </entry>
        <entry id="3" tags="Head Mode &amp; Body Mode">
          <question>
            Does a card that refers to Bot Mode apply to a Titan Master (Head + Body mode)?
          </question>
          <answer>
            No. A character in Body mode is not also in Bot mode.

            This means that cards like Escape Route do not flip a Body mode character to Alt mode. For an example of a card that works with both Body mode and Bot mode characters, look at how Mission Briefing explicitly says 'in bot mode or body mode'. 
            Note that cards like Start Your Engines and Hunker Down do not flip the characters from Body mode to Alt mode, however if the characters have Car and Tank traits respectively, they still get the secondary effects of those cards. 
          </answer>
      </entry>
      <entry id="8" tags="Head Mode &amp; Body Mode">
          <question>
              Which cards do not 'work' on a character in Body mode?
          </question>
          <answer>
              The following cards apply to Bot mode and thus will not affect an enemy character in its Body mode:
                - Cornered!
                - Marksmanship
              The following cards apply to Bot mode and thus will not affect one of your characters in its Body mode:
                - Cliffjumper - Renegade Warrior's Alt mode ability
                - Conversion Expertise (still provides Tough 1 in Alt mode)
                - Escape Route
                - Hit and Run
                - Hunker Down (still upgrades with Armor if the character with Body mode is currently a Tank)
                - Pop a Wheelie (if there was a Motorcycle with a Body mode, it would not flip)
                - Roll Out!
                - Start Your Engines (still untaps if the character with Body mode is currently a Car)
                - Swerve
                - Unconventional Flying Object
          </answer>
      </entry>
      <entry id="4" tags="Hybrid Battle Icon">
          <question>
              Why are there tiny icons on the Battle Icons?
          </question>
          <answer>
              Hybrid Battle Icons, introduced in <a href="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360039289832-Nagle-s-Notes-When-Icons-Combine">When Icons Combine</a> are new with Wave 5. They consist of a Trait icon on top of a Battle Icon, and only a character with that Trait receives the benefit of the icon colour when flipping in a battle. For example, a Ranged icon on top of a Green pip would allow only a character in Ranged form (i.e. showing a Ranged trait) to swap that card at the end of a battle. 
          </answer>
      </entry>
      <entry id="5" tags="Hybrid Battle Icon">
          <question>
              Which cards have Hybrid Battle Icons?
          </question>
          <answer>
              The following cards have Hybrid Battle Icons:
                  - Concealing Contrails (Plane)
                  - Hand-To-Hand Combat (Melee)
                  - Headbutt (Titan Master)
                  - Hull Down (Tank)
                  - Lock on Target (Plane)
                  - Master of Metallikato (Specialist/Ranged/Melee)
                  - Nitro Booster (Car)
                  - Paralyzo Box (Ranged)
                  - Spymaster's Ruse (Specialist)
          </answer>
      </entry>
      <entry id="6" tags="Head Mode &amp; Body Mode">
          <question>
              For cards like Heavy Handed that count stars, do you use the sum of the head and body star costs for the card's effect?
          </question>
          <answer>
              Yes.
          </answer>
      </entry>
      <entry id="7" tags="Emissary">
          <question>
              Is Emissary required as the head for Cerebros - City Commander?
          </question>
          <answer>
              No. You may use any 4 star or less Head mode character. 
          </answer>
      </entry>
    </target>
    <target name="Topspin - Air &amp; Space Assault">
        <entry id="8">
          <question>
              Topspin doesn't have any stars on his card, can I play him for free?
          </question>
          <answer>
              No. That was a printing error. Topspin is a 9-star card. 
          </answer>
      </entry>
    </target>
    <target name="Tidal Wave - Dark Fleet (Battleship)">
        <entry id="9" tags="Tidal Wave - Dark Fleet">
            <question>
                 If your opponent KOs one of your characters, other than the Battleship, and you play an I Still Function! to bring that character back, does Tidal Wave combine at the end of turn?
            </question>
            <answer>
                Yes, Tidal Wave does combine. WotC (Drew) confirmed this in a comment to this <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/transformerstcg/permalink/2998793173489493/">community poll</a>.
            </answer>
        </entry>
    </target>
    <target name="Sabotage">
        <entry id="10" tags="Autobot Gears - Transport &amp; Reconnaissance">
            <question>
                Why is there a Decepticon symbol on Gear's stratagem?
            </question>
            <answer>
                In the 1985 <a href="https://tfwiki.net/wiki/Changing_Gears">Changing Gears</a> episode of the G1 cartoon, Gears has a circuit removed and becomes a happy to please mechanoid who will help anyone, including the Decepticons. The symbol on the stratagem is <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/transformerstcg/permalink/2778809832154496/?comment_id=2778864748815671">stated</a> to be a tongue in cheek reference to that episode. 
            </answer>
        </entry>
    </target>

    <target name="Head Mode &amp; Body Mode">
        <entry id="11">
          <question>
              Canon-wise, which Heads go with which Bodies?
              </question>
              <answer>
                  While you are encouraged to mix and match your Head and Body Mode characters, their original pairings are:
                  <dt>Autobots</dt>
                  <dd><ul><li>Optimus Prime - Legendary Warrior &#x2192; Apex</li><li>Autobot Nautica - Camien Engineer - &#x2192; Parsec</li><li>Brainstorm - Biomechanical Engineer &#x2192; Autobot Teslor or (Decepticon) Arcana</li><li>Chromedome - Computer Programmer &#x2192; Autobot Stylor</li><li>Sergeant Kup - Wrecker Leader &#x2192; Flintlock</li><li>Topspin - Air &amp; Space Assault &#x2192; Freezeout</li><li>Twin Twist - Demolitions &#x2192; Flameout</li><li>Perceptor - Precise Sniper &#x2192; Convex</li><li>Fortress Maximus - Great War Veteran &#x2192; Cerebros</li><li>Cerebros - City Commander &#x2192; Emissary</li></ul></dd>
                  <dt>Decepticons</dt><dd><ul><li>Megatron - Fallen Hero &#x2192; Doomshot</li><li>Decepticon Quake - Ground Assault &#x2192; Chasm</li><li>Fangry - Sky Tracker &#x2192; Brisko</li><li>Horri-Bull - Ground Trooper &#x2192; Kreb</li><li>Mindwipe - Hypnotist &#x2192; Vorath</li><li>Skullsmasher - Swamp Warrior &#x2192; Grax</li><li>Wolfwire - Ground Tracker &#x2192; Monxo</li><li>Sky Shadow - Elite Warrior &#x2192; Ominus</li></ul></dd>
                  While Clobber looks like Grimlock's head, there's no canon (as yet) in which Clobber is his head.
            </answer>
        </entry>
    </target>

    <target name="Better Things To Do Than Die">
        <entry id="12" tags="Sergeant Springer - Special Ops - Aerial Defense">
            <question>
                Can the Better Things To Do Than Die stratagem be used on Sergeant Springer?
            </question>
            <answer>
                No. It is solely for Autobot Springer - Aerial Defense. The lack of "Autobot" in the stratagem target is believed to be unintended.
            </answer>
        </entry>
    </target>
</faq>
