<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-11-08" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360035662892-War-for-Cybertron-Siege-II-FAQ-and-Rules-Roundup" published_date="2019-11-08" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="9-1">
      <question>
Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend flips completely for his attack &amp; chooses Leap of Faith as his Action. The first card Leap of Faith reveals is Grenade Launcher. If I attach it to Optimus Prime Battlefield Legend, does he immediately get the +4 Attack boost?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-2">
      <question>
Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend is equipped with Power Punch, flips completely for his attack, and chooses Leap of Faith as his Action. The first card Leap of Faith reveals is W-5 Gyro Blaster. If OPBL attaches this, do I keep all the flips revealed from Power Punch? If so, does that mean my opponent now cannot flip more than 2 cards for their defense now that W-5 Gyro Blaster has been attached?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, W-5 Gyro Blaster&#x2019;s ability only triggers if it&#x2019;s attached when the character attacks or defends.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-3">
      <question>
If I have a character with Bumpers attached, and I play Involuntary Promotion on a car in my KO area, does the returned character receive the Bumpers in time to prevent the damage counters from being moved?
        </question>
      <answer>
The damage and upgrades are moved at the same time. Bumpers&#x2019; effect won&#x2019;t stop the damage counters from being moved.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-4" tags="Pincer Movement,Razorclaw - Predacon Leader,Brave">
      <question>
Regarding Pincer, will it allow the follow-up attack to bypass normal rule processes? For example, I attack with Razorclaw in Bot Mode against an untapped unit. Can my other Decepticon attack this untapped unit? What about bypassing Brave?
        </question>
      <answer>
If you can&#x2019;t legally choose another Decepticon as the attacker, and the same character as the defender, you don&#x2019;t get the extra attack. In other words, you can&#x2019;t just ignore Brave or other rules.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-5" tags="Battle Master">
      <question>
Can I KO a Battle Master with Involuntary Promotion if I have no bots in my KO area?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes. If you have no characters in KO or the characters in your KO area have too many stars, you can use Involuntary Promotion to KO one of your characters.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-6">
      <question>
Regarding Involuntary Promotion trigger timings, when I shift the upgrade and damage counters to the returned character. Do I get to choose to shift the damage counters first followed by the upgrades since they are both my triggers?
        </question>
      <answer>
No part of Involuntary Promotion is a triggered ability. The instructions are all followed in order and the damage counters and upgrades are moved at the same time.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-7" tags="Raider Tailwind - Air Strike Patrol - Strategist">
      <question>
If I equip Crash Landing on an Air Strike Patrol bot that is buffed by Tailwind's +2 Attack, does it trigger Crash Landing with the extra Attack?
        </question>
      <answer>
Crash Landing will do damage based on whatever the plane&#x2019;s attack was when it was last on the battlefield. Bonuses like Tailwind&#x2019;s will still apply because the plane is KO&#x2019;d during the battle.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-8" tags="Nightbird - Enigmatic Agent">
      <question>
Nightbird stealing cards from an opponent's scrap pile: Can I keep them after playing them?
        </question>
      <answer>
No. Any action you play from your opponent&#x2019;s scrap pile goes into your played area, and eventually back to their scrap pile. (Cards always go to their owner&#x2019;s hand, deck, KO area, and scrap pile).
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-9" tags="Revenge,Bounty,Raider Ratbat - Spy Patrol - Fuel Scout,Deadlock - Soldier Of Fortune">
      <question>
Revenge on Ratbat and Bounty on Deadlock both trigger upon Ratbat's KO, but which triggers first?
        </question>
      <answer>
Bounty abilities and Revenge abilities will usually trigger at the same time. Bounty abilities are usually handled first because they belong to the active player.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-10" tags="Captain Omega Supreme - Transport - City Defender">
      <question>
Can Omega Supreme be used in a manner like the Sentinels where you can have a section of his base mode in your KO area at the start of the game?
        </question>
      <answer>
No. Characters on your team always start on the battlefield unless specifically stated otherwise.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-11">
      <question>
How does Pincer Movement work?  If I have three untapped Decepticons and play Pincer Movement, do I get to attack the same enemy with each of my Decepticons in sequence, or do I only get one extra attack total.  If I can get multiple attacks this way, and I untap one of the previously attacking Decepticons (such as via Anticipation Engine revealing Ready for Action), can that Decepticon attack again?
        </question>
      <answer>
Pincer Movement gives you only one additional attack. After you play it, the next time one of your Decepticons attacks an enemy this turn, you&#x2019;ll get the extra attack after the current attack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-12" tags="Captain Omega Supreme - Transport - City Defender">
      <question>
So, let's say we have Omega Supreme (Base), (Spaceship), and (Tank) verses Kickback, Shrapnel, Barrage and Ransack. No side has any KO bots.  All bots on Omega's team is tapped. Shrapnel and Barrage are tapped.  It's the Insecticons turn with Kickback and Ransack untapped and ready to attack. They have 4 battlecards in their deck. They send Kickback to attack Omega Supreme (Tank). Kickback needs to flip at least 8 Battlecards, so 4 Battlecards are first flipped, causing their deck to be reshuffled.  Captain Omega Supreme then formed. Kickback continues his same attack now onto Captain Omega Supreme, flipping at least 4 more battlecards. The player with Omega NOW gets to flip for defending. Since Captain Omega Supreme is now untapped, Ransack is no longer able to attack, thus ending the turn of the Insecticons.
My question is, is the sequence of events that I have listed correct, or did I miss something?
        </question>
      <answer>
Well don&#x2019;t just leave us hanging! What cards were flipped? Who won?
(Yes, everything you listed is correct).
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-13" tags="Raider Calibust - Air Force - Weapons">
      <question>
A question on Calliburst? After the initial first draw, if my opponent draws three cards, do they take three damage all at once or do they take one, then one, then one again, for a total of three. 
        </question>
      <answer>
One then one then one again. Now say that five times fast.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-14">
      <question>
When you use Sabotaged Armaments, and your opponent has a Power Punch on the attacker, do they get the Bold before Sabotaged Armaments activates?
        </question>
      <answer>
No. This all happens before Battle Cards are flipped.
Speaking of which, what happens when a character upgraded with Anticipation Engine swings into a Sabotaged Armaments?
Anticipation Engine and Sabotaged Armaments will both trigger at the same time. The attacker will resolve Anticipation Engine first, then the defender will resolve Sabotaged Armaments.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-15">
      <question>
Does Involuntary Promotion count as "repairing" the resurrected character? In other words, could Torox or Ratchet benefit from its play?
        </question>
      <answer>
No. The character appears on the Battlefield fully repaired. It&#x2019;s not repaired while on the Battlefield.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-16" tags="Metroplex - Autobot City,Trypticon - Assault Base">
      <question>
If I&#x2019;m playing Metroplex and I get KO&#x2019;d in round one, can I sideboard in Trypticon?
        </question>
      <answer>
Your character sideboard is allowed 1 character with 19 stars or fewer. Trypticon is too big for this and is wondering why you&#x2019;re not just running him on your team to begin with.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-17" tags="Focus">
      <question>
What happens when I want to Focus 2 but I have last card in my deck?
        </question>
      <answer>
Utter calamity! Look at the top card, set it aside, reshuffle your scrap pile into your deck, look at the new top card, then decide what to do with the two cards you&#x2019;ve looked at. Now, look at me. I am the captain now.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-18" tags="Captain Omega Supreme - Transport - City Defender">
      <question>
For Omega Supreme, it says once your opponent shuffles their deck you combine. If I swing with one of Omega's pieces, but mid-attack my opponent shuffles their deck, do I combine and stop my attack because the character who triggered the attack isn't and my opponent has another character untapped? Along the same lines, when someone attacks into an Omega Supreme piece and they shuffle their deck. When you go to combine, does the attack still go through to the now combined Omega Supreme? Or does the attack get canceled as the original target isn't on the field anymore?
        </question>
      <answer>
If a character attacks or defends, and in the middle of the attack, combines into another character, the new combined character continues to attack or defend. Note that the combined character is untapped and will remain untapped for the duration of the attack.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-19">
      <question>
If I play Dual Wield on a mercenary who has no weapons on him originally, do I have to discard that weapon at the end of turn, or because I still have an open weapon slot can I keep that weapon?
        </question>
      <answer>
You do not! You can keep it in the original Weapon slot.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-20">
      <question>
Does Daring Escape continually check the whole turn or does it only check when the card is played?
        </question>
      <answer>
It only checks one time when the card is played, not the whole turn.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-21">
      <question>
If I play Brainstorm into 2 Overwhelming Advantages and meet all the requirements, can I do 15 damage to 2 different enemies? Or must they target the same character?
        </question>
      <answer>
Each Overwhelming Advantage is separate, so they can do damage to different characters.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-22">
      <question>
If I have a Cassette in Bot Mode that is chosen as a defender but flip a Swerve does it fizzle the attack when the character flips to Cassette due to the Stealth on that side as long as another target is legal to attack? Or not, since it's already been chosen as the defender?
        </question>
      <answer>
Once an attack is legally declared, the defender picking up Stealth won&#x2019;t matter.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-23">
      <question>
If I flip a character who lets me play a card for free such as Detritus - Arms Dealer who allows me to play a Black Pip card, can I play a Smoke Cloak this way to give Detritus Tough 1 for that battle, or does it apply after flips have ready happened?
        </question>
      <answer>
Swerve happens before Battle Cards are flipped, so if you reveal Swerve to flip Detritus in this way and play Smoke Cloak, the Tough 1 would be in place before Battle Cards are flipped..
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="9-24">
      <question>
I play Brainstorm, then Ancient Wisdom and System Reboot. My new hand is Multi-Mission Gear, Brainstorm, and 2 Unleashed Potential. Can I play Mutli-Mission Gear, then Brainstorm, and then both Unleashed Potentials?
        </question>
      <answer>
Let&#x2019;s walk through this whole play. You play Brainstorm and your first action is Ancient Wisdom. Ancient Wisdom has you scrap the top two cards of your deck and put an Action and/or Upgrade from among the scrapped cards into your hand. At this point, you can play Unleash Potential, if it&#x2019;s in your hand.
Let&#x2019;s say you do. You get a card with 1 star from outside the game and put it into your hand. This may not be a great idea, because you then play the second action from Brainstorm, which is System Reboot. You scrap your hand (including that fancy star card you just snagged) and draw 4 cards.
But instead, let&#x2019;s say you don&#x2019;t play Unleash Potential. That brings you to the end of Ancient Wisdom and now you System Reboot just as above.
In either case, your new hand is Multi-Mission Gear, Brainstorm, and 2 Unleash Potentials. You&#x2019;ve already played an Action this turn, so we&#x2019;re guessing you&#x2019;ll now play Multi-Mission Gear. This allows you to play an Action such as Brainstorm. Brainstorm will allow you to play 2 Unleash Potentials. You played Ancient Wisdom earlier in your turn, so you can get two 1-star cards from outside the game.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
