<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-11-22" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360036215412-Rules-Roundup-11-22-19" published_date="2019-11-22" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="10-1">
      <question>
My opponent just went and used &#x201C;Peace Through Tyranny&#x201D; and KO&#x2019;d his Lionizer...putting it on Spinister. Pteraxadon was already tapped. He then attacked with Spinister and KO&#x2019;d my Scamper. My Metroplex is still untapped. My opponent has another turn from the PTT. How does that work seeing he&#x2019;s all tapped out, but I still have a character that&#x2019;s untapped?
        </question>
      <answer>
Your opponent still takes their extra turn, even if they won&#x2019;t be able to attack during that turn. They&#x2019;ll still draw a card and can play cards, etc.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-2">
      <question>
With Showing Off, would a Bot receive any and all "when you flip to" triggers during the process or does it only count the final mode it's flipped to? For example, if Grimlock - Dinobot Leader is in bot mode and plays Showing Off, could he end in Bot mode with the Bold 3 from his Alt mode?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, you can first flip Grimlock to alt mode, causing the ability on that mode to trigger, and then flip back to bot mode.

          <tftcg-note>While the alt mode ability triggers when Grimlock is flipped to alt-mode, note that the trigger does not resolve until after Showing Off has completed and Grimlock is back in bot-mode. </tftcg-note>
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-3">
      <question>
When a character is KO'd as part of resolving a card effect, like Peace Through Tyranny, is the character put into the KO area fully damaged, or only with the amount of damage it had when it was KO'd?
        </question>
      <answer>
Characters in KO are always fully damaged.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-4">
      <question>
At the end of the turn, does a weapon equipped from the scrap pile that is in the &#x201C;extra&#x201D; weapon slot get scrapped or do you choose?
        </question>
      <answer>
You choose.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-5">
      <question>
For Relentless Invasion, do you have to have all three minions KO&#x2019;d or can you revive one or two of them?
        </question>
      <answer>
They don&#x2019;t all have to be in the KO area. Whichever ones are there can be put onto the battlefield. Only the characters deployed this way go back under Trypticon at the end of your turn.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-6" tags="Sergeant Springer - Special Ops - Aerial Defense">
      <question>
For Showing Off, can I flip Sergeant Springer to one alt mode and use its effect then flip to the other Alt mode and use its effect too? Or must I resolve Showing Off completely first?
        </question>
      <answer>
Showing Off resolves completely before any abilities that triggered happen.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-7">
      <question>
What is the timing for Sabotaged Armaments versus weapons like Power Punch?
        </question>
      <answer>
Sabotaged Armaments is revealed when one of your characters defends, before Battle Cards are flipped. Power Punch will be scrapped before it can affect that battle.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-8">
      <question>
What happens when I play Acute Reflexes on Specialist Flamewar (Bot Mode)?
        </question>
      <answer>
If a character has two instances of Focus 1, they happen sequentially. If you leave the top card of your deck on top of your deck for the first instance of Focus, that will be the card you will get the second time you Focus.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-9">
      <question>
What happens when I play Medic's Protective Field on Private Smokescreen (Alt Mode)?
        </question>
      <answer>
Because the Safeguard value is the same, having two instances of it has no additional effect. Smokescreen can&#x2019;t take more than 3 damage if undamaged. However, if a character has two instances of Safeguard with different values, the lowest value wins. For example, if a character has Safeguard 1 and Safeguard 3, that character can&#x2019;t take more than 1 damage if undamaged.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-10">
      <question>
How many cards do I flip if my opponent shuffles their deck while attacking Omega Supreme (Spaceship)&#x2013;triggering Combination&#x2013;and I have Evasive Maneuvers on Omega Supreme (Spaceship) and Urban Camo on Omega Supreme (Base)?
        </question>
      <answer>
When you combine into Captain Omega Supreme, you get to keep 1 upgrade in each slot, so you can keep both Evasive Maneuvers and Urban Camo. You&#x2019;ll flip a total of 6 Battle Cards. After the battle, you&#x2019;ll scrap Evasive Maneuvers.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-11">
      <question>
If my opponent KO&#x2019;s Skytread (whichever), what happens to his Upgrades? Are they Scrapped? Are they eligible to be transferred to Raider Skytread? Can I choose to Scrap a Reactive Armor even if the other piece doesn't have an Armor?
        </question>
      <answer>
If Skytread (whichever) has any upgrades prior to combining, those upgrades are scrapped. Raider Skytread can keep the upgrades from the Skytread (whichever) that was on the battlefield and not KO&#x2019;d.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-12">
      <question>
My opponent has Nightbird in Alt mode with 9 damage counters on her. If I play Plasma Burst to deal the remaining two damage to finish her off, will I still have to deal 1 damage to one of my characters?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes. Unless the game ends when Nightbird is KO&#x2019;d.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-13">
      <question>
Do Omega Supreme and Skytread&#x2019;s separate uncombined character cards count as separate characters for the purposes of "Choose one of your characters" cards?  Most notable example is if I play Two-Pronged Attack on "Skytread (Plane)", do I also get the tank trigger, or do I only get the Plane trigger?
        </question>
      <answer>
While uncombined, each character is separate. If you play Two-Pronged Attack on Skytread (Plane), you&#x2019;ll only get the damage effect.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-14" tags="Pierce,Insecticon Skrapnel - Insecticon Leader,Safeguard">
      <question>
Is Pierce damage still considered attack damage? For example, if someone is attacking me with Pierce 4 against a character like Insecticon Skrapnel whose text is &#x201C;can&#x2019;t take more than 3 damage during an attack&#x201D;, does that mean even though they have Pierce 4 after adding attack damage, would they only do 3, or would they do 4? 
        </question>
      <answer>
Pierce is an ability that applies to attack damage. But, effects like Insecticon Skrapnel&#x2019;s or the Safeguard ability will still apply. In your example, Skrapnel would take only 3 damage.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-15">
      <question>
If you have Trypticon untapped initially, and your opponents&#x2019; characters are also all untapped, and I play Relentless Invasion to bring back Wipe Out, Full Tilt and Brunt, since the effect of Invasion allows you to attack with them all, can Trypticon attack as well?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes. The attack granted to his three minions is in addition to your normal attack that turn.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-16">
      <question>
If Nightbird attacks with a Contract Contingency and it triggers Nightbird&#x2019;s bounty, can I take another Contract Contingency from my opponent&#x2019;s scrap pile, play this, then trigger Nightbird&#x2019;s bounty again?
Or can you only trigger Contract Contingency once because you are not getting 4 or more attack damage through after applying the plus 2 to the already finished attack?
        </question>
      <answer>
The second Contract Contingency won&#x2019;t trigger because it will be played after the attack damage has been done.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-17">
      <question>
I have 4 cards in my hand and my opponent has Decepticon Shockwave in Bot mode. If they play Brainstorm &gt; System Reboot &gt; System Reboot, do I take 4 damage after each System Reboot or 8 damage after Brainstorm is resolved?
        </question>
      <answer>
Shockwave&#x2019;s ability will trigger a total of 8 times. Each of those abilities resolves separately, so essentially you have 8 damage counters to spread around as you wish.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-18">
      <question>
Using the above scenario, my character is Nightbird in alt mode. What is the timing there? Does the Shockwave player take 1 damage each time an action hits the play area or after the Brainstorm resolves?
I.E. My Nightbird is at full HP (11) and his Shockwave is at 3.  Who wins?
        </question>
      <answer>
Here's what happens. Your opponent starts to play Brainstorm, this causes Nightbird&#x2019;s ability to trigger, but that effect doesn&#x2019;t resolve immediately. Continuing to resolve Brainstorm, your opponent then plays System Reboot. Another Nightbird trigger happens, which, again, doesn&#x2019;t resolve immediately. The System Reboot resolves, causing Shockwave to trigger four times. Continuing to resolve Brain Storm, your opponent then plays the second System Reboot. This causes another Nightbird trigger. The second System Reboot causes another four Shockwave triggers. Now that Brainstorm has resolved, we start resolving triggers, beginning with the ones that triggered most recently and working backwards. The four Shockwave triggers caused by the second System Reboot happen one at a time. Next, the Nightbird trigger caused by the second System Reboot happens. Next, the Shockwave triggers caused by the first System Reboot happens. Next, the Nightbird trigger caused by the first System Reboot happens. And finally, the Nightbird trigger caused by the Brain Storm happens. At any point, if resolving one of these triggers causes a player to KO their last character, that player loses the game. If Shockwave was at 3 and Nightbird was at 8 at the beginning of this sequence, Nightbird is going to lose.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-19" tags="Raider Skytread - Special Ops - Soldier">
      <question>
The answer from the last rules roundup states that the new combiners (Omega Supreme and Skytread) keep all upgrades and damage when they combine. Even with that explanation, rule enforcers where I play tell me that it doesn't apply to the KO'd Skytread's upgrades and that those upgrades are scrapped during the KO process before Revenge combining takes place and do not transfer to the combined Skytread. Can I please get a specific ruling on this?
        </question>
      <answer>
Upgrades attached to the Skytread half that gets KO&#x2019;d are scrapped at the same time. Those upgrades can&#x2019;t be put on Raider Skytread.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-20">
      <question>
Let's say, in theory, Lockdown has a 4 cards in hand, along with a Weapon, Armor, Utility, and one card underneath him.  Lockdown flips to his alt mode, allowing him to draw 4 discard 4, but I reveal Hijack.  Would I get to draw 4 while Lockdown's player has to pay the discard part of the effect or since he drew 0 cards he discards 0 cards?
        </question>
      <answer>
You draw the 4 cards. The Lockdown player would have to scrap 4 cards. That poor, sweet fool has been Hijacked.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-21">
      <question>
Does an Autobot Battle Master in upgrade mode on a character still count as an Autobot on the battlefield when putting cards on your KO area for Daring Escape?
        </question>
      <answer>
No. Daring Escape only counts Autobot characters.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-22">
      <question>
I have Trypticon and Full-Tilt on the battlefield untapped, with Wipeout and Brunt in the KO area.  I play Relentless Invasion, returning the two KOed bots to the battlefield and attack with them.  Am I then required to attack with Trypticon or Full-Tilt?
        </question>
      <answer>
If your opponent is entirely tapped out, you must attack with both characters. If not, you can attack with one or the other (not both), but you don&#x2019;t have to.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-23">
      <question>
Relentless Invasion returns Wipeout to the battlefield, I flip him to Bot mode, and attack with him.  After he gets pulled back under Trypticon, I use Battlefield Incursion the next turn to replay him.  Does Wipeout enter the battlefield in Bot mode or Alt mode?
        </question>
      <answer>
Alt mode.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-24">
      <question>
Let's say I've got an Armor on one of my characters as well as Defensive Configuration, giving me an extra empty Armor slot. I then play Hunker Down which checks to see if I have an Armor or not. Since Configuration will be giving me an empty Armor slot, would I be able to put an Armor on my character through Hunker, or will it not work since I do still have an Armor in the 1st Armor slot?
        </question>
      <answer>
It will not work since your Tank already has an Armor attached.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-25">
      <question>
If I have a LV Gamma Disruptor Launcher on Shockwave and play a Dual Wield for my turn, giving Shockwave another Weapon slot, and I play another LV Gamma as my upgrade for the turn, then attack. Since 2 LV gammas are allowed in one weapon slot, I presume the one attached by Dual Wield will stay on as well?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-26" tags="Sergeant Six-Gun - Artillery - Soldier">
      <question>
Interesting Sergeant Six-Gun question. If I have both of his Upgrades on one character, and say an Armor in his Armor slot (so in this case Six-Gun&#x2019;s Upgrades are in Weapon and Utility, respectively), can I scrap said armor to put on a Utility? One of his guns says you can put in Armor or Utility slots but I'm not sure if you could scrap one to play the other.
        </question>
      <answer>
No. You choose the slots when you attach the upgrades to the character.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-27" tags="Private Turbo Board - Air Command - Evac">
      <question>
If you have Private Turbo Board defending against Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend, after his opponent already played an Upgrade and an Action for their turn, and Optimus flips an Action, may he use it?
        </question>
      <answer>
No.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-28">
      <question>
Question regarding interaction between Backup Bag and weapons which can be scrapped during attack (e.g. Sturdy Javelin and Multi-Missile Pod). If I choose to scrap the weapon and it's saved by Backup Bag, can I choose to scrap it again during the same attack?
        </question>
      <answer>
No. It scraps as a result of a triggered ability, which does not trigger again. You would have to somehow attack a second time.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-29">
      <question>
If I reveal Stable Cover while Jazz is defending in Alt mode, does this protect his ability from being shut down even if the attacker has Pierce?
        </question>
      <answer>
No.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-30" tags="Weaponizer">
      <question>
Can a Weaponizer be used as your sideboard character?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes. Although it is two cards, it is one character.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-31">
      <question>
Involuntary Promotion: if I play it and chose a tapped character, does the revived character come back tapped or untapped?  
        </question>
      <answer>
Untapped.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-32">
      <question>
If my Predaking attacks with 5 weapons and a Spare Parts, and my opponent reveals a Sabotage Armaments Secret Action, what happens? Does the Sabotage Armaments scrap Spare Parts only or does it scrap only 4 of the Weapons and Spare Parts?
        </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, you could use Spare Parts to save one Weapon of your choice.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-33">
      <question>
My question is about the interaction of Debilitating Crystal and the new Expanded Rules document. If my attacker has a Debilitating Crystal, and the Defender has a Gyro Blaster I wish to return, I believe the Gyro Blaster would still limit each character to 2 flips this battle. Is this correct? I know a previous Rules Roundup clarified that a Security Console would still Draw and Plan even if a Debilitating Crystal returned it. Is this also the case with a Sparring Gear I wish to return? Do they still have Tough 2 this battle?
        </question>
      <answer>
Expanded Rules point 8.5 indicates the Gyro Blaster is returned before flips are determined, so it will not affect them. Likewise, Sparring Gear will no longer grant Tough 2 when flips are determined.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-34">
      <question>
If an opponent attacks me with a Sturdy Javelin on a ranged character and I reveal a Sabotaged Armaments I played last turn, how do the cards resolve? Does the Javelin scrap and deal two damage before the secret action takes effect or does the secret action scrap the Javelin before the two damage is dealt?
        </question>
      <answer>
The attacking player will scrap the Javelin to do 2 Damage. Because attacker effects resolve before defender effects.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-35" tags="Private Firedrive - Ground Command - Artillery">
      <question>
Furthermore in the case of Firedrive&#x2019;s weapon mode, it says the upgraded character gets the attack bonus, so will the character keep the attack bonus, just not the +3 since the weapon will be scrapped? 
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes. The character will keep the Attack bonus but not the +3.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-36" tags="Autobot Cosmos - Recon &amp; Communication,Lord Megatron - Conqueror of Cybertron">
      <question>
Autobot Cosmos is in Bot mode and attacks Lord Megatron in Bot mode. During Cosmos&#x2019; attack against Lord Megatron, I have to reshuffle. Does the reshuffle trigger both Cosmos and Lord Megatron's abilities at the same time? Or does Cosmos KO Lord Megatron first?
        </question>
      <answer>
Cosmos would KO Lord Megatron first. Megatron&#x2019;s ability will still happen afterwards if the game has not ended.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-37" tags="Autobot Mirage - Lone Wolf">
      <question>
Let say I'm attacking with Mirage and flip 2 black pips and 3 white pips. As far as I know, my attack is 5 Pierce 2 and then his ability triggered and I untap. Then I attack again and this time I flip 1 white pip and 3 black pips. Is my attack 5 Pierce 3 or is it 5 Pierce 5?
        </question>
      <answer>
5 Pierce 5.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-38">
      <question>
I have a character with a Reactive Armor. I play a Scrapper Gauntlets on that character. My opponent only has a single Armor in play.  What is the timing on the triggers here?  Are they considered simultaneous, or does one need to happen before the other?
        </question>
      <answer>
They trigger simultaneously and you resolve them in an order of your choosing.
      </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-39" tags="Safeguard,Raider Kickback - Infantry Soldier">
      <question>
Beginning player here, not sure where else to go for clarification in general. My buddy and I played a killer game with Insecticons (me) v Special Ops Specialists (buddy). All three of his characters had Safeguard. I swung into one of them (undamaged) with Raider Kickback (bot) and flipped one blue and several orange. My thinking was the one damage from Kickback's ability would eliminate the Safeguard, thus allowing all combat damage to be applied. Then came the confusion. I believe his thinking was that all the damage came at once, prevented to some degree by Safeguard. After scouring stupid Google for help to no avail, I decided to simply concede to his perspective and move the game along. He won, but it was close, and it would have been a drastically different story had all that combat damage been applied.
        </question>
      <answer>
Kickback&#x2019;s ability does 1 Damage before Attack damage is applied, thus disabling Safeguard. Congratulations on your crushing theoretical victory!
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="10-40" tags="Bounty">
      <question>
Do you need to have the character in Bot mode showing the Bounty for this card to use the bounty. Or does the card activate the character&#x2019;s Bounty regardless of mode?
        </question>
      <answer>
Abilities are only active if that side is face-up. I.E. you must be in Bot Mode to use a Bot Mode ability.
</answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
