<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-08-23" source_url="https://transformerstcg-support.wizards.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033073232-Rules-Roundup-8-23-19" published_date="2019-08-23" sourced_at="2020-03-04">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="4-1">
      <question>
What happens if someone has Brave and Stealth at the same time, like if I played Hiding Spot on Blitzwing while he was in tank mode, do they cancel out, does the newer stays take effect?
        </question>
      <answer>
They cancel each other out. An attacker is not able to fulfill both conditions, therefore the attacking player can choose a defender as normal.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-2">
      <question>
I have a ruling question about Optimus Prime - Battlefield Legend. If I my attack checks an action like Pep Talk, when do I activate the effect? Immediately (I draw 2 cards, then continue the check) or after resolution? (continue the checks, then draw two cards). On a similar note. If I decide to use an action with an orange or white pip, am I still able to keep the pip effect, or does that vanish with the card?
        </question>
      <answer>
First, you attack with OPBL, then you flip the Battle Cards (including any Bold). If you flip a white battle icon, you flip two more Battle Cards. Then, you check if you have flipped an Action. You can play one of the actions. You will still get plus attack from the orange icons flipped on that Action.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-3">
      <question>
I was wondering about Sergeant Chromia from Wave 3 and how the Alt mode flip ability works. Does the flip ability work in saying that you can play any blue armor upgrade, like possibly Superior Plating as an example, along with your original upgrade and action, or is it saying that the player is able to play an additional blue armor upgrade from hand along with their own upgrade and action on that turn?
        </question>
      <answer>
Sergeant Chromia&#x2019;s flip ability asks you to play a blue armor right then. If you don&#x2019;t, you&#x2019;ve forfeited the opportunity to do so. Your normal upgrade play and action play aren&#x2019;t affected by this. The flip ability does not allow playing Superior Plating without previously having played Tech Research.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-4">
      <question>
I have Sturdy Armor on Soundwave and my opponent's Optimus Prime, Battlefield Legend attacks him while in Bot Mode, where he is Ranged. Optimus flips Roll Out as one of his Battle Card flips and plays it via his ability, changing to Alt Mode, in which he is now Melee. Does Soundwave still get the extra +1 Defense from Sturdy Armor since Optimus was Ranged when he attacked? Or does he not get the bonus since Optimus is now Melee?
        </question>
      <answer>
In this scenario, Sturdy Armor would not give the extra +1 Defense as Optimus is not Ranged. Sturdy Armor is constantly checking for the enemy&#x2019;s Ranged trait, all the way up until damage is dealt.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-5">
      <question>
If I have a tapped character get KO&#x2019;d that has already attacked, if I play I Still Function!, does he come from the KO pile untapped?
        </question>
      <answer>
Tapped characters get KO&#x2019;d into the KO Area and are no longer tapped or untapped once in the KO Area. I Still Function! Returns the KO&#x2019;d character to the Battlefield untapped.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-6">
      <question>
If I have a Laser Cutlass and a Crushing Treads on say, Slammer, and I attack an opponent, does Slammer get the pierce 3 from the Laser Cutlass plus the pierce 3 from the Crushing Treads since pierce adds together and both pierce abilities are triggered differently? So, attacking for 4 with Pierce 6.
        </question>
      <answer>
That&#x2019;s correct. In this scenario you would be attacking for 4 with Pierce 6. Pierce stacks on Pierce, but not on regular attack damage.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-7">
      <question>
Optimus Prime, Gleaming Commander attacks Private Lionizer, knocking him out. Lionizer changes to RS Firesteel Saber, onto another of my characters, but Optimus Prime triggers his bot mode ability, and uses it to transform Prowl, Strategic Mastermind in my opponent&#x2019;s KO area, which then transforms to Prowl&#x2019;s bot mode and triggers his bot mode ability to remove a weapon. My opponent scraps RS Firesteel Saber. This all happened as a result of my opponent&#x2019;s attack- is this the correct order of play?
        </question>
      <answer>
Not quite. There are two errors in the scenario you&#x2019;re describing. The first is that Optimus&#x2019; trigger will resolve before damage is dealt to Lionizer. The second, is that your Optimus can only choose characters in your KO Area, so you would not be able to flip any characters in your opponent&#x2019;s KO Area.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-8">
      <question>
Question about Unconventional Flying Object. Can this be played on a Spaceship that is already in bot mode in order to flip it to alt mode, essentially ignoring the first sentence as "already done" (somewhat similar to Hunker Down)?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, it cannot.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-9">
      <question>
Can Quartermaster be used on Sergeant Cog? If not, is there a way to revive Cog from the KO/discard area for use again?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, and not currently&#x2026;
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-10">
      <question>
The question I have today is in regard to attacking with Anticipation Engine. I am playing with a combiner team, and I have just converted my last character. I don't have the Enigma in my hand to play it, so I play a different action instead. I attack using a character with Anticipation Engine and flip the Enigma. Am I able to play it, transform, and continue the attack with the Combiner, or does my attack get cancelled and it becomes my opponent's turn? (This is because the Enigma has the Combiner enter play untapped)

Update to the question, as I see it was already answered in a previous Rules Round-up.

&#x201C;Anticipation Engine + Enigma = Transformed and attacking, but untappedYou said the character was untapped, but still attacking. Does this mean that my opponent can only attack with one character if they have multiple available?
        </question>
      <answer>
Yes, your opponent can attack with only one character&#x201D;
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-11">
      <question>
My questions are:
1. If all my opponent&#x2019;s characters have already been tapped, can I still attack with the newly formed Combiner?
If all of your opponent&#x2019;s characters have already been tapped and you finish an attack with your untapped Combiner, you will then attack a second time with the Combiner.

    When Bolster activates during my opponent&#x2019;s turn, and Multi-Mission Gear is played with a Combiner Enigma, where does the attack land? As the defending character is no longer there, does it hit the Combiner?
        </question>
      <answer>
    The character they were attacking is part of your newly formed Combiner, so they are now attacking your Combiner.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-12">
      <question>
Does Start Your Engines affect cars in the KO area?
        </question>
      <answer>
No, it does not. Cards only affect cards in the KO Area if it is specifically stated in the card text.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-13">
      <question>
Hi, I just wondered if you can choose somebody that can't take non-attack damage as the recipient of non-attack damage, like if an opponent played Frag Toss and I had Motormaster in alt mode, would the damage have to go on Motormaster or could I choose somebody else and nullify it?
        </question>
      <answer>
You can choose someone else to nullify it.
</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="4-14">
      <question>
I have a character with a weapon and Spare Parts. My opponent hits me with Disarm or Debilitating Crystal. Is the weapon returned to my hand or does Spare Parts get scrapped, or returned to my hand instead?
        </question>
      <answer>
Same scenario, but my weapon is a Battle Master/Weaponizer.
In both scenarios, Spare Parts does not protect your weapon. A Battle Master or Weaponizer in weapon mode would go to KO rather than to your hand.
        </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
