<?xml version="1.0"?>
<faq name="Rules Roundup 2019-02-01" source_url="https://www.facebook.com/notes/transformers-trading-card-game/rules-roundup-2119/1991359677652514/" published_date="2019-02-01" sourced_at="2020-04-15">
  <target name="Placeholder">
    <entry id="201-1">
      <question>
Are actions played with Field Communicator set aside like actions played from a hand, or do they remain in the scrap pile?
      </question>
      <answer>
They are set aside like actions played from a hand.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-2" tags="Motormaster - Stunticon Leader">
      <question>
With Motormaster’s ability, for instance, are both character cards and battle cards considered to be "cards"?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-3" tags="Autobot Mirage - Lone Wolf">
      <question>
If Cornered! were played on an Autobot Mirage, allowing a player to play an action during their opponent's turn, and they played an All-Out Attack; could they attack with all of their characters during their opponent's turn?
      </question>
      <answer>
No. A player cannot attack during an opponent’s turn.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-4" tags="Decepticon Shockwave - Cybertron Commander">
      <question>
I have Decepticon Shockwave in bot mode (untapped), and start by playing Brainstorm, then play Disruption to have the opponent scrap a card in hand, then Security Checkpoint and to have the opponent scrap 2 more cards. So a total of 3 cards were scrapped by 2 action cards. Would the opponent take 1 damage for each action card played (that made them scrap cards) or take 3 damage since the opponent scrapped 3 cards total?
      </question>
      <answer>
The opponent would take 3 damage total.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-5" tags="Chop Shop - Sneaky Insecticon">
      <question>
At what point does the upgrade I chose to move to Chop Shop take effect? During the attack so I gain the possible effect for my current attack, or does the cards effect (additional attack, additional bold, etc.) not happen until the next time I attack with Chop Shop?
      </question>
      <answer>
You would get the benefits of the upgrade immediately, with the exception of abilities that trigger from Chop Shop attacking, because that event would have already passed (i.e. Data Pad).
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-6" tags="Combiner,Optimus Maximus - Ultimate Defender,Ironhide - Steadfast Brawler">
      <question>
When Combiners combine can the keep an equipment that they normally couldn't equip? Example could Optimus Maximus keep a Power Sword from Ironhide even though he's a ranged character?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-7" tags="Combiner">
      <question>
When you play an Enigma of Combination to combine and all characters are in bot mode, do you also get to do the other text on the Enigma such as drawing 2 cards when you play the Stunticon Enigma, or do you only get that effect if you play the Stunticon Enigma once Menasor has already been formed?
      </question>
      <answer>
You perform the actions on the card in the order that they’re written, which dictates when effects are applicable to a given scenario. For example, if you’ve already played an Enigma to combine, you would receive the top bonus.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-8" tags="Combiner,Optimus Maximus - Ultimate Defender,Prowl - Strategic Mastermind">
      <question>
The enigma cards mention a Combiner keeps an upgrade in each slot, but here's a weird scenario involving that: Say Prowl, Strategic Mastermind is upgraded with a Power Sword. Since he's a melee character, he can obviously take this upgrade. But could you keep that Power Sword on Optimus Maximus when he combines, even though he's a ranged character?
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-9" tags="Motormaster - Stunticon Leader,Combiner">
      <question>
If Motormaster or Ironhide - Steadfast Brawler have three Cargo Trailer attached to them and they combine, can the Cargo Trailers be transferred over to the new Combiner even though the new Combiner is not a Truck? If so, can you transfer all three Cargo Trailers or just one? 
      </question>
      <answer>
You can transfer all three Cargo Trailers.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-10" tags="Combiner">
      <question>
Furthermore, can a Power Sword be transferred if the combined form is not Melee? 
      </question>
      <answer>
Yes.
    </answer>
    </entry>
    <entry id="201-11" tags="Combiner">
      <question>
If the Combiner is treated like a new character upon combination, will Armed Hovercraft activate if moved from a composite part to the Combiner upon combination? 
      </question>
      <answer>
No. It would stay attached, but would not activate upon combination.
    </answer>
    </entry>
  </target>
</faq>
